<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-01-23T00:36:13.310Z</id>
    <title>A curated list of immersive ramblings</title>
    <updated>2023-01-23T00:36:13.310Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local diffusion vs. nonlocal dispersal in periodic logistic equations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000098</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000098?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:57.200Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): Jian-Wen Sun]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kato square root problem for degenerate elliptic operators on bounded Lipschitz domains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002203962200763X</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002203962200763X?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:57.113Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 April 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 353
Author(s): Junqiang Zhang, Dachun Yang, Sibei Yang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inviscid limit of compressible viscoelastic equations with the no-slip boundary condition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039622007641</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039622007641?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:57.086Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 April 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 353
Author(s): Dehua Wang, Feng Xie]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the strongly competitive case in a fully parabolic two-species chemotaxis system with Lotka-Volterra competitive kinetics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000086</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000086?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:57.075Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): Xu Pan, Chunlai Mu, Weirun Tao]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heat kernels and theory of Hardy spaces associated to Schrödinger operators on stratified groups]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000025</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000025?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:57.052Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 April 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 353
Author(s): The Anh Bui, Qing Hong, Guorong Hu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal <em>L</em><sup>2</sup>-decay of solutions to the dissipative nonlinear Schrödinger equation in higher space dimensions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000013</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000013?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:57.042Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): Naoyasu Kita, Takuya Sato]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basins of attraction and paired Hopf bifurcations for delay differential equations with bistable nonlinearity and delay-dependent coefficient]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000153</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000153?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:56.974Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): Genghong Lin, Lin Wang, Jianshe Yu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General renewal equations motivated by biology and epidemiology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002203962300013X</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002203962300013X?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:56.953Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): R.M. Colombo, M. Garavello, F. Marcellini, E. Rossi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The combined non-equilibrium diffusion and low Mach number limits of a model arising in radiation magnetohydrodynamics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039622007689</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039622007689?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:56.917Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 April 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 353
Author(s): Fucai Li, Shuxing Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Invariant measures and stochastic Liouville type theorem for non-autonomous stochastic reaction-diffusion equations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039622007471</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039622007471?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:56.896Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 April 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 353
Author(s): Zhang Chen, Dandan Yang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Existence of global weak solutions to an inhomogeneous Doi model for active liquid crystals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000062</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000062?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:56.830Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): Oliver Sieber]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quasi-periodic solutions to the incompressible Euler equations in dimensions two and higher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000128</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039623000128?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T00:35:56.446Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2023
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 354
Author(s): Alberto Enciso, Daniel Peralta-Salas, Francisco Torres de Lizaur]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic predictions of postoperative complications from explainable, uncertainty-aware, and multi-task deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27418-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27418-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Dynamic predictions of postoperative complications from explainable, uncertainty-aware, and multi-task deep neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Scientific Computing]]></title>
        <id>10915</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10915"/>
        <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Order CENO Finite-Volume Scheme with Anisotropic Adaptive Mesh Refinement: Efficient Inexact Newton Method for Steady Three-Dimensional Flows]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02068-3</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02068-3"/>
        <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
A high-order finite-volume scheme with anisotropic adaptive mesh refinement (AMR) is combined with a parallel inexact Newton method for the solution of steady compressible fluid flows governed by the Euler and Navier–Stokes equations on three-dimensional multi-block body-fitted hexahedral meshes. The proposed steady flow solution method combines a family of robust and accurate high-order central essentially non-oscillatory (CENO) spatial discretization schemes with both a scalable and efficient Newton–Krylov–Schwarz (NKS) algorithm and a block-based anisotropic AMR method. The CENO scheme is based on a hybrid solution reconstruction procedure that provides high-order accuracy in smooth regions (even for smooth extrema) and non-oscillatory transitions at discontinuities and makes use of a high-order representation of the mesh and a high-order treatment of boundary conditions. In the proposed Newton method, the resulting linear systems of equations are solved using the generalized minimal residual (GMRES) algorithm preconditioned by a domain-based additive Schwarz technique. The latter uses the domain decomposition provided by the block-based AMR scheme leading to a fully parallel implicit approach with an efficient scalability of the overall scheme. The anisotropic AMR method is based on a binary tree data structure and permits local anisotropic refinement of the grid in preferred directions as directed by appropriately specified physics-based refinement criteria. Numerical results are presented for a range of inviscid and viscous steady problems and the computational performance of the combined scheme is demonstrated and assessed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectral Analysis of High Order Continuous FEM for Hyperbolic PDEs on Triangular Meshes: Influence of Approximation, Stabilization, and Time-Stepping]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02087-0</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02087-0"/>
        <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this work we study various continuous finite element discretization for two dimensional hyperbolic partial differential equations, varying the polynomial space (Lagrangian on equispaced, Lagrangian on quadrature points (Cubature) and Bernstein), the stabilization techniques (streamline-upwind Petrov–Galerkin, continuous interior penalty, orthogonal subscale stabilization) and the time discretization (Runge–Kutta (RK), strong stability preserving RK and deferred correction). This is an extension of the one dimensional study by Michel et al. (J Sci Comput 89(2):31, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10915-021-01632-7), whose results do not hold in multi-dimensional frameworks. The study ranks these schemes based on efficiency (most of them are mass-matrix free), stability and dispersion error, providing the best CFL and stabilization coefficients. The challenges in two-dimensions are related to the Fourier analysis. Here, we perform it on two types of periodic triangular meshes varying the angle of the advection, and we combine all the results for a general stability analysis. Furthermore, we introduce additional high order viscosity to stabilize the discontinuities, in order to show how to use these methods for tests of practical interest. All the theoretical results are thoroughly validated numerically both on linear and non-linear problems, and error-CPU time curves are provided. Our final conclusions suggest that Cubature elements combined with SSPRK and OSS stabilization is the most promising combination.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Fully-Decoupled Artificial Compressible Crank–Nicolson–Leapfrog Time Stepping Scheme for the Phase Field Model of Two-Phase Incompressible Flows]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02048-7</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02048-7"/>
        <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this paper, we consider efficient numerical approximations for the phase field model of two-phase incompressible flows. To develop easy-to-implement time stepping scheme, we introduce two types of nonlocal auxiliary variables to achieve highly efficient and fully-decoupled scheme based on the Crank–Nicolson–Leapfrog (CNLF) formula and artificial compression method. We prove that the scheme is linear and unconditionally energy stable. Ample numerical experiments are performed to demonstrate the accuracy, stability and efficiency.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research, education, and connection in the face of war]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2023/research-education-connection-face-war-tetiana-herasymova-0120</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/research-education-connection-face-war-tetiana-herasymova-0120"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I wouldn’t let the aggressor in the war squash my dreams,” says Ukrainian mathematician and MITx MicroMasters learner Tetiana Herasymova.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ouellette | MIT Open Learning</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standard Model of Cosmology Survives a Telescope’s Surprising Finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=122280</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/standard-model-of-cosmology-survives-jwsts-surprising-finds-20230120/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T15:49:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports that the James Webb Space Telescope killed the reigning cosmological model turn out to have been exaggerated. But astronomers still have much to learn from distant galaxies glimpsed by Webb.            
The post Standard Model of Cosmology Survives a Telescope’s Surprising Finds first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Boyle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MIT researchers develop an AI model that can detect future lung cancer risk]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2023/ai-model-can-detect-future-lung-cancer-0120</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/ai-model-can-detect-future-lung-cancer-0120"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deep-learning model takes a personalized approach to assessing each patient’s risk of lung cancer based on CT scans.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Ouyang | Abdul Latif Jameel Clinic for Machine Learning in Health</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematicians Roll Dice and Get Rock-Paper-Scissors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=122246</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/mathematicians-roll-dice-and-get-rock-paper-scissors-20230119/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T15:02:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematicians have uncovered a surprising wealth of rock-paper-scissors-like patterns in randomly chosen dice.            
The post Mathematicians Roll Dice and Get Rock-Paper-Scissors first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erica Klarreich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An intelligent model for supporting edge migration for virtual function chains in next generation internet of things]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27674-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27674-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - An intelligent model for supporting edge migration for virtual function chains in next generation internet of things]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design of highly nonlinear confusion component based on entangled points of quantum spin states]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28002-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28002-7"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Design of highly nonlinear confusion component based on entangled points of quantum spin states]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semantic wikis as flexible database interfaces for biomedical applications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27743-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27743-9"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Semantic wikis as flexible database interfaces for biomedical applications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video-based formative and summative assessment of surgical tasks using deep learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-26367-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-26367-9"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Video-based formative and summative assessment of surgical tasks using deep learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meshless optical mode solving using scalable deep deconvolutional neural network]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25613-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25613-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Meshless optical mode solving using scalable deep deconvolutional neural network]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design of highly nonlinear confusion component based on entangled points of quantum spin states]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28002-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28002-7"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Design of highly nonlinear confusion component based on entangled points of quantum spin states]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stabilization through self-coupling in networks of small-world and scale-free topology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27809-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27809-8"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Stabilization through self-coupling in networks of small-world and scale-free topology]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inference of monopartite networks from bipartite systems with different link types]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27744-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27744-8"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Inference of monopartite networks from bipartite systems with different link types]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gaining real-world industry experience through Break Through Tech AI at MIT]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2023/break-through-tech-ai-mit-0118</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/break-through-tech-ai-mit-0118"/>
        <updated>2023-01-18T21:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new experiential learning opportunity challenges undergraduates across the Greater Boston area to apply their AI skills to a range of industry projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Terri Park | MIT Schwarzman College of Computing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally, a Fast Algorithm for Shortest Paths on Negative Graphs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=122171</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/finally-a-fast-algorithm-for-shortest-paths-on-negative-graphs-20230118/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-18T17:02:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers can now find the shortest route through a network nearly as fast as theoretically possible, even when some steps can cancel out others.            
The post Finally, a Fast Algorithm for Shortest Paths on Negative Graphs first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Brubaker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Genes From the Mother Shape the Baby’s Microbiome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=122139</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/mobile-genes-from-the-mother-shape-the-babys-microbiome-20230117/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T16:43:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny genetic sequences in a mother’s bacteria seem to hop into the infant's bacteria, perhaps ensuring a healthy microbiome later in life.            
The post Mobile Genes From the Mother Shape the Baby’s Microbiome first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yasemin Saplakoglu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the archive: an economic model named after a goddess, and an ill-fated octopus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-00029-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-00029-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Snippets from Nature’s past.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using survey data to estimate the impact of the omicron variant on vaccine efficacy against COVID-19 infection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27951-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27951-3"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Using survey data to estimate the impact of the omicron variant on vaccine efficacy against COVID-19 infection]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the importance of structural equivalence in temporal networks for epidemic forecasting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28126-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28126-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - On the importance of structural equivalence in temporal networks for epidemic forecasting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distinctive physical insights driven from machine learning modelling of nuclear power plant severe accident scenario propagation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28205-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28205-y"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Distinctive physical insights driven from machine learning modelling of nuclear power plant severe accident scenario propagation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient gene–environment interaction testing through bootstrap aggregating]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28172-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28172-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Efficient gene–environment interaction testing through bootstrap aggregating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning classification of active tuberculosis lung zones wise manifestations using chest X-rays: a multi label approach]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28079-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28079-0"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Deep learning classification of active tuberculosis lung zones wise manifestations using chest X-rays: a multi label approach]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Predicting cascading extinctions and efficient restoration strategies in plant–pollinator networks via generalized positive feedback loops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27525-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27525-3"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Predicting cascading extinctions and efficient restoration strategies in plant–pollinator networks via generalized positive feedback loops]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convergence and Error Estimates of a Mixed Discontinuous Galerkin-Finite Element Method for the Semi-stationary Compressible Stokes System]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02096-7</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02096-7"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this paper, we study a mixed discontinuous Galerkin-finite element method (DG-FEM) for solving the semi-stationary compressible Stokes system in a bounded domain. The approximation of continuity equation is obtained by a piecewise constant discontinuous Galerkin method. The discretization of momentum equation is obtained by conforming Bernardi–Raugel finite elements. The convergence of mixed DG-FEM for nonlinear, isentropic stokes problem is rigorously established by compactness arguments and the existence analysis of Lions on the discrete level. Employing the continuous relative energy functional method and a detailed consistency analysis, we derive two error estimates for the numerical solution of the semi-stationary isentropic stokes system. In particular, we establish the 
                      
                      \(L^2\)
                      
                     error estimates for the pressure. All convergence results do not require the boundedness of numerical solutions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning based on parameterized physical forward model for adaptive holographic imaging with unpaired data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00584-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00584-3"/>
        <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The reconstruction of spatially resolved information of an extended object from an observed intensity diffraction pattern in holographic imaging is a challenging problem. By incorporating an explicit physical model, Lee and colleagues propose a deep learning method that can be used in holographic image reconstruction under physical perturbations and which generalizes well beyond object-to-sensor distances and pixel sizes seen during training.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting the socio-economic drivers of confidence in government with eXplainable Artificial Intelligence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28020-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-28020-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Detecting the socio-economic drivers of confidence in government with eXplainable Artificial Intelligence]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goal-Oriented Sensitivity Analysis of Hyperparameters in Deep Learning]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02083-4</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02083-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
Tackling new machine learning problems with neural networks always means optimizing numerous hyperparameters that define their structure and strongly impact their performances. In this work, we study the use of goal-oriented sensitivity analysis, based on the Hilbert–Schmidt independence criterion (HSIC), for hyperparameter analysis and optimization. Hyperparameters live in spaces that are often complex and awkward. They can be of different natures (categorical, discrete, boolean, continuous), interact, and have inter-dependencies. All this makes it non-trivial to perform classical sensitivity analysis. We alleviate these difficulties to obtain a robust analysis index that is able to quantify hyperparameters’ relative impact on a neural network’s final error. This valuable tool allows us to better understand hyperparameters and to make hyperparameter optimization more interpretable. We illustrate the benefits of this knowledge in the context of hyperparameter optimization and derive an HSIC-based optimization algorithm that we apply on MNIST and Cifar, classical machine learning data sets, but also on the approximation of Runge function and Bateman equations solution, of interest for scientific machine learning. This method yields neural networks that are both competitive and cost-effective.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Fictitious Domain Spectral Method for Solving the Helmholtz Equation in Exterior Domains]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02098-5</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02098-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
We extend the fictitious domain spectral method presented in Gu and Shen (SIAM J Sci Comput 43:A309–A329, 2021) for elliptic PDEs in bounded domains to the Helmhotlz equation in exterior domains. We first reduce the problem in an exterior domain to a bounded domain using the exact Dirichlet-to-Neumann operator. Next, we formulate the reduced problem into an equivalent problem in an annulus by using a fictitious domain approach. Then, we apply the Fourier-spectral method in the radial direction to reduce the problem in an annulus to a sequence of 1-D Bessel-type equations, each with a one-sided open boundary condition that are to be determined by the boundary condition of the original Helmholtz equation. We solve these 1-D Bessel-type equations by the Legendre-spectral method, and determine the open boundary conditions with a least square approach. We derive a wave number explicit error estimate for the special case of a circular obstacle, and provide ample numerical results to show the effectiveness of the proposed method.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast calculation of scattering patterns using hypergeometric function algorithms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27558-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27558-8"/>
        <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Fast calculation of scattering patterns using hypergeometric function algorithms]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computers that power self-driving cars could be a huge driver of global carbon emissions]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2023/autonomous-vehicles-carbon-emissions-0113</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/autonomous-vehicles-carbon-emissions-0113"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study shows that if autonomous vehicles are widely adopted, hardware efficiency will need to advance rapidly to keep computing-related emissions in check.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Zewe | MIT News Office</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prediction of continuous and discrete kinetic parameters in horses from inertial measurement units data using recurrent artificial neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27899-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27899-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Prediction of continuous and discrete kinetic parameters in horses from inertial measurement units data using recurrent artificial neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classification of red cell dynamics with convolutional and recurrent neural networks: a sickle cell disease case study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27718-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27718-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Classification of red cell dynamics with convolutional and recurrent neural networks: a sickle cell disease case study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Region-adaptive magnetic resonance image enhancement for improving CNN-based segmentation of the prostate and prostatic zones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27671-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27671-8"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Region-adaptive magnetic resonance image enhancement for improving CNN-based segmentation of the prostate and prostatic zones]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Device simulations with A U-Net model predicting physical quantities in two-dimensional landscapes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27599-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27599-z"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Device simulations with A U-Net model predicting physical quantities in two-dimensional landscapes]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimising remanufacturing decision-making using the bees algorithm in product digital twins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27631-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27631-2"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Optimising remanufacturing decision-making using the bees algorithm in product digital twins]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2022-23 Takeda Fellows: Leveraging AI to positively impact human health]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2023/takeda-fellows-leveraging-ai-positively-impact-human-health-0112</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/takeda-fellows-leveraging-ai-positively-impact-human-health-0112"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New fellows are working on health records, robot control, pandemic preparedness, brain injuries, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>School of Engineering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probability and Number Theory Collide — in a Moment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=122102</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/in-a-moment-mathematicians-merge-probability-and-number-theory-20230112/"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T15:37:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematicians are taking ideas developed to study random numbers and applying them to a broad range of categories.            
The post Probability and Number Theory Collide — in a Moment first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leila Sloman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engineering in harmony]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2023/frederick-ajisafe-music-aerospace-engineering-0112</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/frederick-ajisafe-music-aerospace-engineering-0112"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AeroAstro major and accomplished tuba player Frederick Ajisafe relishes the community he has found in the MIT Wind Ensemble.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Rosado | MIT News correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hunting for the best bioscience software tool? Check this database]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-00053-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-00053-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A data set funded by the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative shows how research software and tools are used across disciplines — and helps developers gain credit for their work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realizing acoustic qubit analogues with nonlinearly tunable phi-bits in externally driven coupled acoustic waveguides]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27427-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27427-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Realizing acoustic qubit analogues with nonlinearly tunable phi-bits in externally driven coupled acoustic waveguides]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple vehicle cooperation and collision avoidance in automated vehicles: survey and an AI-enabled conceptual framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27026-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27026-9"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Multiple vehicle cooperation and collision avoidance in automated vehicles: survey and an AI-enabled conceptual framework]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Translating single-cell genomics into cell types]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00600-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00600-6"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Machine translation of languages can now automatically detect different cell types from single-cell transcriptomic data. Such a feat opens the prospect of dissecting complex clinical samples such as heterogenous tumours at scale.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Converging orifice used to control the discharge rate of spherical particles from a flat floor silo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27431-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27431-8"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Converging orifice used to control the discharge rate of spherical particles from a flat floor silo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple vehicle cooperation and collision avoidance in automated vehicles: survey and an AI-enabled conceptual framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27026-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27026-9"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Multiple vehicle cooperation and collision avoidance in automated vehicles: survey and an AI-enabled conceptual framework]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using identification method to modelling short term luminous flux depreciation of LED luminaire to reducing electricity consumption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27925-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27925-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Using identification method to modelling short term luminous flux depreciation of LED luminaire to reducing electricity consumption]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identification of potent antimicrobial peptides via a machine-learning pipeline that mines the entire space of peptide sequences]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41551-022-00991-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41551-022-00991-2"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A machine-learning pipeline that mines the entire space of polypeptide-chain sequences can identify potent antimicrobial peptides by integrating tasks that gradually narrow down the search space.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Family of Fast Multi-resolution ENO Schemes for Compressible Flows]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02095-0</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02095-0"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this paper, a new class of high-order fast multi-resolution essentially non-oscillatory (FMRENO) schemes is proposed with an emphasis on both the performance and the computational efficiency. First, a new candidate stencil arrangement is developed for a multi-resolution representation of the local flow scales. A set of candidate stencils ranging from high- to low-order (from large to small stencils) is constructed in a hierarchical manner. Second, the monotonicity-preserving (MP) limiter is introduced as the regularity criterion of the candidate stencils. A candidate stencil, with which the reconstructed cell interface flux locates within the MP lower and upper bounds, is regarded to be smooth. Third, a multi-resolution stencil selection strategy, which prioritizes the stencils with better spectral property or higher-order accuracy meanwhile satisfying the MP criterion, is proposed. If all the candidate stencils are judged to be nonsmooth, the targeted stencil that violates the MP criterion the least is deployed as the final reconstruction instead. With this new framework, the desirable high-order accuracy is restored in the smooth regions while the sharp shock-capturing capability is achieved by selecting the targeted stencil satisfying the MP criterion most. Moreover, the new FMRENO schemes feature low numerical dissipation for resolving the broadband physical fluctuations by adaptively choosing the candidate stencil with better spectra or higher accuracy order based on the local flow regularity. Compared to the standard weighted/targeted essentially non-oscillatory (W/TENO) schemes, the computational efficiency is dramatically enhanced by avoiding the expensive evaluations of the classical smoothness indicators. A set of benchmark simulations demonstrate the performance of the new FMRENO schemes for handling complex fluid problems with a wide range of length scales.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A novel optimization method for belief rule base expert system with activation rate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27498-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27498-3"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A novel optimization method for belief rule base expert system with activation rate]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A reliable vaccine tracking and monitoring system for health clinics using blockchain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-26029-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-26029-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A reliable vaccine tracking and monitoring system for health clinics using blockchain]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Predicting efficacy of drug-carrier nanoparticle designs for cancer treatment: a machine learning-based solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27729-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27729-7"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Predicting efficacy of drug-carrier nanoparticle designs for cancer treatment: a machine learning-based solution]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controllable branching of robust response patterns in nonlinear mechanical resonators]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-35685-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-35685-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feedback control applied to mechanical resonators can lead to the formation of various complex dynamic behaviors. Here the authors demonstrate flexible and controllable switching between dynamical structures in the response of harmonically driven micro-mechanical resonators.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative hypergraph models and spectral embedding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27565-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27565-9"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Generative hypergraph models and spectral embedding]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient Approaches for Verifying the Existence and Bound of Inverse of Linear Operators in Hilbert Spaces]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02097-6</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02097-6"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
This paper describes some numerical verification procedures to prove the invertibility of a linear operator in Hilbert spaces and to compute a bound on the norm of its inverse. These approaches improve on previous procedures that use an orthogonal projection of the Hilbert space and its a priori error estimations. Several verified examples which confirm the effectiveness of the new procedures are presented.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multigrid Method for Nonlinear Eigenvalue Problems Based on Newton Iteration]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02070-9</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02070-9"/>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this paper, a novel multigrid method based on Newton iteration is proposed to solve nonlinear eigenvalue problems. Instead of handling the eigenvalue 
                      
                      \(\lambda \)
                      
                     and eigenfunction u separately, we treat the eigenpair 
                      
                      \((\lambda , u)\)
                      
                     as one element in a product space 
                      
                      \({\mathbb {R}} \times H_0^1(\Omega )\)
                      
                    . Then in the presented multigrid method, only one discrete linear boundary value problem needs to be solved for each level of the multigrid sequence. Because we avoid solving large-scale nonlinear eigenvalue problems directly, the overall efficiency is significantly improved. The optimal error estimate and linear computational complexity can be derived simultaneously. In addition, we also provide an improved multigrid method coupled with a mixing scheme to further guarantee the convergence and stability of the iteration scheme. More importantly, we prove convergence for the residuals after each iteration step. For nonlinear eigenvalue problems, such theoretical analysis is missing from the existing literatures on the mixing iteration scheme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A vision transformer architecture for the automated segmentation of retinal lesions in spectral domain optical coherence tomography images]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27616-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27616-1"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A vision transformer architecture for the automated segmentation of retinal lesions in spectral domain optical coherence tomography images]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning the dynamics of realistic models of C. elegans nervous system with recurrent neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25421-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25421-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Learning the dynamics of realistic models of C. elegans nervous system with recurrent neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High accuracy gender determination using the egg shape index]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27772-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27772-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - High accuracy gender determination using the egg shape index]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning the dynamics of realistic models of C. elegans nervous system with recurrent neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25421-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-25421-w"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Learning the dynamics of realistic models of C. elegans nervous system with recurrent neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automatic detection and vascular territory classification of hyperacute staged ischemic stroke on diffusion weighted image using convolutional neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27621-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27621-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Automatic detection and vascular territory classification of hyperacute staged ischemic stroke on diffusion weighted image using convolutional neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-supervised learning for remote sensing scene classification under the few shot scenario]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27313-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27313-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Self-supervised learning for remote sensing scene classification under the few shot scenario]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3D reconstruction of proximal femoral fracture from biplanar radiographs with fractural representative learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27607-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27607-2"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - 3D reconstruction of proximal femoral fracture from biplanar radiographs with fractural representative learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical error performance analysis for variational quantum circuit based functional regression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41534-022-00672-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41534-022-00672-7"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Quantum Information - Theoretical error performance analysis for variational quantum circuit based functional regression]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A quantum complexity lower bound from differential geometry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-022-01884-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-022-01884-6"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum operations can be considered as points in a high-dimensional space in which distance reflects the similarity of two operations. Applying differential-geometric methods in this picture gives insights into the complexity of quantum systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-supervised learning for remote sensing scene classification under the few shot scenario]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27313-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-27313-5"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Self-supervised learning for remote sensing scene classification under the few shot scenario]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3D reconstruction of proximal femoral fracture from biplanar radiographs with fractural representative learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27607-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-27607-2"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - 3D reconstruction of proximal femoral fracture from biplanar radiographs with fractural representative learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second Order, Unconditionally Stable, Linear Ensemble Algorithms for the Magnetohydrodynamics Equations]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-022-02091-4</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-022-02091-4"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
We propose two unconditionally stable, linear ensemble algorithms with pre-computable shared coefficient matrices across different realizations for the magnetohydrodynamics equations. The viscous terms are treated by a standard perturbative discretization. The nonlinear terms are discretized fully explicitly within the framework of the generalized positive auxiliary variable approach (GPAV). Artificial viscosity stabilization that modifies the kinetic energy is introduced to improve accuracy of the GPAV ensemble methods. Numerical results are presented to demonstrate the accuracy and robustness of the ensemble algorithms.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>