<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-09-26T00:52:29.213Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-09-26T00:52:29.213Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Longitudinal single-cell chemical imaging of engineered strains reveals heterogeneity in fatty acid production [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2021.07.26.453865v2?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2021.07.26.453865v2?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding metabolic heterogeneity is critical for optimizing microbial production of valuable chemicals, but requires tools that can quantify metabolites at the single-cell level over time. Here, we develop longitudinal hyperspectral stimulated Raman scattering (SRS) chemical imaging to directly visualize free fatty acids in engineered Escherichia coli over many cell cycles. We also develop compositional analysis to determine the chain length and unsaturation of the fatty acids in living cells. Our method reveals substantial heterogeneity in fatty acid production among and within colonies that emerges over the course of many generations. Interestingly, the strains display distinct types of production heterogeneity in an enzyme-dependent manner. By pairing time-lapse and SRS imaging, we examine the relationship between growth and production at the single-cell level. Single-cell quantification does not show a significant growth-production tradeoff in a strain that exhibits high production heterogeneity. Our results demonstrate that cell-to-cell production heterogeneity is pervasive and provide a means to link single-cell and population-level production.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tague, N.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing a Minimal Artificial Glycolytic Pathway [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.22.508994v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.22.508994v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The canonical glycolysis generates two molecules of acetyl-coenzyme A (acetyl-CoA) from one glucose through eleven cascade biochemical reactions. Here, we designed and constructed a Minimal Artificial Glycolytic (MAG) pathway consisting of only three types of biochemical reactions, with phosphoketolase as the core, combined with phosphatase and isomerase as auxiliary enzymes. It could theoretically achieve a 100% carbon yield to acetyl-CoA from any monosaccharide by integrating one-carbon condensation reaction. We tested the MAG pathway in vitro and in vivo, demonstrating the catabolism of typical C1-C6 carbohydrates to acetyl-CoA with yields from 82% to 95%. This novel glycolytic pathway provides a promising route for biomanufacturing with stoichiometric productivity from multiple carbon sources in the future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang, Y.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An approach towards identifying the site of interaction between the Streptomyces phage PhiC31 protein Gp3 and the coiled-coil domain of its serine integrase [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.24.509315v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.24.509315v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Streptomyces phage PhiC31 encodes a serine integrase which recombines the host (attB) and phage (attP) attachment sites to form new attL and attR sites. For attL and attR to be recombined by the integrase, the presence of its cognate recombination directionality factor (RDF) is required. It is hypothesized that the RDF binds the coiled-coil domain of the integrase to accomplish this switch in recombination directionality. Yet, nothing is known about the site of interaction between the RDF and integrase. Here, we tried to identify the region on the coiled-coil domain of PhiC31 integrase to which its cognate RDF (gp3) might bind. Mutant integrases fused to their cognate RDF (gp3) were created and selected for inactivity in attL x attR recombination. It was not possible to characterize the mutants and identify the Int-RDF binding region, due to unforeseen errors that occurred during the construction of the mutant library, but we demonstrated that simple experimental approaches could be used to identify this region. Despite this, an integrase mutant (P398L D595N) fused to gp3 was characterized. This mutant was catalyzing a more unidirectional attL x attR recombination reaction with reduced attP x attB recombination compared to the wild-type integrase. This mutant was selected since it could be used within the field of molecular biology to construct inversion switches which are a key element by which cells can be computerized.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Halablab, M.-L.-K.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novel multi epitope-based vaccine against monkeypox virus: vaccinomic approach]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20397-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20397-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Novel multi epitope-based vaccine against monkeypox virus: vaccinomic approach]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confrontation of AlphaFold models with experimental structures enlightens conformational dynamics supporting CYP102A1 functions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20390-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20390-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Confrontation of AlphaFold models with experimental structures enlightens conformational dynamics supporting CYP102A1 functions]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous directed evolution of a feedback-resistant Arabidopsis arogenate dehydratase in plantized E. coli [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.24.509247v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.24.509247v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous directed evolution (CDE) is a powerful tool for enzyme engineering due to the depth and scale of evolutionary search that it enables. If suitably controlled and calibrated, CDE could be widely applied in plant breeding and biotechnology to improve plant enzymes ex planta. We tested this concept by evolving Arabidopsis arogenate dehydratase (AtADT2) for resistance to feedback inhibition. We used an Escherichia coli platform with a phenylalanine biosynthesis pathway reconfigured (plantized) to mimic the plant pathway, a T7RNA polymerase-base deaminase hyper-mutation system (eMutaT7), and 4-fluorophenylalanine as selective agent. Selection schemes were pre-validated using a known feedback-resistant AtADT2 variant. We obtained variants that had 4-fluorophenylalanine resistance at least matching the known variant and that carried mutations in the ACT domain responsible for feedback inhibition. We conclude that ex planta CDE of plant enzymes in a microbial platform is a viable way to tailor characteristics that involve interaction with small molecules.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leong, B. J.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tunable dynamics in a multi-straintranscriptional pulse generator [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.23.509237v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.23.509237v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A major challenge in synthetic biology is the manipulation of engineered gene circuits toward a specified behavior. This challenge becomes more difficult as synthetic systems become more complex by incorporating additional genes or strains. Here we demonstrate that circuit dynamics can be tuned in synthetic consortia through the manipulation of strain fractions within the community. To do this, we constructed a microbial consortium comprised of three strains of engineered Escherichia coli that, when co-cultured, use homoserine lactone (HSL) mediated intercellular signaling to create a multi-strain incoherent type-1 feedforward loop (I1-FFL). Like naturally occurring I1-FFL motifs in gene networks, this engineered microbial consortium acts as a pulse generator of gene expression. We demonstrated that the amplitude of the pulse can be easily tuned by adjusting the relative population fractions of the strains. We created a mathematical model for the temporal dynamics of the microbial consortium and, using this model, identified population fractions that produced desired pulse characteristics. Our work demonstrates that intercellular gene circuits can be effectively tuned simply by adjusting the starting fractions of each strain type.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zong, D. M.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Kinetic Models Capture Cell-Free Metabolism for Improved Butanol Production [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.20.508127v2?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.20.508127v2?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cell-free systems are useful tools for prototyping metabolic pathways and optimizing the production of various bioproducts. Mechanistically-based kinetic models are uniquely suited to analyze dynamic experimental data collected from cell-free systems and provide vital qualitative insight. However, to date, dynamic kinetic models have not been applied with rigorous biological constraints or trained on adequate experimental data to the degree that they would give high confidence in predictions and broadly demonstrate the potential for widespread use of such kinetic models. In this work, we construct a large-scale dynamic model of cell-free metabolism with the goal of understanding and optimizing butanol production in a cell-free system. Using a novel combination of parameterization methods, the resultant model captures experimental metabolite measurements across two experimental conditions for nine metabolites at timepoints between 0 and 24 hours. We present analysis of the model predictions, provide recommendations for butanol optimization, and identify the aldehyde/alcohol dehydrogenase as the primary bottleneck in butanol production. Sensitivity analysis further reveals the extent to which various parameters are constrained, and our approach for probing valid parameter ranges can be applied to other modeling efforts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin, J. P.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[origamiFISH allows universal, label-free, single molecule visualization of DNA origami nanodevices across biological samples [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.19.508533v2?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.19.508533v2?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Structural DNA nanotechnology enables user-prescribed design of DNA nanostructures (DNs) for biological applications, but how DN design determines their bio-distribution and cellular interactions remain poorly understood. One challenge is that current methods for tracking DN fates in situ, including fluorescent-dye labeling, suffer from low sensitivity and dye-induced artifacts. Here we present origamiFISH, a label-free and universal method for single-molecule fluorescence detection of DNA origami nanostructures in cells and tissues. origamiFISH targets pan-DN scaffold sequences with hybridization chain reaction (HCR) probes to achieve thousand-fold signal amplification. We identify cell-type and shape-specific spatiotemporal uptake patterns within 1 minute of uptake and at picomolar DN concentrations, 10,000x lower than field standards. We additionally optimized compatibility with immunofluorescence and tissue clearing to visualize DN distribution within tissue cryo/vibratome-sections, slice cultures, and whole-mount organoids. Together, origamiFISH enables faithful mapping of DN interactions across subcellular and tissue barriers for guiding the development of DN-based therapeutics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wang, W. X.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State space methods for phase amplitude coupling analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18475-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18475-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - State space methods for phase amplitude coupling analysis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identification of potential modulators of IFITM3 by in-silico modeling and virtual screening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20259-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20259-8"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Identification of potential modulators of IFITM3 by in-silico modeling and virtual screening]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TIAToolbox as an end-to-end library for advanced tissue image analytics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43856-022-00186-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43856-022-00186-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pocock, Graham et al. present TIAToolbox, a Python toolbox for computational pathology. The extendable library can be used for data loading, pre-processing, model inference, post-processing, and visualization.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The effects of microclimatic winter conditions in urban areas on the risk of establishment for Aedes albopictus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20436-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20436-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - The effects of microclimatic winter conditions in urban areas on the risk of establishment for Aedes albopictus]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lead-exposure associated miRNAs in humans and Alzheimer’s disease as potential biomarkers of the disease and disease processes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20305-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20305-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Lead-exposure associated miRNAs in humans and Alzheimer’s disease as potential biomarkers of the disease and disease processes]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bell-Evans model and steered molecular dynamics in uncovering the dissociation kinetics of ligands targeting G-protein-coupled receptors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20065-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20065-2"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Bell-Evans model and steered molecular dynamics in uncovering the dissociation kinetics of ligands targeting G-protein-coupled receptors]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synthetic neuromorphic computing in living cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33288-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33288-8"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Computational properties of neuronal networks have been applied to computing systems using simplified models comprising repeated connected nodes. Here the authors create layered assemblies of genetically encoded devices that perform non-binary logic computation and signal processing using combinatorial promoters and feedback regulation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Targeting non-coding RNA family members with artificial endonuclease XNAzymes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03987-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03987-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Engineered RNA endonuclease XNAzymes can specifically target individual disease-associated non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) in vitro with potential as platform technology for precision detection or knockdown of individual microRNAs or longer ncRNAs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Novel Split Intein-Mediated Enzymatic Channeling Accelerates the Multimeric Bioconversion Pathway of Ginsenoside]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00216</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00216"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00216]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cho-Heun Lee, Jun-Hyoung Lee, Ju Young Lee, Chang-Hao Cui, Byung-Kwan Cho, and Sun-Chang Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Engineered Spore-Forming <italic toggle="yes">Bacillus</italic> as a Microbial Vessel for Long-Term DNA Data Storage]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00291</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00291"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00291]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Feng Liu, Jiashu Li, Tongzhou Zhang, Jun Chen, and Chun Loong Ho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards the creation of Acholeplasma laidlawii driven by synthetic genomes [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.21.508766v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.21.508766v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Assembling synthetic bacterial genomes in yeast and genome transplantation has enabled an unmatched level of bacterial strain engineering, giving rise to cells with minimal and chemically synthetic genomes. However, this technology is currently limited to members of the Spiroplasma phylogenetic group, mostly Mycoplasmas, within the Mollicute class. Here, we propose the development of these technologies for Acholeplasma laidlawii, which is phylogenetically distant from Mycoplasmas and, unlike most Mollicutes, uses a standard genetic code. Towards this goal, we first investigated a donor-recipient relationship between two A. laidlawii strains through whole-genome sequencing. We then created a multi-host shuttle plasmid and used it to optimize an electroporation protocol. For genome transplantation, we selected A. laidlawii 8195 as the recipient strain and we created a PG-8A donor strain by inserting a Tn5 transposon carrying a tetracycline resistance gene. Our optimized genetic tools will accelerate the creation of Acholeplasma strains driven by synthetic genomes.

Graphical Abstract

O_FIG O_LINKSMALLFIG WIDTH=200 HEIGHT=98 SRC="FIGDIR/small/508766v1_ufig1.gif" ALT="Figure 1">
View larger version (34K):
org.highwire.dtl.DTLVardef@d9ac55org.highwire.dtl.DTLVardef@c13f75org.highwire.dtl.DTLVardef@12d500dorg.highwire.dtl.DTLVardef@1e2ba66_HPS_FORMAT_FIGEXP  M_FIG C_FIG]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nucifora, D. P.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Specific Codons Control Cellular Resources and Fitness [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.21.508913v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.21.508913v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As biotechnology research progresses from simply overexpressing proteins to creating intricate metabolic pathways, gene circuits, and complex phenotypes, harmonizing gene fitness in the context of a host organism has become essential. A significant amount of recent work has focused on decoupling gene expression from host resources to improve the outcome of synthetic biology and metabolic engineering efforts. While insightful, few of these studies have investigated the mechanistic underpinnings of resource allocation during translation elongation. There is a degeneracy in codons - but they are not equivalent. While there is an understanding that codon use is unequal in native genes, there is less knowledge of how this usage bias modulates the supply and demand of protein translation resources. Here we investigate how the partitioning of microbial translational resources, specifically through allocation of tRNA by incorporating dissimilar codon usage bias, can drastically alter expression of proteins and reduce the burden on the host resources. By isolating individual codons experimentally, we find heterologous gene expression can trans-regulate fitness of the host and other heterologous genes. Interestingly, specific codons drive profitable or catastrophic phenotypic outcomes. We correlate codon usage patterns with genetic fitness and empirically derive a novel coding scheme for multi-gene expression called Codon Harmony Index (CHI, {chi}). CHI enables the design of harmonious multi-gene expression systems while avoiding catastrophic cellular burden.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Love, A. M.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Golden Standard: A complete standard, portable, and interoperative MoClo tool for model and non-model bacterial hosts [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.20.508659v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.20.508659v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modular cloning assembly has become a benchmark technology in synthetic biology. However, there is a mismatch between its impressive development and the standardization required to promote interoperability between the different systems available. The full development of the field is thus hampered by a surge of oftentimes incompatible organism-specific systems. To overcome these issues, we present Golden Standard (GS), a Type IIS assembly method underpinned by the Standard European Vector Architecture (SEVA). GS unlocks modular cloning applications with any type of microorganism and delivers consistent combinatorial multi-part assembly of standardized genetic elements to create genetic circuits of up to twenty transcription units. Reliance on the Golden Gate syntax renders GS fully compatible with many existing tools and it sets the path towards efficient reusability of available part libraries and assembled TUs. GS was fully validated in terms of DNA assembly performance, portability and phenotype engineering in model and non-model bacteria. In order to facilitate the widespread adoption and future community-driven development of GS, we provide a web-portal featuring: i) a repository of parts and vectors, ii) a SBOLHub for exchange and analysis of constructs and iii) Wizard and Setup tools to guide the design of constructs using stored and user-specific parts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Blazquez, B.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Normalizing cancer RNA-seq data for library size, tumor purity and batch effects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41587-022-01441-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41587-022-01441-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accurate identification and effective removal of unwanted variation is essential to derive meaningful biological results from large and complex RNA-seq studies. Technical replicates together with negative and positive control genes are key tools for carrying out this task. We show how to proceed when technical replicates are unavailable.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Publisher Correction: Age-dependent sex differences in cardiometabolic risk factors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44161-022-00146-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44161-022-00146-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature Cardiovascular Research - Publisher Correction: Age-dependent sex differences in cardiometabolic risk factors]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data mining-based discriminant analysis as a tool for the study of egg quality in native hen breeds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20111-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20111-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Data mining-based discriminant analysis as a tool for the study of egg quality in native hen breeds]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identification and expression of functionally conserved circadian clock genes in lichen-forming fungi]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19646-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19646-y"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Identification and expression of functionally conserved circadian clock genes in lichen-forming fungi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ADGRL3 genomic variation implicated in neurogenesis and ADHD links functional effects to the incretin polypeptide GIP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20343-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20343-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - ADGRL3 genomic variation implicated in neurogenesis and ADHD links functional effects to the incretin polypeptide GIP]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A 3D image-based modelling approach for understanding spatiotemporal processes in phosphorus fertiliser dissolution, soil buffering and uptake by plant roots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19047-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19047-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A 3D image-based modelling approach for understanding spatiotemporal processes in phosphorus fertiliser dissolution, soil buffering and uptake by plant roots]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simultaneous prediction of risk for multiple common diseases using metabolomics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-022-01992-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-022-01992-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Early identification of at-risk people is critical in disease prevention, but current screening approaches are resource intensive and are often restricted to one disease at a time. We show how nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy–derived metabolomics profiles can be used to predict multi-disease risk for the onset of 24 common conditions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[STAR sleep recording export software for automatic export and anonymization of sleep studies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19892-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19892-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - STAR sleep recording export software for automatic export and anonymization of sleep studies]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using multiple sampling strategies to estimate SARS-CoV-2 epidemiological parameters from genomic sequencing data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32812-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32812-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SARS-CoV-2 genome sequencing data can be used to infer epidemiological parameters, but the impact of the strategy used to select samples on these estimates is rarely considered. Here, the authors produce estimates using different sampling strategies and compare results to those based on case reporting data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A distinct symptom pattern emerges for COVID-19 long-haul: a nationwide study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20214-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20214-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A distinct symptom pattern emerges for COVID-19 long-haul: a nationwide study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recursive state and parameter estimation of COVID-19 circulating variants dynamics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18208-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18208-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Recursive state and parameter estimation of COVID-19 circulating variants dynamics]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synaptic plasticity in self-powered artificial striate cortex for binocular orientation selectivity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33393-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33393-8"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Designing efficient bio-inspired vision systems remains a challenge. Here, the authors report a bio-inspired striate visual cortex with binocular and orientation selective receptive field based on self-powered memristor to enable machine vision with brisk edge and corner detection in the future applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activation of stably silenced genes by recruitment of a synthetic de-methylating module]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33181-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33181-4"/>
        <updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stably silenced genes with methylated CpG at the promoter are refractory to current CRISPR activation systems. Here the authors create a more robust activation system, TETact that recruits DNA-demethylating TET1 with transcriptional activators.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cell Rover: Exploring and augmenting the inner world of the cell]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/cell-rover-exploring-augmenting-inner-world-cell-0922</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/cell-rover-exploring-augmenting-inner-world-cell-0922"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T15:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIT researchers demonstrate an intracellular antenna that's compatible with 3D biological systems and can operate wirelessly inside a living cell.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michaela Jarvis | MIT Media Lab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Math of Wrinkling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=119021</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-new-math-of-wrinkling-patterns-20220922/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T15:05:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A comprehensive mathematical framework treats wrinkling patterns as elegant solutions to geometric problems.            
The post The New Math of Wrinkling first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Ornes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] A <italic toggle="yes">p</italic>‑Coumaroyl-CoA Biosensor for Dynamic Regulation of Naringenin Biosynthesis in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Saccharomyces cerevisiae</named-content>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00111</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00111"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00111]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dany Liu, Maria Sole Sica, Jiwei Mao, Lucy Fang-I Chao, and Verena Siewers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical systems defined on simplicial complexes: Symmetries, conjugacies, and invariant subspaces]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0093842?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0093842?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T02:59:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We consider the general model for dynamical systems defined on a simplicial complex. We describe the conjugacy classes of these systems and show how symmetries in a given simplicial complex manifest in the dynamics defined thereon, especially with regard to invariant subspaces in the dynamics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eddie Nijholt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structural position vectors and symmetries in complex networks]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0107583?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0107583?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T02:59:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Symmetries, due to their fundamental importance to dynamical processes on networks, have attracted a great deal of current research. Finding all symmetric nodes in large complex networks typically relies on automorphism groups from algebraic-group theory, which are solvable in quasipolynomial time. We articulate a conceptually appealing and computationally extremely efficient approach to finding and characterizing all symmetric nodes by introducing a structural position vector (SPV) for each node in networks. We establish the mathematical result that symmetric nodes must have the same SPV value and demonstrate, using six representative complex networks from the real world, that all symmetric nodes in these networks can be found in linear time. Furthermore, the SPVs not only characterize the similarity of nodes but also quantify the nodal influences in propagation dynamics. A caveat is that the proved mathematical result relating the SPV values to nodal symmetries is not sufficient; i.e., nodes having the same SPV values may not be symmetric, which arises in regular networks or networks with a dominant regular component. We point out with an analysis that this caveat is, in fact, shared by the known existing approaches to finding symmetric nodes in the literature. We further argue, with the aid of a mathematical analysis, that our SPV method is generally effective for finding the symmetric nodes in real-world networks that typically do not have a dominant regular component. Our SPV-based framework, therefore, provides a physically intuitive and computationally efficient way to uncover, understand, and exploit symmetric structures in complex networks arising from real-world applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yong-Shang Long</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matrix coupling and generalized frustration in Kuramoto oscillators]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0108672?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0108672?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T02:59:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The Kuramoto model describes the synchronization of coupled oscillators that have different natural frequencies. Among the many generalizations of the original model, Kuramoto and Sakaguchi (KS) proposed a frustrated version that resulted in dynamic behavior of the order parameter, even when the average natural frequency of the oscillators is zero. Here, we consider a generalization of the frustrated KS model that exhibits new transitions to synchronization. The model is identical in form to the original Kuramoto model but written in terms of unit vectors and with the coupling constant replaced by a coupling matrix. The matrix breaks the rotational symmetry and forces the order parameter to point in the direction of the eigenvector with the highest eigenvalue, when the eigenvalues are real. For complex eigenvalues, the module of order parameter oscillates while it rotates around the unit circle, creating active states. We derive the complete phase diagram for the Lorentzian distribution of frequencies using the Ott–Antonsen ansatz. We also show that changing the average value of the natural frequencies leads to further phase transitions where the module of the order parameter goes from oscillatory to static.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guilhermo L. Buzanello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The qualitative and quantitative relationships between pattern formation and average degree in networked reaction-diffusion systems]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0107504?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0107504?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T02:59:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The Turing pattern is an important dynamic behavior characteristic of activator–inhibitor systems. Differentiating from traditional assumption of activator–inhibitor interactions in a spatially continuous domain, a Turing pattern in networked reaction-diffusion systems has received much attention during the past few decades. In spite of its great progress, it still fails to evaluate the precise influences of network topology on pattern formation. To this end, we try to promote the research on this important and interesting issue from the point of view of average degree—a critical topological feature of networks. We first qualitatively analyze the influence of average degree on pattern formation. Then, a quantitative relationship between pattern formation and average degree, the exponential decay of pattern formation, is proposed via nonlinear regression. The finding holds true for several activator–inhibitor systems including biology model, ecology model, and chemistry model. The significance of this study lies that the exponential decay not only quantitatively depicts the influence of average degree on pattern formation, but also provides the possibility for predicting and controlling pattern formation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lili Chang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health digital twins as tools for precision medicine: Considerations for computation, implementation, and regulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-022-00694-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-022-00694-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Digital Medicine - Health digital twins as tools for precision medicine: Considerations for computation, implementation, and regulation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved tracking via cell region fingerprints]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01525-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01525-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TracX shows that fast proofreading of track assignments leads to improved cell tracking performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A machine learning-based SNP-set analysis approach for identifying disease-associated susceptibility loci]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19708-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19708-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A machine learning-based SNP-set analysis approach for identifying disease-associated susceptibility loci]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A pipeline for automated deep learning liver segmentation (PADLLS) from contrast enhanced CT exams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20108-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20108-8"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A pipeline for automated deep learning liver segmentation (PADLLS) from contrast enhanced CT exams]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development of a new toolbox for mouse PET–CT brain image analysis fully based on CT images and validation in a PD mouse model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19872-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19872-4"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Development of a new toolbox for mouse PET–CT brain image analysis fully based on CT images and validation in a PD mouse model]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Massive annotation of bacterial l-asparaginases reveals their puzzling distribution and frequent gene transfer events]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19689-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19689-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Massive annotation of bacterial l-asparaginases reveals their puzzling distribution and frequent gene transfer events]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analyzing integrated network of methylation and gene expression profiles in lung squamous cell carcinoma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20232-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-20232-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Analyzing integrated network of methylation and gene expression profiles in lung squamous cell carcinoma]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixing patterns and the spread of pandemics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00312-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00312-2"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Integrating social mixing data into epidemic models can help policy makers better understand epidemic spread. However, empirical mixing data might not be immediately available in most populations. In a recent work, a network model methodology is proposed to construct micro-level social mixing structure when empirical data are not available.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlphaFold developers win US$3-million Breakthrough Prize]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-02999-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-02999-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DeepMind’s system for predicting the 3D structure of proteins is among five recipients of science’s most lucrative awards.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping track of the T cells that matter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43018-022-00432-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43018-022-00432-8"/>
        <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The identification of tumor-reactive T cells using phenotypic markers is now well established in treatment-naive tumors. It is unclear, however, whether these markers can also be useful after immune checkpoint blockade (ICB). A new study finds that CXCL13 expression robustly identifies tumor-reactive T cells before and after ICB and is associated with treatment response.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Temperature Superconductivity Understood at Last]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118980</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/high-temperature-superconductivity-understood-at-last-20220921/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-21T14:06:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new atomic-scale experiment all but settles the origin of the strong form of superconductivity seen in cuprate crystals, confirming a 35-year-old theory.            
The post High-Temperature Superconductivity Understood at Last first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Light-Dependent Control of Bacterial Expression at the mRNA Level]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00365</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00365"/>
        <updated>2022-09-21T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00365]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Américo T. Ranzani, Markus Wehrmann, Jennifer Kaiser, Marc Juraschitz, Anna M. Weber, Georg Pietruschka, Uwe Gerken, Günter Mayer, and Andreas Möglich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Precise Genomic Riboregulator Control of Metabolic Flux in Microbial Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00638</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00638"/>
        <updated>2022-09-21T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.1c00638]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Naresh Pandey, Steffi A. Davison, Malathy Krishnamurthy, Daniel S. Trettel, Chien-Chi Lo, Shawn Starkenburg, Katherine L. Wozniak, Theresa L. Kern, Sean D. Reardon, Clifford J. Unkefer, Scott P. Hennelly, and Taraka Dale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A de novo matrix for macroscopic living materials from bacteria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33191-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33191-2"/>
        <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Engineered living materials (ELMs) embed living cells in a biopolymer matrix to create novel materials with tailored functions. In this work, the authors engineered bacteria to grow novel macroscopic materials that can be reshaped, functionalized, and used to filter contaminated water while also showing that the stiffness of these materials can be tuned through genetic changes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Do Fireflies Flash in Sync? Studies Suggest a New Answer.]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118926</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-do-fireflies-flash-in-sync-studies-suggest-a-new-answer-20220920/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T14:36:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Field research suggests a new explanation for the synchronized flashing in fireflies and confirms that a novel form of “chimeric” synchrony occurs naturally.            
The post How Do Fireflies Flash in Sync? Studies Suggest a New Answer. first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Sokol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[virDTL: Viral Recombination Analysis Through Phylogenetic Reconciliation and Its Application to Sarbecoviruses and SARS-CoV-2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0507?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0507?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sumaira Zaman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] A Versatile in Vivo DNA Assembly Toolbox for Fungal Strain Engineering]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00159</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00159"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00159]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zofia Dorota Jarczynska, Katherina Garcia Vanegas, Marcus Deichmann, Christina Nrskov Jensen, Marouschka Jasmijn Scheeper, Malgorzata Ewa Futyma, Tomas Strucko, Fabiano Jares Contesini, Tue Sparholt Jrgensen, Jakob Blæsbjerg Hoof, and Uffe Hasbro Mortensen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synchronization of Belousov–Zhabotinsky oscillators with electrochemical coupling in a spontaneous process]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096689?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096689?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T01:48:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
A passive electrochemical coupling approach is proposed to induce spontaneous synchronization between chemical oscillators. The coupling exploits the potential difference between a catalyst redox couple in the Belousov–Zhabotinsky (BZ) reaction, without external feedback, to induce surface reactions that impact the kinetics of the bulk system. The effect of coupling in BZ oscillators under batch condition is characterized using phase synchronization measures. Although the frequency of the oscillators decreases nonlinearly over time, by a factor of 2 or more within 100 cycles, the coupling is strong enough to maintain synchronization. In such a highly drifting system, the Gibbs–Shannon entropy of the cyclic phase difference distribution can be used to quantify the coupling effect. We extend the Oregonator BZ model to account for the drifting natural frequencies in batch condition and for electrochemical coupling, and numerical simulations of the effect of acid concentration on synchronization patterns are in agreement with the experiments. Because of the passive nature of coupling, the proposed coupling scheme can open avenues for designing pattern recognition and neuromorphic computation systems using chemical reactions in a spontaneous process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yifan Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transport and nonequilibrium phase transitions in polygonal urn models]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0101933?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0101933?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T01:48:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We study the deterministic dynamics of [math] point particles moving at a constant speed in a 2D table made of two polygonal urns connected by an active rectangular channel, which applies a feedback control on the particles, inverting the horizontal component of their velocities when their number in the channel exceeds a fixed threshold. Such a bounce-back mechanism is non-dissipative: it preserves volumes in phase space. An additional passive channel closes the billiard table forming a circuit in which a stationary current may flow. Under specific constraints on the geometry and on the initial conditions, the large [math] limit allows nonequilibrium phase transitions between homogeneous and inhomogeneous phases. The role of ergodicity in making a probabilistic theory applicable is discussed for both rational and irrational urns. The theoretical predictions are compared with the numerical simulation results. Connections with the dynamics of feedback-controlled biological systems are highlighted.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emilio N. M. Cirillo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Group percolation in interdependent networks with reinforcement network layer]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0091342?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0091342?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T01:48:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
In many real-world interdependent network systems, nodes often work together to form groups, which can enhance robustness to resist risks. However, previous group percolation models are always of a first-order phase transition, regardless of the group size distribution. This motivates us to investigate a generalized model for group percolation in interdependent networks with a reinforcement network layer to eliminate collapse. Some backup devices that are equipped for a density [math] of reinforced nodes constitute the reinforcement network layer. For each group, we assume that at least one node of the group can function in one network and a node in another network depends on the group to function. We find that increasing the density [math] of reinforcement nodes and the size [math] of the dependency group can significantly enhance the robustness of interdependent networks. Importantly, we find the existence of a hybrid phase transition behavior and propose a method for calculating the shift point of percolation types. The most interesting finding is the exact universal solution to the minimal density [math] of reinforced nodes (or the minimum group size [math]) to prevent abrupt collapse for Erdős–Rényi, scale-free, and regular random interdependent networks. Furthermore, we present the validity of the analytic solutions for a triple point [math] (or [math]), the corresponding phase transition point [math], and second-order phase transition points [math] in interdependent networks. These findings might yield a broad perspective for designing more resilient interdependent infrastructure networks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qian Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Application of the Slater criteria to localize invariant tori in Hamiltonian mappings]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0103427?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0103427?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T01:48:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We investigate the localization of invariant spanning curves for a family of two-dimensional area-preserving mappings described by the dynamical variables [math] and [math] by using Slater’s criterion. The Slater theorem says there are three different return times for an irrational translation over a circle in a given interval. The returning time, which measures the number of iterations a map needs to return to a given periodic or quasi periodic region, has three responses along an invariant spanning curve. They are related to a continued fraction expansion used in the translation and obey the Fibonacci sequence. The rotation numbers for such curves are related to a noble number, leading to a devil’s staircase structure. The behavior of the rotation number as a function of invariant spanning curves located by Slater’s criterion resulted in an expression of a power law in which the absolute value of the exponent is equal to the control parameter [math] that controls the speed of the divergence of [math] in the limit the action [math] is sufficiently small.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yoná H. Huggler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Screening microbially produced Δ9-tetrahydrocannabinol using a yeast biosensor workflow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33207-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33207-x"/>
        <updated>2022-09-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microbial production of cannabinoids promises a cheaper and more sustainable route to these important therapeutic molecules, but strain improvement and screening is challenging. Here, the authors develop a yeast-based Δ9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) biosensor for screening microbial mutant libraries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Mathematical Curves Enable Advanced Communication]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118880</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-mathematical-curves-power-cryptography-20220919/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T14:44:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A simple geometric idea has been used to power advances in information theory, cryptography and even blockchain technology.            
The post How Mathematical Curves Enable Advanced Communication first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordana Cepelewicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resilience of supply-chain systems under perturbations: A network approach]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096983?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096983?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T12:42:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Supply-chain systems (SCSs) are an indispensable part of our daily infrastructures. Note that a small perturbation in a SCS can be amplified, eliciting cascading failures. It is of significant value to ensure a high resilience of SCSs. However, due to the complexity of SCSs, it is quite challenging to study their resilience under conditions of perturbations. In view of this, this paper presents a complex network perspective toward the resilience of SCSs. To achieve this goal, a complex SCS is modeled as a multilayer supply-chain network (SCN) with physical organizations being modeled as nodes and interactions among them as edges. A modeled SCN contains three types of nodes, i.e., suppliers, manufacturers, and retailers. An algorithm is proposed to construct a multilayer SCN. For each layer of a multilayer SCN, two kinds of networks, i.e., networks with Poisson degree distributions and networks with power-law degree distributions, are considered. For a given multilayer SCN, a ripple-effect network model is proposed to analyze its resilience under perturbations. Regarding the perturbations, two scenarios, i.e., random node failures and target node failures, are adopted in this research. In order to validate the effectiveness of the proposed network perspective, simulations on computer-generated SCNs are carried out. Interestingly, it is found that the resilience of SCNs under both random and target perturbations presents a discontinuous phase-change phenomenon, which indicates that SCNs are quite fragile under perturbations. It is further noticed that SCNs with power-law degree distributions are relatively more robust than SCNs with Poisson degree distributions. Although SCNs are found to be fragile, it has been discovered that denser interactions between different system organizations can enhance the network’s resilience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weiwei Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic scaling and stochastic fractal in nucleation and growth processes]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097417?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097417?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T12:42:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
A class of nucleation and growth models of a stable phase is investigated for various different growth velocities. It is shown that for growth velocities [math] and [math], where [math] and [math] are the mean domain size of the metastable phase (M-phase) and the mean nucleation time, respectively, the M-phase decays following a power law. Furthermore, snapshots at different time [math] that are taken to collect data for the distribution function [math] of the domain size [math] of the M-phase are found to obey dynamic scaling. Using the idea of data-collapse, we show that each snapshot is a self-similar fractal. However, for [math], such as in the classical Kolmogorov–Johnson–Mehl–Avrami model, and for [math], the decays of the M-phase are exponential and they are not accompanied by dynamic scaling. We find a perfect agreement between numerical simulation and analytical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amit Lahiri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Erratum: “Saddle-center and periodic orbit: Dynamics near symmetric heteroclinic connection” [Chaos 31, 023113 (2021)]]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0121435?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0121435?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T12:42:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. M. Lerman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Transcriptional Reactivation of Lignin Biosynthesis for the Heterologous Production of Etoposide Aglycone in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Nicotiana benthamiana</named-content>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00289</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00289"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00289]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stacie S. Kim, Diego L. Wengier, Carin J. Ragland, and Elizabeth S. Sattely</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biosynthesis of plant hemostatic dencichine in Escherichia coli]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33255-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33255-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biosynthetic pathway of dencichine, a plant derived nature product that has found various pharmacological applications, is still elusive. Here, the authors design artificial pathways through retro-biosynthesis approaches and achieve its efficient production in E. coli by systematic metabolic and enzymatic engineering.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A global synchronization theorem for oscillators on a random graph]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0090443?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0090443?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T12:44:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Consider [math] identical Kuramoto oscillators on a random graph. Specifically, consider Erdős–Rényi random graphs in which any two oscillators are bidirectionally coupled with unit strength, independently and at random, with probability [math]. We say that a network is globally synchronizing if the oscillators converge to the all-in-phase synchronous state for almost all initial conditions. Is there a critical threshold for [math] above which global synchrony is extremely likely but below which it is extremely rare? It is suspected that a critical threshold exists and is close to the so-called connectivity threshold, namely, [math] for [math]. Ling, Xu, and Bandeira made the first progress toward proving a result in this direction: they showed that if [math], then Erdős–Rényi networks of Kuramoto oscillators are globally synchronizing with high probability as [math]. Here, we improve that result by showing that [math] suffices. Our estimates are explicit: for example, we can say that there is more than a [math] chance that a random network with [math] and [math] is globally synchronizing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Kassabov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riemann–Hilbert approach to two-component modified short-pulse system and its nonlocal reductions]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0088293?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0088293?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T12:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
In this paper, a Riemann–Hilbert approach to a two-component modified short-pulse (mSP) system on the line with zero boundary conditions is developed. A parametric representation of the solution to the related Cauchy problem is obtained. Four nonlocal integrable reductions, namely, the real reverse space-time nonlocal focusing and defocusing mSP equations and the complex reverse space-time nonlocal focusing and defocusing mSP equations, are studied in detail. For each case, soliton solutions are presented, and, unlike their local counterparts, the nonlocal equations exhibit certain novel properties induced by the impact of nonlocality.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cong Lv</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patched patterns and emergence of chaotic interfaces in arrays of nonlocally coupled excitable systems]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0111507?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0111507?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T12:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We disclose a new class of patterns, called patched patterns, in arrays of non-locally coupled excitable units with attractive and repulsive interactions. The self-organization process involves the formation of two types of patches, majority and minority ones, characterized by uniform average spiking frequencies. Patched patterns may be temporally periodic, quasiperiodic, or chaotic, whereby chaotic patterns may further develop interfaces comprised of units with average frequencies in between those of majority and minority patches. Using chaos and bifurcation theory, we demonstrate that chaos typically emerges via a torus breakup and identify the secondary bifurcation that gives rise to chaotic interfaces. It is shown that the maximal Lyapunov exponent of chaotic patched patterns does not decay, but rather converges to a finite value with system size. Patched patterns with a smaller wavenumber may exhibit diffusive motion of chaotic interfaces, similar to that of the incoherent part of chimeras.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Igor Franović</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Target recovery of the economic system based on the target reinforcement path method]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097175?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097175?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T12:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
An effective and stable operation of an economic system leads to a prosperous society and sustainable world development. Unfortunately, the system faces inevitable perturbations of extreme events and is frequently damaged. To maintain the system's stability, recovering its damaged functionality is essential and is complementary to strengthening its resilience and forecasting extreme events. This paper proposes a target recovery method based on network and economic equilibrium theories to defend the economic system against perturbations characterized as localized attacks. This novel method stimulates a set of economic sectors that mutually reinforce damaged economic sectors and is intuitively named the target reinforcement path (TRP) method. Developing a nonlinear dynamic model that simulates the economic system's operation after being perturbed by a localized attack and recovering based on a target recovery method, we compute the relaxation time for this process to quantify the method's efficiency. Furthermore, we adopt a rank aggregation method to comprehensively measure the method's efficiency by studying the target recovery of three country-level economic systems (China, India, and Japan) for 73 different regional attack scenarios. Through a comparative analysis of the TRP method and three other classic methods, the TRP method is shown to be more effective and less costly. Applicatively, the proposed method exhibits the potential to recover other vital complex systems with spontaneous recovery ability, such as immune, neurological, and ecological systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ze Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instability of oscillations in the Rosenzweig–MacArthur model of one consumer and two resources]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0105340?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0105340?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T12:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The system of two resources [math] and [math] and one consumer [math] is investigated within the Rosenzweig–MacArthur model with a Holling type II functional response. The rates of consumption of particular resources are normalized as to keep their sum constant. Dynamic switching is introduced as to increase the variable [math] in a process of finite speed. The space of parameters where both resources coexist is explored numerically. The results indicate that oscillations of [math] and mutually synchronized [math], which appear equal for the rates of consumption, are destabilized when these rates are modified. Then, the system is driven to one of fixed points or to a limit cycle with a much smaller amplitude. As a consequence of symmetry between the resources, the consumer cannot change the preferred resource once it is chosen.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Przemysław Gawroński</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying the spatiotemporal organization of high-traffic events in a mobile communication system using event synchronization and complex networks]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0083137?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0083137?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T12:43:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
In mobile communication systems, congestion is related to high-traffic events (HTEs) that occur in the coverage areas of base stations. Understanding, recognizing, and predicting these HTEs and researching their occurrence rules provides theoretical and decision-making support for preventing system congestion. Communication sectors are regarded as nodes, and if HTEs occur synchronously among sectors, then the corresponding nodes are connected. The total number of synchronous HTEs determines the edge weights. The mobile-communication spatiotemporal data are mapped to a weighted network, with the occurrence locations of HTEs as the basic elements. Network analysis provides a structure for representing the interaction of HTEs. By analyzing the topological features of the event synchronization network, the associations among the occurrence times of HTEs can be mined. We find that the event synchronization network is a small-world network, the cumulative strength distribution is exponential, and the edge weight obeys a power law. Moreover, the node clustering coefficient is negatively correlated with the node degree. A congestion coefficient based on several topological parameters is proposed, and the system congestion is visualized. The congestion coefficient contains information about the synchronous occurrence of HTEs between a sector and its neighbors and information about the synchronous occurrence of HTEs among its neighbors. For the mobile communication system considered in this study, the congestion coefficient of a large number of sectors is small and the risk of system congestion is low.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. N. Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novel Network Method Major Minor Variation Clustering Enables Identification of Poliovirus Clusters with High-Resolution Linkages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0292?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0292?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiahui Tan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unleashing the potential of noncanonical amino acid biosynthesis to create cells with precision tyrosine sulfation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33111-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33111-4"/>
        <updated>2022-09-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incorporation of noncanonical amino acids into proteins holds great promise for altering structure and function of these proteins. Here the authors generate metabolically modified prokaryotic and eukaryotic cells that can biosynthesize sTyr and incorporate it into proteins in a site-specific manner.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos Researchers Can Now Predict Perilous Points of No Return]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118815</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/ai-algorithm-foresees-chaotic-tipping-points-20220915/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-15T14:17:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A custom-built machine learning algorithm can predict when a complex system is about to switch to a wildly different mode of behavior.            
The post Chaos Researchers Can Now Predict Perilous Points of No Return first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Brubaker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Functional Comparison between Endogenous and Synthetic Notch Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00247</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00247"/>
        <updated>2022-09-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00247]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bassma Khamaisi, Vincent C. Luca, Stephen C. Blacklow, and David Sprinzak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nucleation of stem cell domains in a bistable activator–inhibitor model of the shoot apical meristem]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0093841?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0093841?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-14T02:05:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Shoot apical meristems (SAMs) give rise to all above-ground tissues of a plant. Expansion of meristematic tissue is derived from the growth and division of stem cells that reside in a central zone of the SAM. This reservoir of stem cells is maintained by expression of a transcription factor WUSCHEL that is responsible for the development of stem cells in the central zone. WUSCHEL expression is self-activating and downregulated by a signaling pathway initiated by CLAVATA proteins, which are upregulated by WUSCHEL. This classic activator–inhibitor network can generate localized patterns of WUSCHEL activity by a Turing instability provided certain constraints on reaction rates and diffusion constants of WUSCHEL and CLAVATA are satisfied, and most existing mathematical models of nucleation and confinement of stem cells in the SAM rely on Turing's mechanism. However, Turing patterns have certain properties that are inconsistent with observed patterns of stem cell differentiation in the SAM. As an alternative mechanism, we propose a model for stem cell confinement based on a bistable-switch in WUSCHEL–CLAVATA interactions. We study the bistable-switch mechanism for pattern formation in a spatially continuous domain and in a discrete cellularized tissue in the presence of a non-uniform field of a rapidly diffusing hormone. By comparing domain formation by Turing and bistable-switch mechanisms in these contexts, we show that bistable switching provides a superior account of nucleation and confinement of the stem cell domain under reasonable assumptions on reaction rates and diffusion constants.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dorjsuren Battogtokh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life brought to artificial cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-02231-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-02231-8"/>
        <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A synthetic system that reproduces several attributes of living cells.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Layered feedback control overcomes performance trade-off in synthetic biomolecular networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33058-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33058-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Layered feedback is an optimization strategy in feedback control designs widely used in engineering. Here, combining simulation and experimentation, the authors apply layered control - a powerful optimization strategy in engineering - to synthetic biomolecular networks in living bacteria to show layered control overcomes performance trade-offs in biology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living material assembly of bacteriogenic protocells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05223-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05223-w"/>
        <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bacteriogenic strategy for constructing membrane-bounded, molecularly crowded, and compositionally, structurally and morphologically complex synthetic cells provides opportunities for the fabrication of new synthetic cell modules and augmented living/synthetic cell constructs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SMART Innovation Center awarded five-year NRF grant for new deep tech ventures]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/smart-innovation-center-awarded-nrf-grant-0913</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/smart-innovation-center-awarded-nrf-grant-0913"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By providing researchers with financial and strategic support from the early stages, the Innovation Center hopes to bring new and disruptive technologies to market.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BDEtools: A MATLAB Package for Boolean Delay Equation Modeling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0658?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0658?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ozgur E. Akman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RESISTOR: A New OSPREY Module to Predict Resistance Mutations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0254?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0254?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Guerin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Engineering of the Translesion DNA Synthesis Pathway Enables Controllable C‑to‑G and C‑to‑A Base Editing in <italic toggle="yes">Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00265</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00265"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00265]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu Wang, Dongdong Zhao, Letian Sun, Jie Wang, Liwen Fan, Guimin Cheng, Zhihui Zhang, Xiaomeng Ni, Jinhui Feng, Meng Wang, Ping Zheng, Changhao Bi, Xueli Zhang, and Jibin Sun</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractional Brownian motion with random Hurst exponent: Accelerating diffusion and persistence transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0101913?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0101913?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T02:58:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Fractional Brownian motion, a Gaussian non-Markovian self-similar process with stationary long-correlated increments, has been identified to give rise to the anomalous diffusion behavior in a great variety of physical systems. The correlation and diffusion properties of this random motion are fully characterized by its index of self-similarity or the Hurst exponent. However, recent single-particle tracking experiments in biological cells revealed highly complicated anomalous diffusion phenomena that cannot be attributed to a class of self-similar random processes. Inspired by these observations, we here study the process that preserves the properties of the fractional Brownian motion at a single trajectory level; however, the Hurst index randomly changes from trajectory to trajectory. We provide a general mathematical framework for analytical, numerical, and statistical analysis of the fractional Brownian motion with the random Hurst exponent. The explicit formulas for probability density function, mean-squared displacement, and autocovariance function of the increments are presented for three generic distributions of the Hurst exponent, namely, two-point, uniform, and beta distributions. The important features of the process studied here are accelerating diffusion and persistence transition, which we demonstrate analytically and numerically.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michał Balcerek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of seasonally forced noisy environment on aquatic prey–predator model with water level fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0087838?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0087838?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T02:58:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
In this paper, the impact of environmental noise on prey–predator interactions with seasonal fluctuations in water levels has been studied. Both intensity of noise and water level variations together play a significant role in the dynamics of an aquatic prey–predator system. Analytically, we have shown the existence of a positive solution and its uniqueness, the ultimate bound of the system’s solutions, and the global attractivity of the solution. Moreover, parametric conditions for which model species either persist (strongly or weakly) in the system or go into extinction are derived and their biological significance is also discussed. The sufficient condition of stochastic permanence is also analyzed. To justify the analytical results, we have performed numerical simulations of both deterministic and stochastic systems and observed some significant dynamics in the considered system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhijit Sarkar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear vs nonlinear transport during chaotic advection in fluid flows]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0087258?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0087258?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T02:58:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The goal of this study is explicit demarcation of the region of validity of a linear canonical representation for chaotic advection of Lagrangian fluid parcels in “chaotic seas” in two-dimensional (2D) and three-dimensional (3D) time-periodic fluid flows governed by Hamiltonian mechanics. The concept of lobe dynamics admits exact and unique geometric demarcation of this region and, inherently, distinction of the portions of chaotic seas with essentially linear vs nonlinear Lagrangian transport. This, furthermore, admits explicit establishment of a topological equivalence between the (embedded) Hamiltonian structure of the Lagrangian dynamics in 2D (3D) flows and their canonical form. The linear transport region in physical space encompasses four adjacent subregions that each corresponds to one of the four quadrants in canonical space and may exchange material with their environment in two essentially nonlinear ways. First, exchange between quadrants within the linear transport region and, second, exchange with the exterior of this region. Both forms of exchange can be linked to specific subsets of material elements defined by interacting lobes and combined give rise to circulation through the quadrants of the linear transport region that systematically exchanges the material with the exterior.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. F. M. Speetjens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effects of species vigilance on coexistence in evolutionary dynamics of spatial rock–paper–scissors game]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0103247?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0103247?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-13T02:58:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Recognizing surrounding situations, such as enemy attacks, which can be realized by predator–prey relationships, is one of the common behaviors of the population in ecosystems. In this paper, we explore the relationship between such species’ behavior and biodiversity in the spatial rock–paper–scissors game by employing the ecological concept “vigilance.” In order to describe the vigilance process, we adopt a multiplex structure where two distinct layers describe virtual and physical interactions. By investigating the process of evolution in species, we also found that species with different vigilance go together. In addition, by utilizing the dynamic time warping method, we found that species with the same vigilance have consistent behavior, but species with different vigilance have diverse behavior. Our findings may lead to broader interpretations of mechanisms promoting biodiversity via vigilance in species ecosystems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yikang Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differentiable Learning of Sequence-Specific Minimizer Schemes with DeepMinimizer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0275?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0275?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minh Hoang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transient chaotic behavior of fuzzy controlled polishing processes]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0101257?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0101257?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T04:21:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
This paper investigates the dynamics of a fuzzy controlled polishing machine where the effect of temporal sampling is also taken into account. Chaotic and transient chaotic behaviors are experienced for certain control parameter combinations. In the case of transient chaotic motion, closed-form algebraic expressions are determined for the expected value of the kickout number and for the corresponding standard deviation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bence Szaksz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constructing differential equations using only a scalar time-series about continuous time chaotic dynamics]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0100166?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0100166?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T04:21:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We propose a simple method of constructing a system of differential equations of chaotic behavior based on the regression only from scalar observable time-series data. The estimated system enables us to reconstruct invariant sets and statistical properties as well as to infer short time-series. Our successful modeling relies on the introduction of a set of Gaussian radial basis functions to capture local structures. The proposed method is used to construct a system of ordinary differential equations whose orbit reconstructs a time-series of a variable of the well-known Lorenz system as a simple but typical example. A system for a macroscopic fluid variable is also constructed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natsuki Tsutsumi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Intestinal Engineered Probiotics as Living Therapeutics: Chassis Selection, Colonization Enhancement, Gene Circuit Design, and Biocontainment]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00314</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00314"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00314]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yan Huang, Xiaojun Lin, Siyang Yu, Ruiyue Chen, and Weizhao Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Steady-State Operation of a Cell-Free Genetic Band-Detection Circuit]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00195</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00195"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00195]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna C. Jäkel, Lukas Aufinger, and Friedrich C. Simmel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust data storage in DNA by de Bruijn graph-based de novo strand assembly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33046-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33046-w"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DNA data storage is a rapidly developing technology with great potential due to its high density, long-term durability, and low maintenance cost. Here the authors present a strand assembly algorithm (DBGPS) using de Bruijn graph and greedy path search.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinetic compartmentalization by unnatural reaction for itaconate production]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33033-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33033-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unlike eukaryotic system, bacterial hosts lack membranous system, which is one of the limitations for efficient metabolic engineering. Here, the authors report a kinetic compartmentalization strategy to increase substrate availability from competitive reactions for the efficient production of itaconate in E. coli.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Reprogramming T7RNA Polymerase in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Escherichia coli</named-content> Nissle 1917 under Specific <italic toggle="yes">Lac</italic> Operon for Efficient <italic toggle="yes">p</italic>‑Coumaric Acid Production]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00363</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00363"/>
        <updated>2022-09-10T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00363]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sefli Sri Wahyu Effendi and I-Son Ng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Pseudotyping Bacteriophage P2 Tail Fibers to Extend the Host Range for Biomedical Applications]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00629</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00629"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.1c00629]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabitha G. Cunliffe, Alan L. Parker, and Alfonso Jaramillo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-parametric tests for serial dependence in time series based on asymptotic implementations of ordinal-pattern statistics]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0094943?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0094943?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T08:05:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Ordinal patterns can be used to construct non-parametric hypothesis tests that aim to discover (possibly non-linear) serial dependence in a real-valued time series. We derive the asymptotic distribution of the vector of sample frequencies of ordinal patterns and that of various corresponding tests statistics such that the targeted tests for serial dependence are easily implemented based on asymptotic approximations. Simulations are used to check the finite-sample performance of these tests as well as their power properties with respect to various alternative scenarios. The application and interpretation of the tests in practice are illustrated by an environmental data example.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian H. Weiß</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the origin of chaotic attractors with two zero Lyapunov exponents in a system of five biharmonically coupled phase oscillators]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098163?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098163?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We study chaotic dynamics in a system of four differential equations describing the interaction of five identical phase oscillators coupled via biharmonic function. We show that this system exhibits strange spiral attractors (Shilnikov attractors) with two zero (indistinguishable from zero in numerics) Lyapunov exponents in a wide region of the parameter space. We explain this phenomenon by means of bifurcation analysis of a three-dimensional Poincaré map for the system under consideration. We show that chaotic dynamics develop here near a codimension three bifurcation, when a periodic orbit (fixed point of the Poincaré map) has the triplet of multipliers [math]. As it is known, the flow normal form for such bifurcation is the well-known three-dimensional Arneodó–Coullet–Spiegel–Tresser (ACST) system, which exhibits spiral attractors. According to this, we conclude that the additional zero Lyapunov exponent for orbits in the observed attractors appears due to the fact that the corresponding three-dimensional Poincaré map is very close to the time-shift map of the ACST-system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny A. Grines</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting bifurcations in dynamical systems with CROCKER plots]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0102421?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0102421?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Existing tools for bifurcation detection from signals of dynamical systems typically are either limited to a special class of systems or they require carefully chosen input parameters and a significant expertise to interpret the results. Therefore, we describe an alternative method based on persistent homology—a tool from topological data analysis—that utilizes Betti numbers and CROCKER plots. Betti numbers are topological invariants of topological spaces, while the CROCKER plot is a coarsened but easy to visualize data representation of a one-parameter varying family of persistence barcodes. The specific bifurcations we investigate are transitions from periodic to chaotic behavior or vice versa in a one-parameter collection of differential equations. We validate our methods using numerical experiments on ten dynamical systems and contrast the results with existing tools that use the maximum Lyapunov exponent. We further prove the relationship between the Wasserstein distance to the empty diagram and the norm of the Betti vector, which shows that an even more simplified version of the information has the potential to provide insight into the bifurcation parameter. The results show that our approach reveals more information about the shape of the periodic attractor than standard tools, and it has more favorable computational time in comparison with the Rösenstein algorithm for computing the maximum Lyapunov exponent.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>İsmail Güzel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-subject emotion recognition using visibility graph and genetic algorithm-based convolution neural network]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098454?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098454?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
An efficient emotion recognition model is an important research branch in electroencephalogram (EEG)-based brain–computer interfaces. However, the input of the emotion recognition model is often a whole set of EEG channels obtained by electrodes placed on subjects. The unnecessary information produced by redundant channels affects the recognition rate and depletes computing resources, thereby hindering the practical applications of emotion recognition. In this work, we aim to optimize the input of EEG channels using a visibility graph (VG) and genetic algorithm-based convolutional neural network (GA-CNN). First, we design an experiment to evoke three types of emotion states using movies and collect the multi-channel EEG signals of each subject under different emotion states. Then, we construct VGs for each EEG channel and derive nonlinear features representing each EEG channel. We employ the genetic algorithm (GA) to find the optimal subset of EEG channels for emotion recognition and use the recognition results of the CNN as fitness values. The experimental results show that the recognition performance of the proposed method using a subset of EEG channels is superior to that of the CNN using all channels for each subject. Last, based on the subset of EEG channels searched by the GA-CNN, we perform cross-subject emotion recognition tasks employing leave-one-subject-out cross-validation. These results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method in recognizing emotion states using fewer EEG channels and further enrich the methods of EEG classification using nonlinear features.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qing Cai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry breaking of solitons in the PT-symmetric nonlinear Schrödinger equation with the cubic–quintic competing saturable nonlinearity]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0091738?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0091738?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The symmetry breaking of solitons in the nonlinear Schrödinger equation with cubic–quintic competing nonlinearity and parity-time symmetric potential is studied. At first, a new asymmetric branch separates from the fundamental symmetric soliton at the first power critical point, and then, the asymmetric branch passes through the branch of the fundamental symmetric soliton and finally merges into the branch of the fundamental symmetric soliton at the second power critical point, while the power of the soliton increases. This leads to the symmetry breaking and double-loop bifurcation of fundamental symmetric solitons. From the power-propagation constant curves of solitons, symmetric fundamental and tripole solitons, asymmetric solitons can also exist. The stability of symmetric fundamental solitons, asymmetric solitons, and symmetric tripole solitons is discussed by the linear stability analysis and direct simulation. Results indicate that symmetric fundamental solitons and symmetric tripole solitons tend to be stable with the increase in the soliton power. Asymmetric solitons are unstable in both high and low power regions. Moreover, with the increase in saturable nonlinearity, the stability region of fundamental symmetric solitons and symmetric tripole solitons becomes wider.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wen-Bo Bo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dipole and quadrupole nonparaxial solitary waves]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096099?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096099?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The cubic nonlinear Helmholtz equation with third and fourth order dispersion and non-Kerr nonlinearity, such as the self steepening and the self frequency shift, is considered. This model describes nonparaxial ultrashort pulse propagation in an optical medium in the presence of spatial dispersion originating from the failure of slowly varying envelope approximation. We show that this system admits periodic (elliptic) solitary waves with a dipole structure within a period and also a transition from a dipole to quadrupole structure within a period depending on the value of the modulus parameter of a Jacobi elliptic function. The parametric conditions to be satisfied for the existence of these solutions are given. The effect of the nonparaxial parameter on physical quantities, such as amplitude, pulse width, and speed of the solitary waves, is examined. It is found that by adjusting the nonparaxial parameter, the speed of solitary waves can be decelerated. The stability and robustness of the solitary waves are discussed numerically.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Naresh Saha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When costly migration helps to improve cooperation]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0100772?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0100772?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Motion is a typical reaction among animals and humans trying to reach better conditions in a changing world. This aspect has been studied intensively in social dilemmas where competing players’ individual and collective interests are in conflict. Starting from the traditional public goods game model, where players are locally fixed and unconditional cooperators or defectors are present, we introduce two additional strategies through which agents can change their positions of dependence on the local cooperation level. More importantly, these so-called sophisticated players should bear an extra cost to maintain their permanent capacity to evaluate their neighborhood and react accordingly. Hence, four strategies compete, and the most successful one can be imitated by its neighbors. Crucially, the introduction of costly movement has a highly biased consequence on the competing main strategies. In the majority of parameter space, it is harmful to defectors and provides a significantly higher cooperation level when the population is rare. At an intermediate population density, which would be otherwise optimal for a system of immobile players, the presence of mobile actors could be detrimental if the interaction pattern changes slightly, thereby blocking the optimal percolation of information flow. In this parameter space, sophisticated cooperators can also show the co-called Moor effect by first avoiding the harmful vicinity of defectors; they subsequently transform into an immobile cooperator state. Hence, paradoxically, the additional cost of movement could be advantageous to reach a higher general income, especially for a rare population when subgroups would be isolated otherwise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hsuan-Wei Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry breaking yields chimeras in two small populations of Kuramoto-type oscillators]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0088465?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0088465?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Despite their simplicity, networks of coupled phase oscillators can give rise to intriguing collective dynamical phenomena. However, the symmetries of globally and identically coupled identical units do not allow solutions where distinct oscillators are frequency-unlocked—a necessary condition for the emergence of chimeras. Thus, forced symmetry breaking is necessary to observe chimera-type solutions. Here, we consider the bifurcations that arise when full permutational symmetry is broken for the network to consist of coupled populations. We consider the smallest possible network composed of four phase oscillators and elucidate the phase space structure, (partial) integrability for some parameter values, and how the bifurcations away from full symmetry lead to frequency-unlocked weak chimera solutions. Since such solutions wind around a torus they must arise in a global bifurcation scenario. Moreover, periodic weak chimeras undergo a period-doubling cascade leading to chaos. The resulting chaotic dynamics with distinct frequencies do not rely on amplitude variation and arise in the smallest networks that support chaos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oleksandr Burylko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Publisher Correction: Standardized excitable elements for scalable engineering of far-from-equilibrium chemical networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01058-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01058-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature Chemistry - Publisher Correction: Standardized excitable elements for scalable engineering of far-from-equilibrium chemical networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analyzing the potential of AlphaFold in drug discovery]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/alphafold-potential-protein-drug-0906</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/alphafold-potential-protein-drug-0906"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study finds computer models that predict molecular interactions need improvement before they can help identify drug mechanisms of action.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anne Trafton | MIT News Office</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Development of Base Editors for Simultaneously Editing Multiple Loci in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Lactococcus lactis</named-content>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00561</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00561"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.1c00561]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kairen Tian, Xia Hong, Manman Guo, Yanni Li, Hao Wu, Qinggele Caiyin, and Jianjun Qiao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracking the order of transcriptional events in living cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01610-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01610-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers describe Retro-Cascorder, a tool that employs prokaryotic retrons and CRISPR integrases to write transcriptional events into the genome of Escherichia coli.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of an Escherichia coli strain growing on methanol via the ribulose monophosphate cycle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32744-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32744-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using one carbon compounds as feedstock is a promising approach in abating climate change. Here, the authors report the conversion of E. coli into a synthetic methylotroph that assimilates methanol via the ribulose monophosphate cycle and a set of distinctive mutations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MVsim is a toolset for quantifying and designing multivalent interactions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32496-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32496-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arising through multiple binding elements, multivalency can specify the avidity, duration, cooperativity, and selectivity of biomolecular interactions, but quantitative prediction and design of these properties has remained challenging. Here the authors enable facile analysis and engineering of multivalent binding by developing MVsim, a simulator that incorporates biochemical and biophysical parameters of interacting molecules and is accessible through a graphical user interface.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signal processing and generation of bioactive nitric oxide in a model prototissue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32941-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32941-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A challenge for synthetic biology is the design and construction of prototissue. Here, the authors spatially segregate layers of enzyme-decorated coacervate protocells as a model prototissue capable of chemical signal processing and modulating outputs of nitric oxide to inhibit blood clot formation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine-Learning Prospects for Detecting Selection Signatures Using Population Genomics Data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0447?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0447?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 943-960, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harshit Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Integer Linear Programming Approach for Scaffolding Based on Exemplar Breakpoint Distance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0399?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0399?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 961-973, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-kung Shieh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Design of Synthetic DNA Sequences Without Unwanted Binding Sites]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0417?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0417?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 974-986, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zehavit Leibovich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RDscan: A New Method for Improving Germline and Somatic Variant Calling Based on Read Depth Distribution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0269?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0269?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 987-1000, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sunho Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[kmer2vec: A Novel Method for Comparing DNA Sequences by word2vec Embedding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0536?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0536?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1001-1021, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruohan Ren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing Rewards Undermines Coordinated Hunting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0549?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0549?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1022-1030, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minglu Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-Organ Transcriptomic Comparison Reveals Universal Factors During Maturation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0349?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0349?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1031-1044, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandeep Kambhampati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harnessing Fuzzy Rule Based System for Screening Major Histocompatibility Complex Class I Peptide Epitopes from the Whole Proteome: An Implementation on the Proteome of Leishmania donovani]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0464?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0464?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1045-1058, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saravanan Vijayakumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A modular XNAzyme cleaves long, structured RNAs under physiological conditions and enables allele-specific gene silencing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01021-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01021-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oligonucleotide catalysts such as ribozymes and DNAzymes can cleave RNA efficiently and specifically but are typically dependent on high concentrations of divalent cations, limiting their biological applications. A modular XNAzyme catalyst composed of 2′-deoxy-2′-fluoro-β-d-arabino nucleic acid (FANA) has now been developed that can cleave long (>5 kb), highly structured mRNAs under physiological conditions and enables allele-specific catalytic RNA knockdown inside cells.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expanding the terpene biosynthetic code with non-canonical 16 carbon atom building blocks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32921-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32921-w"/>
        <updated>2022-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Establishing methods to access the chemical space that lies beyond canonical terpenoid biosynthesis will increase the applications of isoprenoids. Here, the authors reconstruct the modular structure of terpene biosynthesis on 16-carbon backbones by engineered yeast and synthesize 28 different unique terpenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action potential and chaos near the edge of chaos in memristive circuits]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097075?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097075?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T09:53:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Memristor-based neuromorphic systems have a neuro-bionic function, which is critical for possibly overcoming Moore's law limitation and the von Neumann bottleneck problem. To explore neural behaviors and complexity mechanisms in memristive circuits, this paper proposes an N-type locally active memristor, based on which a third-order memristive circuit is constructed. Theoretical analysis shows that the memristive circuit can exhibit not only various action potentials but also self-sustained oscillation and chaos. Based on Chua's theory of local activity, this paper finds that the neural behaviors and chaos emerge near the edge of chaos through subcritical Hopf bifurcation, in which the small unstable limit cycle is depicted by the dividing line between the attraction basin of the large stable limit cycle and the attraction basin of the stable equilibrium point. Furthermore, an analog circuit is designed to imitate the action potentials and chaos, and the simulation results are in agreement with the theoretical analysis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiajie Ying</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effects of infection fatality ratio and social contact matrices on vaccine prioritization strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096532?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096532?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T09:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Effective strategies of vaccine prioritization are essential to mitigate the impacts of severe infectious diseases. We investigate the role of infection fatality ratio (IFR) and social contact matrices on vaccination prioritization using a compartmental epidemic model fueled by real-world data of different diseases and countries. Our study confirms that massive and early vaccination is extremely effective to reduce the disease fatality if the contagion is mitigated, but the effectiveness is increasingly reduced as vaccination beginning delays in an uncontrolled epidemiological scenario. The optimal and least effective prioritization strategies depend non-linearly on epidemiological variables. Regions of the epidemiological parameter space, in which prioritizing the most vulnerable population is more effective than the most contagious individuals, depend strongly on the IFR age profile being, for example, substantially broader for COVID-19 in comparison with seasonal influenza. Demographics and social contact matrices deform the phase diagrams but do not alter their qualitative shapes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arthur Schulenburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A visualization reporter system for characterizing antibiotic biosynthetic gene clusters expression with high-sensitivity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03832-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03832-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quorum sensing based visualization reporter system is presented for the characterization of promoters in Gram-positive bacteria, utilizing violacein production, especially for use in the identification of secondary metabolites.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automated model-predictive design of synthetic promoters to control transcriptional profiles in bacteria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32829-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32829-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transcription rates are regulated by the interactions between RNA polymerase, sigma factor, and promoter DNA sequences in bacteria. Here the authors combine massively parallel experiments & machine learning to develop a predictive biophysical model of transcription, validated across 22132 bacterial promoters, and apply it to the design and debugging of genetic circuits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatiotemporal control of signal-driven enzymatic reaction in artificial cell-like polymersomes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32889-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32889-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have been trying to mimick the cellular spatiotemporal control in normal cells with different approaches. Here, the authors present semi-permeable polymersomes comprising of amphiphilic triblock copolymers to achieve external signal-driven complex coacervation and biophysical reconstitution of cytoskeleton.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quartet Based Gene Tree Imputation Using Deep Learning Improves Phylogenomic Analyses Despite Missing Data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0212?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0212?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sazan Mahbub</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inconsistency of Triplet-Based and Quartet-Based Species Tree Estimation under Intralocus Recombination]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0265?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0265?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Hill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Horizontal gene transfer enables programmable gene stability in synthetic microbiota]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41589-022-01114-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41589-022-01114-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic redundancy by horizontal gene transfer stabilizes gene abundances amidst compositional fluctuations in microbial communities, which suggests a means to program gene stability of complex microbiota.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homodimerized cytoplasmic domain of PD-L1 regulates its complex glycosylation in living cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03845-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03845-4"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Membrane-anchored PD-L1 homodimerizes in cells. N-glycosylation of PD-L1 regulates its homodimerization. The formation of PD-L1 homodimers further regulates their glycan processing, localization to the plasma membrane, and binding to PD-1.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlling gene expression with deep generative design of regulatory DNA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32818-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32818-8"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design of de novo synthetic regulatory DNA is a promising avenue to control gene expression in biotechnology and medicine. Here the authors present EspressionGAN, a generative adversarial network that uses genomic and transcriptomic data to generate regulatory sequences.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reconstructing Kinetic Models for Dynamical Studies of Metabolism using Generative Adversarial Networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00519-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00519-y"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kinetic models of metabolism capture time-dependent behaviour of cellular states and provide valuable insights into cellular physiology, but, due to the lack of experimental data, traditional kinetic modelling can be unreliable and computationally inefficient. A generative framework based on deep learning called REKINDLE can efficiently parameterize large-scale kinetic models, enabling new opportunities to study cellular metabolic behaviour.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nonlinear dynamics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopy technique reveals hidden nanostructures in cells and tissues]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/expansion-revealing-microscopy-cells-0829</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/expansion-revealing-microscopy-cells-0829"/>
        <updated>2022-08-29T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Separating densely packed molecules before imaging allows them to become visible for the first time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anne Trafton | MIT News Office</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The automated Galaxy-SynBioCAD pipeline for synthetic biology design and engineering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32661-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32661-x"/>
        <updated>2022-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated design and build processes can rapidly accelerate work in synthetic biology and metabolic engineering. Here the authors present Galaxy-SynBioCAD, a toolshed for synthetic biology, metabolic engineering, and industrial biotechnology that they use to build and execute Galaxy scientific workflows from pathway design to strain engineering through the automated generation of scripts driving robotic workstations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>