<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-09-12T00:47:34.992Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.992Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution of cooperation driven by diversity on a double-layer square lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eocdbdoadsl.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eocdbdoadsl.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.959Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diversity from different sources is introduced into the prisoner’s dilemma.Diversity favors the evolution of cooperation, independent of its source.Internal diversity promotes cooperation more than external heterogeneity.        Understanding the potential promotion mechanism for the formation and maintenance of cooperation is a pivotal issue in the development of human society and the natural world. Evolutionary games provide a forceful theoretical tool to probe into the essence of cooperative behaviors. It is considered that diversity (heterogeneity) is a common attribute of individuals and their interaction environment. We explore the propagation of cooperation under the influence of diversity and identify the similarities and discrepancies in the impact of internal and external sources of heterogeneity. The results show that heterogeneity, regardless of its origin, can promote the diffusion of cooperative behaviors. However, our researches further demonstrate that diversity of individual internal attributes is more conducive to the formation of cooperative behaviors than environmental heterogeneity. Moreover, we discuss the impact of asymmetry on the results and verify the robustness of the conclusions in different mixed game models. Our explorations shed some light on the promotion mechanism of cooperation from the perspective of sources of heterogeneity and highlight the role of diversity in the spread of altruistic behaviors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu’e Wu; Zhipeng Zhang; Guoli Yang; Haixin Liu; Qingfeng Zhang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Break-up of invariant curves in the Fermi-Ulam model]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_boicitfm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_boicitfm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.950Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The transport of particles in the phase space is investigated in the Fermi-Ulam model. The system consists of a particle confined to move within two rigid walls with which it collides. One is fixed and the other is periodically moving in time. In this work we investigate, for this model, the location of invariant curves that separate chaotic areas in the phase space. Applying the Slater's theorem we verify that the mapping presents a family of invariant spanning curves with a rotation number whose expansion into continued fractions has an infinite tail of the unity, acting as local transport barriers. We study the destruction of such curves and find the critical parameters for that. The determination of the rotation number in the vicinity of one of the considered spanning curves allowed us to understand the dynamics in the vicinity of the considered curve, both before and after criticality. The rotation number profile showed us the fractal character of the region close to the curve, since this profile has a structure similar to a “Devil's Staircase”.            We investigate the location of invariant curves for the Fermi-Ulam model that separate chaotic areas in phase space.We found, for this model, a family of quite robust invariant spanning curves.Through Slater's theorem, we find the position of a family of locally robust invariant spanning curves.Using Slater's theorem allowed us to study the criticality for each of these curves.We determined the critical parameter related to each curve and thus we were able to predict their breakage.We show a similar structure to “Devil's Staircase” for the rotation number profile in the vicinity of the curves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joelson D.V. Hermes; Marcelo A. dos Reis; Iberê L. Caldas; Edson D. Leonel;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some novel mathematical analysis on the fractal–fractional model of the AH1N1/09 virus and its generalized Caputo-type version]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_snmaotvaigcv.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_snmaotvaigcv.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.949Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, we formulate a new model of a particular type of influenza virus called AH1N1/09 in the framework of the four classes consisting of susceptible, exposed, infectious and recovered people. For the first time, we here investigate this model with the help of the advanced operators entitled the fractal–fractional operators with two fractal and fractional orders via the power law type kernels. The existence of solution for the mentioned fractal–fractional model of AH1N1/09 is studied by some special mappings such as -contractions and -admissibles. The Leray–Schauder theorem is also applied for this aim. After investigating the stability criteria in four versions, to approximate the desired numerical solutions, we implement Adams–Bashforth (AB) scheme and simulate the graphs for different data on the fractal and fractional orders. Lastly, we convert our fractal–fractional AH1N1/09 model into a fractional model via the generalized Liouville–Caputo-type (GLC-type) operators and then, we simulate new graphs caused by the new numerical scheme called Kumar–Erturk method.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sina Etemad; Ibrahim Avci; Pushpendra Kumar; Dumitru Baleanu; Shahram Rezapour;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bursting dynamics and the zero-Hopf bifurcation of simple jerk system]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bdatzbosjs.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bdatzbosjs.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.949Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We characterize the zero-Hopf bifurcation of a simple jerk system.The Jerk system produces up to three more periodic orbits that tend to zero.The generation mechanism of different bursting oscillations is revealed in detail.The experience of the analog circuit verifies the theoretical analysis.        We characterize the zero-Hopf bifurcation at a singular point of a parameter jerk system. By employing the second order averaging theory, we demonstrate that up to three periodic orbits generated as disturbance parameters tend to zero. Again, both the bifurcation mechanism and bursting dynamics of the 3D jerk system with external periodic excitation are systematically explored. While an order difference exists between the frequency of external excitation and the average frequency of the system, the system exhibits bursting oscillations. The mechanisms of different bursting oscillations are investigated by means of the equilibrium point curve and the transformed phase portraits. As the amplitudes of the excitation change, the system displays “delayed symmetric pitchfork/point, delayed symmetric pitchfork/supHopf, and delayed pitchfork/supHopf/homoclinic connection bursting”. Finally, an analog circuit is designed to verify the complex bursting phenomena of the system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xi Sun; Shaohui Yan; Yuyan Zhang; Ertong Wang; Qiyu Wang; Binxian Gu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The predictive power of power-laws: An empirical time-arrow based investigation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_tppopaetbi.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_tppopaetbi.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.944Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The efficient market hypothesis forbids any predictability towards future, but there is no such restriction in the case of reversed-looking approaches. We analyze if this asymmetry in non-predictability is reflected in the statistical features of financial time series. Our study is based on the analysis of the length-distribution of periods with high variability, and introduces time-asymmetric modifications of the method which are capable of revealing differences of the time series in forward and reversed time. We show that the future and reversed-looking time-series possess very similar properties, with some features being distinguishable with our method. Our findings give also evidence of the differences in the dynamics of markets before and after crisis, this implying the possibility to predict a forthcoming crisis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Andria; Giacomo di Tollo; Jaan Kalda;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptive movement strategy in rock-paper-scissors models]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_amsirm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_amsirm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.944Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stochastic simulations of the spatial rock-paper-scissors model with organisms of one out of the species performing adaptive movement strategies are performed.Individuals can adjust their mobility to run away from hostile environments and stay in comfort zones.The impact of the adaptive movement strategy on pattern formation is described and the characteristic length of the typical single-species spatial domain is quantified.The mean species densities and selection risks are calculated based on the organisms' perception range and responsiveness strength.        Organisms may respond to local stimuli that benefit or threaten their fitness. The adaptive movement behaviour may allow individuals to adjust their speed to maximise the chances of being in comfort zones, where death risk is minimal. We investigate spatial cyclic models where the rock-paper-scissors game rules describe the nonhierarchical dominance. We assume that organisms of one out of the species can control the mobility rate in response to the information obtained from scanning the environment. Running a series of stochastic simulations, we quantify the effects of the movement strategy on the spatial patterns and population dynamics. Our findings show that the ability to change mobility to adapt to environmental clues is not reflected in an advantage in cyclic spatial games. The adaptive movement provokes a delay in the spatial domains occupied by the species in the spiral waves, making the group more vulnerable to the advance of the dominant species and less efficient in taking territory from the dominated species. Our outcomes also show that the effects of adaptive movement behaviour accentuate whether most individuals have a long-range neighbourhood perception. Our results may be helpful for biologists and data scientists to comprehend the dynamics of ecosystems where adaptive processes are fundamental.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Tenorio; E. Rangel; J. Menezes;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-order compact finite difference schemes for the time-fractional Black-Scholes model governing European options]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_hcfdsftbmgeo.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_hcfdsftbmgeo.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.944Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Based on the price fluctuations of the underlying fractal transmission system, the -order time-fractional Black-Scholes model is obtained. In this paper, we introduce two compact finite difference schemes for the solution of the time-fractional Black-Scholes equation governing European option pricing. In proposed schemes, in order to gain sixth-order and eighth-order accuracy in space, we first use exponential transformation to eliminate the convection term of the Black-Scholes equation. Then, the time-fractional derivative discretizes by a th order numerical formula (called the L1–2 formula here) which is constructed by a linear interpolating polynomial on the first subinterval and the quadratic interpolating polynomials on the other subintervals. We investigate stability and convergence of proposed schemes by Fourier method. Finally, some numerical examples perform to demonstrate the theoretical order of accuracy and illustrate the effectiveness of proposed methods. We also discuss the influence of different parameters on the option price in the time-fractional Black-Scholes model.            Two high-order compact finite difference schemes are considered to solve the numerical solution of the fractional Black-Scholes equation governing European option pricing.We proved that our new schemes: the SCFD and the ECFD schemes are convergent and their order of convergence are  and , respectively.The stability and convergence of these schemes are investigated by the Fourier method.Some numerical examples are performed to demonstrate the theoretical order of accuracy and illustrate the effectiveness of our schemes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Abdi; H. Aminikhah; A.H. Refahi Sheikhani;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boundary state feedback control for semilinear fractional-order reaction diffusion systems]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bsfcfsfrds.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bsfcfsfrds.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.943Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper investigates the stabilization results for a semilinear time fractional-order reaction diffusion partial differential equations using backstepping method. The parabolic system is addressed with time fractional-order of (0, 1) in the Caputo sense. More general type of actuation setup which can be expressed as Dirichlet, Neumann and Robin type boundary actuation's is considered. The main aim is to achieve the stabilization of the considered system using an invertible transformation through the stability of target system which is verified by Mittag-Leffler stability based on (, , ) dissipativity theory and linear matrix inequality (LMI) technique. The explicit solutions of kernel functions are found by method of successive approximation and to be design the boundary control law for the closed loop system. Finally, the proposed results are validated through numerical examples.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Mathiyalagan; T. Renugadevi; A. Shree Nidhi; Yong-Ki Ma; Jinde Cao;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic behaviors of multiple-solitons in a magnetized dusty plasma]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dbomiamdp.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dbomiamdp.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.943Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this work, we theoretically investigate the dynamic behaviors of multiple-solitons, such as single-, two-, three solitons etc. that propagate in a magnetized dusty plasma while the plasma system comprises moving inertial ions, Maxwellian distributed electrons and positrons, and stationary negatively charged dust particles. We examine the multiple-soliton solutions of the KdV equation in order to discuss the time evolution of multiple-solitons and the parametric effects on the soliton profiles. The reductive perturbation approach is exploited to extract the KdV equation. The simplified Hirota method (SHM) and the Cole-Hopf transformation (CHT) are applied to construct the multiple-soliton solutions of the equation. We observe that the magnetic field has a decreasing effect on the multiple-solitons' amplitudes and widths, whereas the dust particle concentration and obliquity angle have an increasing effect.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Md. Abdus Salam; M. Zulfikar Ali; Mustafa Inc; M. Ali Akbar;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bright solitons in fractional coupler with spatially periodical modulated nonlinearity]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bsifcwspmn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bsifcwspmn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.943Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study bright solitons in the fractional coupler with a spatially periodical modulated nonlinearity. The results show that the linear coupling constant , Lévy index , chemical potential  and nonlinear intensity  have a significant influence on the amplitude, width and stability of fundamental solitons, dipole solitons and tripole solitons. We investigate the stability of bright solitons by linear stability analysis and the real-time evolution method. It is found that the bright solitons tend to be stable with the increase of linear coupling constant, Lévy index, chemical potential, and nonlinear intensity in the corresponding parameter interval. The results also show that the distance between adjacent peaks is four times of the nonlinear lattice period for dipole solitons and six times for tripole solitons. We also find that the number of soliton peaks is smaller, and the stable region is wider in the fractional coupler with the spatially periodical modulated nonlinear lattice.            We study solitons in fractional coupler with periodical modulated nonlinearity.The stable regions are found by linear stability analysis and real-time evolution.Bright solitons tend to be stable with the increase of nonlinear intensity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S.R. Li; Y.Y. Bao; Y.H. Liu; T.F. Xu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Untangling role of cooperative hunting among predators and herd behavior in prey with a dynamical systems approach]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_urochapwadsa.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_urochapwadsa.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.941Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the real world, group formation is ubiquitous. This group behavior is according to the species' needs; some species use it for hunting and some for protection from predators. In this paper, we proposed a prey-predator model with cooperative hunting among predators and herd behavior in prey, and we studied the temporal and spatiotemporal analysis. We first examine the system's positivity, boundedness, and then analyze the local stability criterion of equilibrium points. We perform Hopf–bifurcation analysis at feasible equilibrium points by considering  and  as the bifurcation parameters. With the incorporation of diffusion into the system, we derive the diffusion-driven instability of the prey-predator system. Then we performed a weakly nonlinear analysis and derived amplitude equations by considering self-diffusion as Turing bifurcation parameters. The stability analysis of these amplitude equations leads to the identification of various Turing patterns, such as spots, stripes, and mixed. Employing numerical simulations, we present the main types of patterns observed for parameters in the Turing domain. Our findings reveal that cooperative hunting, interspecific competition, and self-diffusion have important implications in the prey-predator system.            Proposed a prey-predator system with hunting cooperation among predators and herd behavior in prey.Studied the effect of both parameters' i.e., hunting cooperation and interspecific competition via Hopf-bifurcation.Derived diffusion-driven instability near the Turing bifurcation threshold.Weakly nonlinear analysis was used to derive amplitude equations.Numerical simulations were presented to illustrate the theoretical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shivam; Kuldeep Singh; Mukesh Kumar; Ramu Dubey; Teekam Singh;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Numerical investigation of fractional-order cholera epidemic model with transmission dynamics via fractal–fractional operator technique]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_niofcetdvfot.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_niofcetdvfot.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.941Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The goal of this research is to determine if it is conceptually sufficient to eliminate infection in a community by utilizing mathematical modelling and simulation techniques when appropriate protective controls are adopted. In this research, we investigate the straightforward interaction transmission method to create a deterministic mathematical formulation of cholera infectious dynamics via the fractal–fractional (F–F) derivative operator. Furthermore, the qualitative characteristics of the framework are investigated, including the invariant region, the existence of a positive invariant solution, the equilibria conditions and their stabilities. In addition, the fundamental reproductive number  is calculated, indicating that the strategy is more plausible. The Atangana–Baleanu, Caputo–Fabrizio, and Caputo F–F differential operators are recently described F–F differential operators that are used to describe the computational formula of the cholera epidemic model. We examined the numerical dynamics of the cholera epidemic, considering three assumptions: (i) altering fractal order while fixing fractional order; (ii) changing fractional order while fixing fractal order; and (iii) fluctuating fractal and fractional orders simultaneously. For the numerical modelling of the aforesaid model, our analysed graphical representations and numerical simulations via MATLAB indicate that the newly proposed Atangana–Baleanu, Caputo–Fabrizio, and Caputo F–F differential operators yield notable outcomes when compared to the classical framework. According to the simulated data, reduced contact rate, successful recovery rate, and appropriate hygiene are the most essential aspects for eliminating cholera disease from the community.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saima Rashid; Fahd Jarad; Abdulaziz Khalid Alsharidi;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing and morphing Boolean gates with adaptive synchronization: The case of spiking neurons]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iambgwstcosn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iambgwstcosn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.940Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptative coupling for implementing Boolean gatesSynchronization/desynchronization of signals for logic operationsAdaptative coupling and synchronization for implementing the universal gate        Boolean logic is the paradigm through which modern computation is performed in silica. When nonlinear dynamical systems are interacting in a directed graph, we show that computation abilities emerge spontaneously from adaptive synchronization, which actually can emulate Boolean logic. Precisely, we demonstrate that a single dynamical unit, a spiking neuron modeled by the Hodgkin-Huxley model, can be used as the basic computational unit for realizing all the 16 Boolean logical gates with two inputs and one output, when it is coupled adaptively in a way that depends on the synchronization level between the two input signals. This is realized by means of a set of parameters, whose tuning offers even the possibility of constructing a  gate, i.e., a logical gate able to switch efficiently from one to another of such 16 Boolean gates. Extensive simulations demonstrate the efficiency and the accuracy of the proposed computational paradigm.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Yang; E. Primo; D. Aleja; R. Criado; S. Boccaletti; K. Alfaro-Bittner;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local bifurcation of a circus truss antenna considering the effect of space thermal excitation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_lboactteoste.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_lboactteoste.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.939Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The local stability and bifurcation of a circus truss antenna under the influence of the thermal excitation are considered using both analytical and numerical methods. On the basis of the obtained four-dimensional averaged equation with 1:2 internal resonance, a kind of eigenvalues of the bifurcation response equation is investigated. By take advantage of the central manifold theory, nonlinear transformation and Routh-Hurwitz criterion, the stable conditions of the equilibrium points are obtained. Finally, the numerical simulations obtained by Runge-Kutta method illustrated the theoretical analysis results.            The stability and bifurcation behaviors of the two-dimension nonlinear supersonic panel are proposed.Norm form is obtained through a systematic and efficient computation method.Hopf bifurcation may occur in the two-dimension nonlinear supersonic panel.Stability conditions of the steady state solutions are determined.Numerical solutions are obtained, which agree with the analytical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaohua Zhang; Liangqiang Zhou; Juan Wang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lie symmetry reductions and generalized exact solutions of Date–Jimbo–Kashiwara–Miwa equation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_lsragesode.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_lsragesode.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.938Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lie symmetry reductions of Date–Jimbo–Kashiwara–Miwa equation are carried out.It is long water wave equation, which describes the propagation of nonlinear and weakly dispersive waves in inhomogeneous media.Some generalized exact solutions are derived.The derived solutions are analyzed graphically.The solutions show doubly soliton, multisoliton, line soliton, bell shape, parabolic nature.        The propagation of nonlinear waves with nonuniform velocities is described by nonlinear evolution equations and their solutions involving arbitrary functions. When a nonlinear evolution equation is integrated, it reveals the several existing features of natural phenomena with continuous and fluctuating background. The Date–Jimbo–Kashiwara–Miwa equation is long water wave equation, which describes th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dig Vijay Tanwar;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the “Delta Variant” affect the nonlinear dynamic characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 transmission?]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dtvatndcost.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dtvatndcost.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.938Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, we analyzed the difference of nonlinear dynamic characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 transmission caused by ‘Delta Variant’. We selected the daily new diagnostic data of SARS-CoV-2 from 15 countries. Four different kinds of complexity metrics such as Kolmogorov complexity, Higuchi's Hurst exponent, Shannon entropy, and multifractal degrees were selected to explore the features of information content, persistence, randomness, multifractal complexity. Afterwards, Student's t-tests were performed to assess the presence of differences of these nonlinear dynamic characteristics for periods before and after “Delta Variant” appearance. The results of two-tailed Student's t-test showed that for all the nonlinear dynamic characteristics, the null hypothesis of equality of mean values were strongly rejected for the two periods. In addition, by one-tailed Student's t-test, we concluded that time series in “Delta period” exhibit higher value of Kolmogorov complexity and Shannon entropy, indicating a higher level of information content and randomness. On the other hand, the Higuchi's Hurst exponent in “Delta period” was lower, which showed the weaker persistent in this period. Moreover, the multifractal specturm width after “Delta” emergence were reduced, representing a more stable multifractality. The sources for the formation of multifractal features are also investigated.            We analyzed the difference of nonlinear dynamic characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 transmission caused by ‘Delta Variant’.A higher level of information content and randomness was founded in “Delta period”.“Delta period” showed a weaker persistence.The multifractal spectrum width after “Delta” emergence was reduced, representing a more stable multifractality.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jian Wang; Mengdie Yang; Lin Lu; Wei Shao;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and bifurcations in a general Cournot duopoly model with distributed time delays]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sabiagdmwdtd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sabiagdmwdtd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.936Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper is devoted to the analysis of a Cournot game, described by a nonlinear mathematical model with four distributed time delays, modelling the behavior of two interacting firms on the market. For each firm, a delay for its own production and one for the production of the competitor are introduced. The analysis of the stability of the four equilibrium points is accomplished. The three equilibria with at least one zero component are shown to be unstable, regardless of the choice of time delays. For the stability and bifurcation analysis of the positive equilibrium, four scenarios are considered to highlight the role played by the time delays: only competitor's delays for both players, equal delays for both players, no delays for one player and only own delays for both players. Numerical simulations are performed to illustrate the theoretical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Loredana Camelia Culda; Eva Kaslik; Mihaela Neamţu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear biological population model; computational and numerical investigations]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nbpmcani.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nbpmcani.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.936Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This research paper provides precise solutions for nonlinear fractional population biology (FBP) models by implementing the generalized Khater (GK) technique and utilizing Atangana's conformable fractional (ACF) derivative operator. Because people have natural death and a birth rate, we can get demographic information using a model. Many physical features, such as exponential, hyperbolic, and trigonometric functions, were given a mathematical explanation. To get a better understanding of such methods, one should draw them in various ways. Many novel analytical solutions are obtained in distinct formulas, such as rational, hyperbolic, parabolic, etc.Additionally, we use Hamiltonian system properties to confirm the stability of the solutions we get. Finally, the trigonometric- quantic-B- spline (TQBS) scheme tests the accuracy of the obtained solutions through the novel applied analytical method by revealing potential problems and eliminating absolute errors. The power and effectiveness of the two employed analytical and numerical techniques are verified through their performances.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mostafa M.A. Khater;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics and bifurcations of a Filippov Leslie-Gower predator-prey model with group defense and time delay]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_daboafwgdatd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_daboafwgdatd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.932Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, the Leslie-Gower model with nonmonotonic functional response is extended to a nonsmooth Filippov control system to reflect the integrated pest management. Different from traditional Filippov models, here, we incorporate time delay as to account for predator maturity time. The stability of the equilibria and the existence of Hopf bifurcation of the subsystems are investigated. Moreover, sliding mode dynamics and regular/virtual/pseudoequilibria are analyzed. Numerical simulations indicate that all solutions finally converge to either the regular equilibrium, the pseudoequilibrium or a stable periodic solution according to different values of time delays and threshold levels. A boundary bifurcation that switches a stable regular equilibrium or a stable limit cycle to a stable pseudoequilibrium can occur. Meanwhile, global bifurcations from the standard periodic solution to the sliding switching bifurcation and then to the crossing bifurcation are obtained as time delay is increased. The results show that Filippov control strategies could effectively control the number of pests under the prescribed threshold, however, time delay may challenge pest control by the occurring of the sliding switching and crossing bifurcations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xubin Jiao; Xiaodi Li; Youping Yang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stationary and non-stationary pattern formation over fragmented habitat]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sanpfofh.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sanpfofh.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.932Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spatio-temporal pattern formation by a Bazykin type model is considered.The range of unstable modes related to Turing instability is identified.Pattern formation is considered over a fragmented domain.Stationary and time-varying spatial patterns are obtained.Transient patterns and their duration are studied numerically.        Spatio-temporal pattern formation over the square and rectangular domain has received significant attention from researchers. A wide range of stationary and non-stationary patterns produced by two interacting populations is abundant in the literature. Fragmented habitats are widespread in reality due to the irregularity of the landscape. This work considers a prey-predator model capable of producing a wide range of stationary and time-varying patterns over a complex habitat. The complex habitat is assumed to have consisted of two rectangular patches connected through a corridor. Our main aim is to explain how the shape and size of the fragmented habitat regulate the spatio-temporal pattern formation at the initial time. The analytical conditions are derived to ensure the existence of a stationary pattern and illustrate the role of the most unstable eigenmodes in determining the number of patches for the stationary pattern. Exhaustive numerical simulations help to explain the effect of the spatial domain size and shape on the transient patterns and the duration of the transients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Malay Banerjee; Swadesh Pal; Pranali Roy Chowdhury;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Predicting the dynamic process and model parameters of vector optical solitons under coupled higher-order effects via WL-tsPINN]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ptdpamuchevw.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ptdpamuchevw.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.931Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We propose the two-subnet physical information neural network with the weighted loss function (WL-tsPINN) to study the higher-order effects of ultra-short pulses in birefringence fiber transmission and analyze the formation mechanism of vector solitons. We predict the dynamical process of mixed-type single/double soliton and soliton molecules based on the higher-order coupled nonlinear Schrödinger equation (CNLSE) by this WL-tsPINN method. Moreover, we deduce the physical coefficients of the higher-order CNLSE from the mixed single soliton solution. Deep learning based on neural network is a powerful tool for further study of higher-order CNLSE and has potential significance for further study of soliton dynamics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo-Wei Zhu; Yin Fang; Wei Liu; Chao-Qing Dai;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interrelation measurement based on the multi-layer limited penetrable horizontal visibility graph]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_imbotmlphvg.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_imbotmlphvg.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.931Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interrelation measurement is the basis of big data mining. This paper proposes an efficient method to measure the dynamic correlation and synchronicity relationship of multidimensional data using the microscopic topological structure of a multi-layer network. In order to measure the dynamic correlation between multidimensional data, multidimensional data are transformed into a time-varying multi-layer limited penetrable horizontal visibility graph network. On this basis, a time-varying correlation measurement index of multidimensional data based on the microscopic structure of the interlayer network connection is proposed. In addition, based on the degree distribution of each layer and information entropy theory, a time-varying information measurement index of multidimensional data is introduced. Further, to measure the synchronicity relationship between multidimensional data, time-delay parameters are defined, and a method to transform multidimensional data into a delay time-varying multi-layer limited penetrable horizontal visibility graph network is developed. A symmetrical and antisymmetrical combinations index is defined to measure the synchronicity relationship and to determine which system leads the others. Numerical simulation verifies the effectiveness of the proposed index and the proposed method's robustness to handle data disturbed by noise. Finally, an empirical analysis is conducted using the price data of the energy and carbon markets. The dynamic relationship between the crude oil future and gasoline future market is obtained. The dynamic information spillover effect between the carbon and energy markets is analyzed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minggang Wang; Chenyu Hua; Mengrui Zhu; Shangshan Xie; Hua Xu; André L.M. Vilela; Lixin Tian;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State observer-based fuzzy echo state network sliding mode control for uncertain strict-feedback chaotic systems without backstepping]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sofesnuscswb.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sofesnuscswb.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.929Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To control uncertain strict-feedback chaotic systems, the adaptive backstepping technique is a popular method, yet this method requires repeatedly differentiating virtual control inputs, which will result in the “explosion of complexity” problem. In this paper, an alternative control method for uncertain strict-feedback chaotic systems without using backstepping technique is presented. We first translate the uncertain strict-feedback chaotic system into a new straightforward normative system whose states are unmeasurable, and then, an observer is designed to estimate the unknown states of the transformed system. A new recurrent neural network, namely fuzzy echo state network (FESN), is constructed to approximate the lumped uncertainty of the normative system. The semi-globally stability of the closed-loop system can be guaranteed by the FESN sliding mode controller that only uses one FESN and one adaptation law. Comparative simulations are put forward to verify the derived theoretical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiayan Li; Jinde Cao; Heng Liu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resistive state relaxation time in ZrO2(Y)-based memristive devices under the influence of external noise]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rsrtizutioen.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rsrtizutioen.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.929Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The effects of external digitally synthesized Gaussian noise on the resistive state relaxation time of a ZrO(Y)-based memristive device when switching from a low resistance state to a high resistance state have been experimentally investigated. A nonmonotonic dependence of the resistive state relaxation time on the external noise intensity is found. This behavior is interpreted as a manifestation of the noise-enhanced stability effect previously observed in various complex systems with metastable states. It is shown that the experimental results agree satisfactorily with the theoretical ones. The presented results indicate the constructive role of external noise and its possible use as a mechanism for controlling the kinetics of resistive switching.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.N. Koryazhkina; D.O. Filatov; V.A. Shishmakova; M.E. Shenina; A.I. Belov; I.N. Antonov; V.E. Kotomina; A.N. Mikhaylov; O.N. Gorshkov; N.V. Agudov; C. Guarcello; A. Carollo; B. Spagnolo;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synchronization phenomena in dual-transistor spiking oscillators realized experimentally towards physical reservoirs]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_spidsoretpr.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_spidsoretpr.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.928Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The spiking dynamics of a ring of transistor-based oscillators are considered.Experiments show multiple pattern-formation phenomena via synchronization.Noise injection, additional links and node patterning confer additional complexity.The system has several features desirable for use in physical reservoir computing.        Transistor-based chaotic oscillators are known to realize highly diverse dynamics despite having elementary circuit topologies. This work investigates, numerically and experimentally using a ring network, a recently-introduced dual-transistor circuit that generates neural-like spike trains. A multitude of non-trivial effects are observed as a function of the supply voltage and coupling strength, including pattern formation under incomplete synchronization and sensitivity to additional long-distance links. Globally-applied noise exerts a synchronizing effect that interacts with the other control parameters. When the network is partitioned in halves at different levels of granularity, their interplay gives rise to adversarial route-to-synchronization phenomena. These results highlight the generative ability of this circuit and motivate its consideration towards the future realization of physical reservoirs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ludovico Minati; Jim Bartels; Chao Li; Mattia Frasca; Hiroyuki Ito;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of nonlinear fractional optimal control systems described by delay Volterra–Fredholm integral equations via a new spectral collocation method]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_aonfocvanscm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_aonfocvanscm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.928Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We aim to introduce a new spectral collocation method for investigating and analyzing nonlinear delay control systems governed by the fractional mixed Volterra–Fredholm integral equations (MVFIEs). The generalized fractional Legendre basis (GFLB) is used as a complete orthogonal basis, and the fractional Legendre–Gaussian nodes are introduced and employed as the fractional collocation points. These nodes correspond to the zeros of the fractional-order Legendre function of degree . The convergence of the generalized orthogonal basis is discussed in detail based on the Sobolev and  norms. Additionally, new fractional integral and delay operators are implemented to reduce the primary control system to a static optimization system. Two benchmark fractional control problems, including delay, are considered to demonstrate the powerfulness and superiority of the new methodology. The introduced collocation approach can be successfully performed for solving even those fractional control problems having any irregularities in the control function, including jump discontinuities and bang–bang behavior.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hamid Reza Marzban; Atiyeh Nezami;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep and handcrafted features from clinical images combined with patient information for skin cancer diagnosis]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dahffcpifscd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dahffcpifscd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.928Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skin lesions diagnostic is a challenging problem due to the variety of visual aspects of the lesions. The clinical analysis of skin lesions relies on the visual information as well as on the complementary information provided by the patient. Since dermatologists make use of visual cues and patient clinical information, we investigate if the combination of features from convolutional neural networks (CNN), handcrafted features and patient clinical information can improve the performance of automated diagnosis of skin cancer. Most works on skin lesion diagnosis in the literature use dermoscopic images without patient clinical information. In order to address this problem, we used a clinical image dataset of skin lesions with patient information collected via smartphone named PAD-UFES-20. With the proposed fusion architecture we show that the results using clinical features as a complement to the CNN and handcrafted features improve the classification in terms of balanced accuracy by 7.1 % for cancer and by 3.2 % for melanoma as compared with only features extracted from a CNN. In addition, our findings show that combining only handcrafted features with deep features did not improve the results, indicating the importance of using clinical metadata for skin lesion classification.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlos Frederico S. da F. Mendes; Renato A. Krohling;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unsaturated piecewise bistable stochastic resonance with three kinds of asymmetries driven by multiplicative and additive noise]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_upbsrwdbmaan.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_upbsrwdbmaan.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.927Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UPBSR with three kinds of asymmetries is constructed.Asymmetric UPBSR driven by multiplicative and additive noise is studied.Both well-depth and well-width asymmetry dominates the three kinds of asymmetries.Two correlated noises can excite SR to appear as a double peak.The effects of individual parameters on SNR are highly coupled.        The performance of an unsaturated piecewise bistable stochastic resonance (UPBSR) with three kinds of asymmetries driven by multiplicative and additive Gaussian white noise is investigated. Firstly, by introducing an asymmetric factor into UPBSR potential, three kinds of asymmetries are constructed, i.e., well-depth asymmetry (WDA), well-width asymmetry (WWA), and both well-depth and well-width asymmetry (BDWA). Then, by deriving the output signal-to-nois…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tianchi Ma; Junxian Shen; Di Song; Feiyun Xu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stationary distribution, extinction and density function of a stochastic prey-predator system with general anti-predator behavior and fear effect]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sdeadfgabafe.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sdeadfgabafe.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.927Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The stochastic prey-predator with anti-predator behavior and fear effect is established.We obtain sufficient but almost conditions for the existence of stationary distribution.Sufficient conditions for population extinction are obtained.We derive the approximate expression of density function of the system.We give parameter analysis regarding the coexistence of population prey and predator.        In this paper, we examine a stochastic prey-predator system with fear effect and general anti-predator behavior. To tackle the impact of stochastic perturbations, we first propose a -stochastic threshold method to construct several necessary -Lyapunov functions. Then by defining a quasi-carrying capacity , sufficient conditions are established for the existence and uniqueness of stationary distribution  of the system. By solving the Fokker-Planck equation, the approximate expression of probability density function of the distribution  around its quasi-positive equilibrium is further derived. Besides, the extinction of prey and predator populations is studied. Finally, some numerical examples are provided to verify our theoretical results and study two aspects: (i) the impact of anti-predator behavior; (ii) the effect of prey fear.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bingtao Han; Daqing Jiang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assessing the impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the dynamics of dengue and HIV via fractional derivatives]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_atiosidahvfd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_atiosidahvfd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.926Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new non-integer order mathematical model for SARS-CoV-2, Dengue and HIV co-dynamics is designed and studied. The impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the dynamics of dengue and HIV is analyzed using the tools of fractional calculus. The existence and uniqueness of solution of the proposed model are established employing well known Banach contraction principle. The Ulam-Hyers and generalized Ulam-Hyers stability of the model is also presented. We have applied the Laplace Adomian decomposition method to investigate the model with the help of three different fractional derivatives, namely: Caputo, Caputo-Fabrizio and Atangana-Baleanu derivatives. Stability analyses of the iterative schemes are also performed. The model fitting using the three fractional derivatives was carried out using real data from Argentina. Simulations were performed with each non-integer derivative and the results thus obtained are compared. Furthermore, it was concluded that efforts to keep the spread of SARS-CoV-2 low will have a significant impact in reducing the co-infections of SARS-CoV-2 and dengue or SARS-COV-2 and HIV. We also highlighted the impact of three different fractional derivatives in analyzing complex models dealing with the co-dynamics of different diseases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Omame; Mujahid Abbas; Abdel-Haleem Abdel-Aty;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lipschitz stability analysis of fractional-order impulsive delayed reaction-diffusion neural network models]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_lsaofidrnnm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_lsaofidrnnm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.926Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fractional reaction-diffusion impulsive model is developed.The model allows for applications of impulsive control strategies.The concept of Lipschitz stability is introduced.Criteria for the global uniforms Lipschitz stability are established.The impulsive Lyapunov approach is applied.        In this paper, the concept of Lipschitz stability is introduced to impulsive delayed reaction-diffusion neural network models of fractional order. Such networks are an appropriate modeling tool for studying various problems in engineering, biology, neuroscience and medicine. Fractional derivatives of Caputo type are considered in the model. The effects of impulsive perturbations and delays are also under consideration. Lipschitz stability analysis is performed and sufficient conditions for global uniform Lipschitz stability of the model are established. The Lyapunov function approach combined with the comparison principle are employed in the development of the main results. The proposed criteria extend some existing stability results for such models to the Lipschitz stability case. The introduced concept is also very useful in numerous inverse problems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ivanka Stamova; Trayan Stamov; Gani Stamov;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction of dense maximal-dimensional hypercyclic subspaces for Rolewicz operators]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_codmhsfro.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_codmhsfro.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.925Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, weighted backward shift operators  associated to a Schauder basis of a Banach space are considered. These operators are emblematic in the setting of linear chaos in topological vector spaces. In a constructive way, it is shown the existence of a dense linear subspace having maximal dimension, all of whose nonzero members are simultaneously -hypercyclic for every  belonging to a sequence of admissible weights. Our proof does not use any general result about algebraic or topological genericity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Bernal-González; M.C. Calderón-Moreno; J. Fernández-Sánchez; G.A. Muñoz-Fernández; J.B. Seoane-Sepúlveda;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analog circuit implementation and adaptive neural backstepping control of a network of four Duffing-type MEMS resonators with mechanical and electrostatic coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_aciaanrwmaec.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_aciaanrwmaec.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.925Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper investigates the analog circuit implementation and adaptive neural backstepping control of a network of four Duffing-type MEMS resonators with mechanical and electrostatic coupling. Firstly, the mathematical model of such network is established by using a series-parallel mode of mechanical and electrostatic coupling between MEMS resonators. Secondly, the dynamic analysis reveals that the coupled network can generate complex nonlinear behaviors which seriously affect the system performance without taking actions. Thirdly, based on the energy flow theory, its equivalent analog electronic circuit is established to further verify inherent dynamical characteristics of a network of four Duffing-type MEMS resonators. Fourthly, to suppress the mentioned harmful nonlinear behaviors above, an adaptive neural backstepping control scheme is proposed here wherein the interval type 2 fuzzy neural network (IT2FNN) is used to estimate unknown nonlinear functions along with cosine barrier function to guarantee states boundedness. Stability analysis proves that all signals of the closed-loop system are bounded and the tracking errors are limited to the pregiven boundary. Finally, the effectiveness of our scheme is testified by abundant numerical simulation results.            We build the model of the Duffing-type MEMS resonator network.Abundant dynamical behaviors of this coupled network are revealed.We construct the circuit experimental platform of this coupled network.We design an adaptive neural backstepping controller to suppress nonlinear oscillations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shenghai Zhang; Shaohua Luo; Shaobo He; Hassen M. Ouakad;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novel fast fixed-time sliding mode trajectory tracking control for manipulator]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nffsmttcfm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nffsmttcfm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.925Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper studies the issue of high-precision trajectory tracking control for manipulator systems with uncertainty disturbances and develops a fast fixed-time control scheme. First, a new type of (FTSM) surface is constructed by combining inverse trigonometric functions, regardless of the size of the system state, which can obtain a faster convergence velocity and high accuracy. The stabilization time of this sliding mode (SM) surface is independent of the initial state. Subsequently, on this basis, an adaptive fixed-time control method is constructed by combining adaptive techniques through the new fixed-time stability lemma proposed in this paper, under which the system's SM variables and tracking errors are guaranteed to reach the region near the equilibrium point at a fixed time while the adaptive law estimates the upper bound of the disturbance and effectively weakens the chattering phenomenon. Finally, the simulation comparison is carried out under different conditions, and the simulation results show the superiority of the control scheme with high precision, fast velocity, and good robustness.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xin Zhang; Ran Shi;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-volatile memory characteristics of a Ti/HfO2/Pt synaptic device with a crossbar array structure]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nmcoatdwacas.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nmcoatdwacas.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.924Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The resistive switching and synaptic behavior of a fabricated Ti/HfO/Pt crossbar array device are investigated. The results demonstrated that TiO layers are created by the movement of oxygen ions during the positive SET process, thereby improving the endurance and multilevel switching behavior of the device. The random properties of SET process were described with the help of stochastic model of memristor based on the length of conductive filament. The analysis of the mean first passage time allows estimating the parameters of the dielectric switching layer such as the activation energy of the diffusive defects, its variation under the influence of the driving voltage and the value of the working temperature. Furthermore, the conductive mechanism of the Ti/HfO/Pt device with temperature variations and Schottky emission fitting was studied. Furthermore, the potentiation, depression, and the spike-time dependent plasticity behavior of the Ti/HfO/Pt devices have been demonstrated by well-designed pulse inputs. The observed gradual change in conductance is suitable for a synaptic device in a neuromorphic system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Osung Kwon; Sungjun Kim; Nikolay Agudov; Alexey Krichigin; Alexey Mikhaylov; Roberto Grimaudo; Davide Valenti; Bernardo Spagnolo;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementation of convolution neural network using scalogram for identification of epileptic activity]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iocnnusfioea.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iocnnusfioea.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.923Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inter-ictal state is a period between convolutions (seizures). Expert neurologist looks for inter-ictal activity within this period to support the diagnosis of epilepsy. The focus of this work is to automate the process of identification of inter-ictal activity from EEG and to distinguish it from the activity of a controlled patient. Also, we have worked on differentiating between different epileptic states. This work uses the Benchmark Bonn dataset and novel patient data collected from Max Hospital, Saket. Five groups are considered from Bonn database with the first four groups, with one case each and group five divided into ten cases and data collected from hospital is also considered. This study explores four cases under group 5, reporting of which is not available in the literature for…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arshpreet Kaur; Kumar Shashvat;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling properties of a class of interfacial singular equations]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_spoacoise.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_spoacoise.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.923Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An analysis of similarity solutions to the 1D singular interfacial equation has been done.The singular interfacial equation is reduced to a singular ordinary differential equation.The coarsening and roughness exponents are calculated analytically.We have obtained the perpetual coarsening on the interfacial equation.Analytical estimations are given for the height profiles.        This paper can be considered as an introductory review of scale invariance theories illustrated by the study of the equation  where  The dimensionals version of this equation is proposed for  to discuss the coarsening of growing interfaces that induce a mound-type structure without slope selection (Golubović, 1997). Firstly, the above equation is investigated in detail by using a dynamic scaling approach, thus allowing for obtaining a wide range of dynamic scaling functions (or pseudosimilarity solutions) which lend themselves to similarity properties. In addition, it is shown that these similarity solutions are spatial periodic solutions for any  confirming that the interfacial equation undergoes a perpetual coarsening process. The exponents  and  describing, respectively, the growth laws of the interfacial width and the mound lateral size are found to be exactly  and  for any  Our analytical contribution examines the scaling analysis in detail and exhibits the geometrical properties of the profile or scaling functions. Our finding coincides with the result previously presented by Golubović for .]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohamed Guedda; Krisztian Hriczo; Laila Taourirte; Jihade Chaiboub; Gabriella Bognar;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring market efficiency: The Shannon entropy of high-frequency financial time series]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mmetseohfts.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mmetseohfts.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.922Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When prices reflect all available information, the price dynamics is a martingale and the market is said to be efficient. However, much empirical evidence supports the conclusion about the inefficiency of financial markets, especially at high-frequency timescales. We investigate the sources and dynamics of the inefficiency of the ETF market at a 1 min timescale by proposing a computational methodology for a genuine estimation of the Shannon entropy. Since several sources of regularity lead to the detection of apparent inefficiencies, we build a multi-step filtering method, which allows (i) to remove the seasonality of volatility and heteroskedasticity, (ii) to detect and remove spurious effects due to price staleness, and (iii) to filter out microstructure noise. We corroborate our findings with an extensive analysis of the ETF market. We conclude that, after removing all known patterns of regularity, the market is not efficient at a one-minute time scale and on a weekly basis; however, the signal is weak.            The Shannon entropy of discretized returns is a tool for measuring market efficiency.Zero returns lead to false detection of market efficiency.A method for filtering out excess zero returns is constructed.A method for estimating entropy when a part of data is missing is developed.There is a low signal of market inefficiency for the Exchange Traded Funds.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrey Shternshis; Piero Mazzarisi; Stefano Marmi;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MFF-SAug: Multi feature fusion with spectrogram augmentation of speech emotion recognition using convolution neural network]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mmffwserucnn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mmffwserucnn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.921Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Speech Emotion Recognition (SER) is a complex task because of the feature selections that reflect the emotion from the human speech. The SER plays a vital role and is very challenging in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI). Traditional methods provide inconsistent feature extraction for emotion recognition. The primary motive of this paper is to improve the accuracy of the classification of eight emotions from the human voice. The proposed MFF-SAug research, Enhance the emotion prediction from the speech by Noise Removal, White Noise Injection, and Pitch Tuning. On pre-processed speech signals, the feature extraction techniques Mel Frequency Cepstral Coefficients (MFCC), Zero Crossing Rate (ZCR), and Root Mean Square (RMS) are applied and combined to achieve substantial performance used for emotion recognition. The augmentation applies to the raw speech for a contrastive loss that maximizes agreement between differently augmented samples in the latent space and reconstructs the loss of input representation for better accuracy prediction. A state-of-the-art Convolution Neural Network (CNN) is proposed for enhanced speech representation learning and voice emotion classification. Further, this MFF-SAug method is compared with the CNN + LSTM model. The experimental analysis was carried out using the RAVDESS, CREMA, SAVEE, and TESS datasets. Thus, the classifier achieved a robust representation for speech emotion recognition with an accuracy of 92.6 %, 89.9, 84.9 %, and 99.6 % for RAVDESS, CREMA, SAVEE, and TESS datasets, respectively.            Speech emotion recognitionFeature fusion – time and frequency domain feature extractionAugmentation techniquesConvolution Neural NetworksImproved accuracy of emotion classification]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Jothimani; K. Premalatha;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-conserving exclusion process with a dynamic obstacle]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nepwado.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nepwado.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.920Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Motivated by complex transport processes occurring in biological and physical systems, we study a non-conserving totally asymmetric simple exclusion process with a dynamic defect particle. The defect particle may appear or disappear stochastically and slows down the traffic of moving particles while bound to the lattice. We analyze the system in the context of mean-field approach, and investigate the steady state properties which exhibit a rich dynamic behavior. The theoretically obtained density profiles and current fully describe the phase diagram, further allowing to elucidate the effect of various dynamics individually. Depending upon non-conserving kinetics and defect dynamics, phase schema displays at most eighteen phases; in total, the system exhibits twenty-one phases. Several critical values of the kinetic rates that trigger a qualitative change in the phase diagrams are obtained using analytical arguments. The theoretical outcomes are validated through extensive Monte Carlo simulations.            The dynamics of the non-conserving TASEP system with a dynamic defect are investigated.The defect which binds/unbinds on a special site stochastically, modifies the hopping rate of particles to that site.Mean-field analysis is employed and density profiles are obtained analytically.Phase diagrams display a rich structure including mixed phases with a possibility of twenty-one distinct phases.The critical values of parameters that trigger the topological changes in the phase diagrams are theoretically calculated.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bipasha Pal; Arvind Kumar Gupta;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying influential nodes in social networks: Centripetal centrality and seed exclusion approach]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iinisnccasea.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iinisnccasea.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.919Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying influential nodes in a network is vital for the study of social network structure and to facilitate the dissemination of requisite information. The challenge we address is that, given a complex network, which nodes are more important? How can a group of disseminators be identified and selected to maximize any given field of influence? A series of centrality measures are proposed from different perspectives based on the topology of nodes. However existing methods suffer from problems that are intrinsic to singular consideration of node topology information, and they neglect the connection relationship between nodes when filtering the spreaders, resulting in imprecise evaluation results and limited spread scale. To solve this issue, this paper proposes a new centrality, inspired …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yan Wang; Haozhan Li; Ling Zhang; Linlin Zhao; Wanlan Li;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Editorial Board]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eb.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eb.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.917Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Chaos, Solitons and Fractals - Scholars Portal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soliton-mediated ionic pulses and coupled ionic excitations in a dissipative electrical network model of microtubules]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sipacidenmom.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sipacidenmom.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.916Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many cellular activities are mediated by microtubules (MTs), with most electrophysiological processes depending on ionic flow through MT cylinders. This paper addresses such conductive features by representing the MT as a nonlinear electrical transmission line composed of capacitive and dissipative properties. Thanks to the semi-discrete approximation near the continuum limit, coupled ionic pulses flowing along cellular microtubules are described by a set of coupled cubic complex Ginzburg-Landau (CGL) equations whose one of the solutions is a plane wave. The stability of the latter is checked, under weak modulation, using an explicit analytical expression for the modulational instability (MI) growth rate. The parametric analysis of the instability growth rate allows detecting parameter regions where ionic conductivity, through modulated waves, in the MT network is likely to occur. Dissipative bright-bright pulse soliton solutions for the nonlinearly coupled cubic CGL equations are constructed using a modified Hirota's bilinear method. A generalized coupled mode for the discrete ionic signal is proposed and used as the initial condition to be propagated in the nonlinear electrical transmission lattice of MT under direct numerical simulations. The ionic pulse transfer, mediated by the nonlinear interaction between oscillatory modes, is manifested by the formation of trains of modulated waves whose behaviors depend on the right choice of system parameters. Those results theoretically suggest that coupled ionic signals may facilitate information processing involving MTs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Tankou; Conrad Bertrand Tabi; Timoléon Crépin Kofané;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multistability, chaos and mean population density in a discrete-time predator–prey system]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mcampdiadps.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mcampdiadps.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.915Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We investigate a discrete-time system derived from the continuous-time Rosenzweig–MacArthur (RM) model using the forward Euler scheme with unit integral step size. First, we analyze the system by varying carrying capacity of the prey species. The system undergoes a Neimark–Sacker bifurcation leading to complex behaviors including quasiperiodicity, periodic windows, period-bubbling, and chaos. We use bifurcation theory along with numerical examples to show the existence of Neimark–Sacker bifurcation in the system. The transversality condition for the Neimark–Sacker bifurcation at the bifurcation point is derived using a different approach compared to the existing ones. Multistability of different kinds: periodic–periodic and periodic–chaotic are also revealed. The basins of attraction for t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajni; Bapan Ghosh;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resemblance of the power-law scaling behavior of a non-Markovian and nonlinear point processes]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rotpsbananpp.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rotpsbananpp.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.913Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We generalize Markovian point process model by introducing fractional Gaussian noise.Event count distributions are well replicated by a simple Markovian point process.Nonlinear Markovian point process replicates PSD of non-Markovian point process.Results hint at relationship between nonlinearity and non-Markovian behavior.        We analyze the statistical properties of a temporal point process driven by a confined fractional Brownian motion. The event count distribution and power spectral density of this non-Markovian point process exhibit power-law scaling. We show that a nonlinear Markovian point process can reproduce the same scaling behavior. This result indicates a possible link between nonlinearity and apparent non-Markovian behavior.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aleksejus Kononovicius; Rytis Kazakevičius; Bronislovas Kaulakys;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrability and high-order localized waves of the (4 + 1)-dimensional nonlinear evolution equation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iahlwot1nee.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_iahlwot1nee.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.912Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Constructing the exact solutions of high-dimensional nonlinear evolution equations and exploring their dynamics have always been important and open problems in real-world applications. The celebrated Korteweg-de Vries equation [KdV] and Kadomtsev-Petviashvili [KP] equation are typical examples of one-dimensional and two-dimensional integrable equations respectively. A natural idea is to investigate the integrable analogues of these equations in higher dimensional space. In this paper, an integrable extension of the Kadomtsev-Petviashvili equation, the (4 + 1)-dimensional nonlinear evolution equation (NLEE) [Physical Review Letters 96, (2006) 190201], is investigated. By dimensionality reduction we obtain three new nonlinear equations, namely (3 + 1)-dimensional NLEE, (2 + 1)-dimensional NLEE and (1 + 1)-dimensional NLEE. Bäcklund transformations and multi-soliton solutions are important characteristics of integrable equations. Based on the binary Bell polynomials and Hirota bilinear method we derive bilinear Bäcklund transformations and N-soliton solutions of these new equations, which show that these equations are integrable. We also give the multiple rational solutions of these new equations. These new integrable NLEEs enrich the models of integrable systems and help understand the new characteristics of nonlinear dynamics in real-world applications.            Due to the complexity of Eq. in the original form, this manuscript is the first study, although the twin one i.e., the first member of eq.  in [Physical Review Letters 96, (2006) 190201], has been studied extensively.Three new degenerate NLEEs are derived, respectively.The bilinear Backlund transformations and exact solutions of these new NLEEs are investigated based on the binary Bell polynomials and Hirota bilinear method.Novel resonant soliton solutions and strange wave solutions are described by 3D plots.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hao Tian; Yujun Niu; Behzad Ghanbari; Zhao Zhang; Yulei Cao;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and bifurcation analysis of a fractional order delay differential equation involving cubic nonlinearity]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sabaoaddeicn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sabaoaddeicn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.911Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fractional derivative and delay are important tools in modeling memory properties in the natural system. This work deals with the stability analysis of a fractional order delay differential equation We provide linearization of this system in a neighborhood of equilibrium points and propose linearized stability conditions. To discuss the stability of equilibrium points, we propose various conditions on the parameters , , ,  and . Even though there are five parameters involved in the system, we are able to provide the stable region sketch in the plane for any positive  and . This provides the complete analysis of stability of the system. Further, we investigate chaos in the proposed model. This system exhibits chaos for a wide range of delay parameter.            Delay differential equation with cubic nonlinearity with fractional order is discussed.Stability analysis is provided by using the linearization near equilibrium points.Stable region is sketched in the parameter plane –.Stability results are valid for any positive parameters  and .Chaos is observed for a wide range of parameters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sachin Bhalekar; Deepa Gupta;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bistable chaotic family and its chaotic mechanism]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bcfaicm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_bcfaicm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.908Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time-delayed effect can be determined by the change of the optimal window.The opposite time-delayed effects lead to chaos.Chaotic mechanism is repeated increasing and decreasing in depth of potential wells caused by delays.Chaotic mechanism is verified by constructing a force-free Duffing equation with an oscillatory double-well potential.Bistable chaotic family is formed based on the same mechanism.        The emergence of many chaotic families shows that chaos can be generated by deterministic approaches. From the perspective of the mechanism of chaos, we add the opposite time-delayed effects to an overdamped bistable system to obtain chaos. The effect of time delay is determined by the change of the optimal window which origin from logical stochastic resonance. A variety of chaotic systems with different chaotic attractors are obtained by different combinations of opposite effects. Furthermore, we propose the mechanism of chaos in time-delayed bistable systems, that is, the opposite time-delayed effects lead to repeated increasing and decreasing in depth of potential wells. This mechanism is verified by constructing a force-free Duffing equation with an oscillatory double-well potential. Results show that the bistable systems can form bistable chaotic family based on the same chaos generation mechanism.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guanghui Cheng; Rong Gui;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preface to the special issue nonlinear economic dynamics: A tribute to Tönu Puu]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_pttsindatttp.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_pttsindatttp.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.888Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Jose S. Cánovas; Laura Gardini; Fabio Tramontana; Anastasiia Panchuk; Iryna Sushko;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image encryption algorithm based on hyperchaotic system and a new DNA sequence operation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ieabohaandso.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ieabohaandso.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.880Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the application of multimedia technology intensifies recently, more and more attention has been paid to privacy protection in image data. The interest in DNA-based image encryption techniques is increasing due to their high parallelism and large storage capacity. However, there are only few types of operations in existing DNA encryption methods and many of them are susceptible to chosen-plaintext attacks. To solve these problems, this paper proposes a novel image encryption algorithm based on a new DNA sequence operation and hyperchaotic system. Firstly, SHA-256 algorithm is used in conjunction with chaotic systems to generate plaintext-related random sequences. Secondly, the plain image is decomposed into  channels and encoded into DNA matrices. Thirdly, a new DNA operation called DNA triploid mutation (DNA-TM) is introduced to achieve cryptographic conversion of DNA bases. Furthermore, after decoding three DNA matrices, row-column permutation and pixel diffusion are employed to fuse the image. The experimental results demonstrate that our encryption approach is secure, with an average information entropy of 7.9972. In addition, the security analysis reveals that our scheme can resist differential attacks, plaintext attacks, noise attacks and occlusion attacks.            Two-dimensional Logistic-adjusted-Sine map (2D-LASM) and four-dimensional quadratic autonomous hyperchaotic system (4D-QAHS) are utilized to generate chaotic sequences.A novel DNA sequence operation called DNA triploid mutation (DNA-TM) is introduced to disrupt the nucleotide bases.Dynamic DNA coding is used in our encryption process to keep the encryption algorithm secure.SHA-256 is combined with two chaotic systems to generate plaintext-related random sequences.Experimental result demonstrates that our method can resist various attacks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jinwei Yu; Wei Xie; Zhenyu Zhong; Huan Wang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Numerical search for the stationary quasi-breather of the graphene superlattice equation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nsftsqotgse.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_nsftsqotgse.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.879Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The propagation of electromagnetic solitons in a graphene superlattice device is governed by a modified sine-Gordon equation, referred to as the graphene superlattice equation. Kink-antikink collisions suggest the existence of a quasi-breather solution. Here, a numerical search for static quasi-breathers is undertaken by using a new initial condition obtained by a regular perturbation of the null solution. Our results show that the frequency of the initial condition has a minimum critical value for the appearance of a robust quasi-breather able to survive during more than one thousand periods. The amplitude and energy of the quasi-breather solution decrease, but its frequency increases, as time grows. The robustness of the new quasi-breather supports its experimental search in real graphene superlattice devices.            Numerical search for static quasi-breathers using a new initial condition obtained by a regular perturbation of the null solution.Appearance of a robust quasi-breather after a minimum critical value for the frequency of the initial condition.The robustness of the new quasi-breather supports its experimental search in real graphene superlattice devices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francisca Martin-Vergara; Francisco Rus; Francisco R. Villatoro;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized correlation dimension and heterogeneity of network spaces]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_gcdahons.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_gcdahons.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.877Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many systems can be transformed into collections containing a large number of networks, such as dynamic networks. Defining metrics on a set of networks leads to analyzing a discrete metric space. In this study, we calculate the generalized correlation dimension of the network space and discuss the relationship between the dimension series and the heterogeneity index. Model-based analysis shows that generalized correlation dimension and  (Global Rényi Index) can be used as basic indicators of network space, and the space with evolutionary structure exhibits different dimension series in local and global perspectives. Furthermore, we analyze two types of network spaces, financial snapshot networks and temporal networks. Calculations show that real network spaces also exhibit heterogeneity and correspond to non-trivial dimension series. In particular, from a global perspective, the correlation dimensions of the analyzed network spaces are significantly smaller than the number of network nodes, implying that the intrinsic dimensions of these spaces are much smaller than those in the distance definition. This paper provides an analytical framework to characterize network space, which can be applied to describe space structure and compare different network sets.            This paper analyzes the multifractality of network space.GRI can characterize the heterogeneity of network space.GRI can be represented by correlation dimensions.Multifractal structures are found in the temporal network dataset.Financial snapshot networks have non-trivial sequence of dimensions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chun-Xiao Nie;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractal interpolation over nonlinear partitions]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_fionp.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_fionp.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.877Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper introduces the fractal interpolation problem defined over domains with a nonlinear partition. This setting generalizes known methodologies regarding fractal functions and provides a new holistic approach to fractal interpolation. In this context, perturbations of nonlinear partition functions are considered and sufficient conditions for the existence of a unique solution of the underlying fractal interpolation problem for some classes of function spaces are given.            Introduces the fractal interpolation problem over domains with a nonlinear partition.Extends known methods and presents a new holistic approach to fractal interpolation.Perturbations of nonlinear partition functions are considered.Derives sufficient conditions for unique solutions in Bochner–Lebesgue and C spaces.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter R. Massopust;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A cooperative ensemble method for multistep wind speed probabilistic forecasting]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_acemfmwspf.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_acemfmwspf.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.876Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accurate wind speed forecasting is of great significance to ensure the safe utilization of wind power. However, the randomness and volatility nature of wind speed give rise to an enormous challenge to the precision of wind speed forecasting. Combining the data preprocess technology, feature selection method, forecasting model, optimization algorithm and data postprocessing technology, the complete ensemble empirical mode decomposition with adaptive noise-least absolute shrinkage and selection operator-quantile regression neural network (CEEMDAN-LASSO-QRNN) model is developed to preform multistep wind speed probabilistic forecasting. Within the proposed model, CEEMDAN technology is firstly employed to decompose original wind speed timeseries into several subsequences. For each subsequence, the explanatory variables constructed by a hybrid multistep forecasting strategy are selected by LASSO regression. Subsequently, QRNN forecasting models are established to obtain multistep conditional quantiles predictions for entire subsequences. Ultimately, the aggregated quantiles are served as the samples to fit approximate distribution through kernel density estimation (KDE), thus obtaining the probability density function, further achieving probabilistic predictions, interval predictions and point predictions. The case studies including four real datasets are provided to validate the dependability and feasibility of the proposed model. Experimental results indicate higher accuracy and robustness of the proposed model occur in multistep wind speed probabilistic forecasting.            The cooperative ensemble method is an ingenious integration of several single methods.CEEMDAN is used to decompose intricate original data into several sample subseries.Each subseries with the optimal parameters promises a more superior performance.Multistep wind speed probabilistic forecasting is realized by DR strategy and KDE.A case including four datasets verifies the performance of CEEMDAN-LASSO-QRNN model.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yaoyao He; Yun Wang; Shuo Wang; Xin Yao;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embedded solitons with                                                             χ                                                                                            (                            2                            )                                                                         and                                                             χ                                                                                            (                            3                            )                                                                         nonlinear susceptibilities having multiplicative white noise via Itô Calculus]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_esw2a3mwnvic.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_esw2a3mwnvic.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.876Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The objective of this paper is to locate the embedded solitons with  and  nonlinear susceptibilities in presence of multiplicative noise. Itô Calculus was implemented to carry out the analysis of the corresponding stochastic differential equation. The unified Riccati equation expansion method and enhanced Kudryashov’s approach yielded dark, bright and singular solitons. The derived soliton solutions show that the effect of white noise is present only in the phase component.            This paper recovered for the first time embedded solitons with  and  nonlinear susceptibilities in presence of multiplicative white noise by the usage of Itô Calculus.The unified Riccati equation expansion method and the enhanced Kudryashov’s approach gave way to such solitons.The effect of white noise appeared only in the phase component of the solitons.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elsayed M.E. Zayed; Mohamed E.M. Alngar; Reham M.A. Shohib; Anjan Biswas; Yakup Yıldırım; Luminita Moraru; Elena Mereuta; Hashim M. Alshehri;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modeling and quantifying the influence of rumor and counter-rumor on information propagation dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_maqtioacoipd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_maqtioacoipd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.875Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Establishing a dynamic modeling framework to analyze rumor propagation in stagesDividing rumor spreaders into super-infected and normal-infectedIntroducing vigilantes and rumor debunkers to reflect the diversity of public opinionEffective communication strategies are identified to refute the rumor.        Today, the spread of Internet rumors has become increasingly easier, however, once they spread widely, the network environment and even the social order will be broken down. Therefore, to help in designing effective rumor control strategies, we propose the two-stage rumor propagation dynamics model, in which the susceptible/educated-infected-recovered (SO-S/EIR) dynamics model is used to characterize the first stage and the susceptible/educated-infected-denied-recovered (C-S/EIDR) dynamics model is to characterize the second stage. In our model, according to the difference of rumor spreaders' confidence in the rumor, we divide them into super-infected and normal-infected, moreover, the global model incorporates vigilantes and rumor debunkers to reflect the diversity of public opinions. Our model is based on the forwarded quantity in the Chinese Sina-microblog and takes into account the impact of interactions between forwarding users, own cognitions, and own knowledge level on the propagation of the rumor. Our Model-based analytic and numerical analyses show that forwarding and transfer probabilities in our model are in accordance with the actual accident situation, besides, our sensitivity analyses describe important factors that affect the spread of the rumor in support of decision strategies to refute the rumor.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fulian Yin; Xinyi Jiang; Xiqing Qian; Xinyu Xia; Yanyan Pan; Jianhong Wu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A novel study on separation of particles driven in two steps based on standing surface acoustic waves]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ansosobossaw.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ansosobossaw.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.874Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the development of surface acoustic wave devices, the separation of micron-sized particles based on standing surface acoustic waves (SSAW) has been studied, and the method has the advantages of high efficiency and ease of operation. In this paper, we design a two steps SSAW-based model for separating three different sizes of particles. The particle with the largest diameter is separated in the first sorting step region, and the remaining two particles are separated in the second sorting step region. During the study, we investigate the SSAW device firstly. We chose three different materials for the comparative analysis of the piezoelectric substrates. Next, we investigate the effects of fork-finger pairs and input voltage of the interdigital transducer (IDT) on the stability of the output waveform and sound pressure intensity. Finally, we select the appropriate number of fork-finger pairs and determine the acoustic pressure intensity in the low and high voltage regions respectively, so that three different particles could be successfully sorted in two steps. This research result can provide a certain theoretical basis for practical research fields such as cell sorting and drug detection.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xueye Chen; Honglin Lv; Yaolong Zhang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discrete vortex quantum droplets]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dvqd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dvqd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.873Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two-dimensional discrete vortex quantum droplets (QDs) are considered for the first time.A novel discrete vortex QD is found, in which two components with different topological charges have the same pattern.The existence and characteristics of discrete vortex QDs with topological charges of up to 5 are investigated.        We analyze the existence and characteristics of discrete vortex quantum droplets with intrinsic topological charges  of up to 5 in two-component Bose-Einstein condensates in a deep two-dimensional (2D) optical lattice. The 2D discrete Gross-Pitaevskii equation with a Lee-Huang-Yang (LHY) correction term is used to model the condensate, which incorporates local contact interactions and LHY corrections induced by quantum fluctuations. The characteristics of vortical modes with  = 1 and  = 2 are studied in detail. The chemical potential  and peak density  of the modes are calculated as functions of the norm . The  curves of on-site-centered and off-site-centered modes with the same number of lattice sites are nearly identical. We make an analysis and reach a conclusion consistent with these simulation results. This system contains a nontrivial type of vortex mode known as the mixed-vortex mode, in which the two components have the same density pattern and different topological charges. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to report vortex modes with isomorphic density patterns and heteromorphic vortices in the field of quantum droplets.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zi-bin Zhao; Gui-hua Chen; Bin Liu; Yong-yao Li;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ratchet transport of particles in the obstacle lattices with topographical gradients]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rtopitolwtg.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rtopitolwtg.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.871Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study the transport of two types of particles (active particles and active particles with polar interaction) moving in the obstacle lattices with topographical gradients in the -direction. The direction of particle motion is determined by the topographical gradient and the transport behaviors are different for different types of particles. For active particles, there exists an optimal rotational diffusion coefficient (or the obstacle number) at which the average velocity of particles takes its maximum value. The average velocity increases with the self-propulsion speed. For active particles with polar interaction, particles can change their direction by changing the system parameters (the polar interaction strength, the rotational diffusion coefficient, and the self-propulsion speed).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei-jing Zhu; Jian-chun Wu; Bao-quan Ai;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chaotic jam and phase transitions in a lattice model with density dependent passing]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_cjaptilmwddp.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_cjaptilmwddp.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.871Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In real traffic dynamics, passing has a significant impact on the traffic flow. Passing/Overtaking is primarily influenced by the traffic density in the surroundings, therefore considering passing as constant is impractical. In this paper, we proposed a lattice hydrodynamic model with the consideration of density dependent passing for a unidirectional single lane highway to examine the traffic system more realistically. Due to various experimental investigations, the passing behavior is considered similar to the flow-density curve. The passing increases with the density and after achieving a maximum at a critical value, it decreases. Thus, implementing the idea to model density dependent passing similar to the optimal velocity function. The impact of density dependent passing on the lattice model is investigated through linear stability analysis and it is shown that with an increase in passing, the stability region reduces significantly. Using nonlinear analysis, the kink-antikink solution of the mKdV equation is obtained to describe the propagating behavior of the density wave near the critical point. For the small values of passing, there is a phase transition from the kink jam region to the free flow region, with decreasing sensitivity. On the other hand, for large values of passing, the phase transition occurs from the uniform to the kink jam region through the chaotic jam region, with increasing delay time. The influence of parameters involved in density dependent passing is investigated theoretically as well as numerically.            A lattice model using density dependent passing is proposed.The impact of density dependent passing on traffic flow is observed using the stability analysis.The effect of parameters involved is analyzed.Theoretical results are validated through simulation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Muskan Verma; Sapna Sharma;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discrete fractional cobweb models]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dfcm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_dfcm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.855Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the first time, the cobweb model is introduced for fractional difference equationsSeveral classical models are translated into discrete fractional calculusExplicit solutions of the models are givenConditions for stability of the equilibrium are given        In this article, we propose two types of discrete fractional cobweb models. We derive the analytical solutions of these models and establish sufficient conditions on the stability of their equilibria. We also provide two examples to demonstrate the applicability of our main results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Bohner; Jagan Mohan Jonnalagadda;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chebyshev cardinal polynomials for delay distributed-order fractional fourth-order sub-diffusion equation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ccpfddffse.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ccpfddffse.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.849Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The distributed-order time fractional fourth-order sub-diffusion equations is defined.The Chebyshev cardinal polynomials are employed to solve these problems.A distributed-order fractional derivative matrix is extracted.The accuracy of the proposed method is investigated in some numerical examples.        In this work, a category of delay distributed-order time fractional fourth-order sub-diffusion equations is investigated. The Chebyshev cardinal polynomials (as a proper class of basis functions) are employed to make an appropriate methodology for these problems. To this end, some matrix relationships regarding the distributed-order fractional differentiation (in the Caputo kind) of these polynomials are extracted and applied in generating the desired approach. The provided method converts solving these problems into obtaining the solution of systems of algebraic equations. The reliability of the technique is evaluated by solving three examples.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.H. Heydari; M. Razzaghi; J. Rouzegar;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-complex chaotic system based on new nonlinear function and OTA-based circuit realization]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_hcsbonnfaocr.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_hcsbonnfaocr.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.849Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This research proposes a chaotic system using a new modified rectangular nonlinear function based on the principle of the third-order jerk concept. The dynamic behaviors can be realized by manipulating only one parameter from periodic, non-periodic, single-scroll, and double-scroll attractors. The proposed chaotic system can achieve relatively high-complexity chaotic behavior, as evident in the comparatively high Kaplan-Yorke dimension (             = 2.43) with the existing jerk systems. The performances of the proposed chaotic system are also computed and simulated through the MATLAB numerical analysis, including scenarios of bifurcations branches, Lyapunov exponents, route to chaos, phase portraits, 0–1 test charts, and Poincaré map. The proposed system analyzes the coexistence of asymmetric or symmetric attractors confirmed with basins of attraction to highlight the presence of multiple attractors, which influence initial conditions. In addition, the system's offset boosting and amplitude control are included. Furthermore, a double-scroll attractor and a four-scroll attractor can also be achieved by placing nonlinear functions at different positions in the third-order system., The circuits of the proposed chaotic systems can be conveniently realized using commercially available operational transconductance amplifiers (OTAs) and capacitors. The performances of the circuit are also proven through the experimental results compared with the numerical results. The experimental results exhibit the ease of construction based on the new nonlinear function and are suitable for applying in the data encryptions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khunanon Karawanich; Pipat Prommee;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-phase synchronization of waves in a multiplex network of van der Pol oscillators]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_asowianovdpo.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_asowianovdpo.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.848Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study numerically the spatiotemporal dynamics and anti-phase synchronization of complex structures in a two-layer multiplex network of bidirectionally and repulsively coupled two-dimensional lattices. Each layer consists of locally and attractively coupled identical van der Pol oscillators. Depending on randomly distributed initial conditions the isolated layers can exhibit either a spiral or a target wave regime. The latter is found for first time for the locally coupled van der Pol lattice considered in this work. We vary the inter-layer coupling strength for either fixed or changing intra-layer coupling strengths in the interacting layers. The numerical results are summarized in the two-dimensional diagrams plotted in the “intra-layer coupling strength – inter-layer coupling strength” parameter plane. Anti-phase synchronization is identified by evaluating the local and global cross-correlation coefficients which are equal to −1. We also explore the impact of random de-multiplexing on the robustness of the observed spatiotemporal structures and anti-phase synchronized regimes in the two-layer network.            Target waves have been found for the first time in a 2D network of locally coupled van der Pol oscillators.Anti-phase synchronization of wave structures has been shown in a two repulsively coupled 2D lattices.The robustness of anti-phase synchronization has been explored for sparse inter-layer coupling.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>I.A. Shepelev; A.V. Bukh; G.I. Strelkova;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution of trust in a hierarchical population with punishing investors]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eotiahpwpi.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eotiahpwpi.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.848Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There exists a stable coexistence state between punishing investors and trustworthy trustees in a hierarchical population.An intermediate fraction of investors can help trust evolve better for low punishment intensity.A higher fraction of investors can be more efficient to elevate the trust level for strong punishment intensity.        Trust plays an essential role in the development of human society. According to the standard trust game, an investor decides whether to keep or transfer a certain portion of initial stake to a trustee. In the latter case, the stake is enhanced to signal the value of trust. The trustee then chooses how much to return to the investor. We here distinguish two types of investors and two types of trustees who can learn from each other. While a trustee can be trustworthy or untrustworthy, an investor could be normal or punishing one. The latter strategy punishes both untrustworthy trustees and normal investors who are reluctant to control misbehaving trustees. Importantly, we assume a hierarchical population where the portion of investors and trustees is fixed. By means of replicator equation approach, we study the -player trust game and calculate the level of trust and trustworthiness. We find that the introduction of punishment can induce a stable coexistence state between punishing investors and trustworthy trustees. Furthermore, an intermediate fraction of investors can better promote the evolution of trust when the punishment intensity is low. For more intensive punishment, however, a higher fraction of investors can be more efficient to elevate the trust level. In addition, we reveal that appropriate increase of the punishment intensity can enlarge the attraction domain of the coexistence state.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ketian Sun; Yang Liu; Xiaojie Chen; Attila Szolnoki;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global dynamics for a class of tristable system with negative stiffness]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_gdfacotswns.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_gdfacotswns.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.846Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tristable system with negative stiffness has attracted extensive attention in the low frequency vibration isolation and vibration energy harvester. As a low frequency vibration isolator, it can achieve high static stiffness and low dynamic stiffness. As a vibration energy harvester, it had a wider bandwidth for resonance than the bistable one. The introduction of negative stiffness may induce subharmonic resonance and chaos in the tristable system. Chaos usually brings disorder to mechanical vibration system. Subharmonic resonance plays the negative effect on low frequency vibration isolation because they will transfer the high frequency energy of the system to the low frequency, but it is beneficial to broaden the working frequency band of vibration energy harvester. In this paper, the subharmonic bifurcation and chaos of a class of tristable system with negative stiffness are studied. The piecewise linearized systems are established to approximate the system with tristable potential. In order to conduct Melnikov analysis, the homoclinic-heteroclinic orbits and periodic orbits for the unperturbed piecewise linearized system are obtained respectively. The subharmonic Melnikov method for nonsmooth systems with four switched manifolds is developed. The thresholds for homoclinic-heteroclinic chaos and subharmonic resonance are derived by using non-smooth Melnikov method. It provides a theoretical support not only for design of the vibration energy harvester to obtain wider working frequency band, but also for design of the vibration isolation system to avoid high frequency energy transfer to low frequency. Moreover, the phenomena for infinite subharmonic bifurcations to chaos from odd order subharmonic orbit and the coexistence for chaotic and subharmonic attractors are revealed. The subharmonic Melnikov method with four switching manifolds developed in this paper lays a foundation for the subharmonic resonance analysis of other nonsmooth tristable systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Biliu Zhou; Yanfei Jin; Huidong Xu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public goods game on coevolving networks driven by the similarity and difference of payoff]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_pggocntsadop.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_pggocntsadop.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.846Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humans try to escape from their mundane lives and look for different experiences. Based on this assumption and story, this paper considers asynchronous public goods games on coevolving networks driven by payoff difference. Starting from a regular square lattice, agents disconnect from neighbors who have similar payoff, and they connect to new agents with different payoff. We measure network cohesion by the clustering coefficient. The results demonstrate multiple stages of the system. There are two stages where cooperation sustains. One is convex, and another is concave. When there is a shift from the defective stage to a cooperative one, the system generates a strong network cohesion facilitating cooperation to begin emerging. Near the tipping point of the two cooperative stages, the system strengthens the network cohesion to promote the stage transition. The time-dependent networks weaken the possibility of counteracting defection by forming cooperative alliances, which happens in the classic public goods game. However, the disconnection from similar payoff and the connection to different payoff can be matched appropriately to sustain cooperation best.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chaoqian Wang; Zongzhe Lin; Dale S. Rothman;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mode selection and stability of attractors in Chua circuit driven by piezoelectric sources]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_msasoaccdbps.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_msasoaccdbps.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.845Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The piezoelectric ceramic can be activated to produce continuous voltage and it is often used to excite nonlinear circuits, which is tamed as functional circuit to detect the acoustic wave and mechanic forcing. When two piezoelectric devices are combined to couple a nonlinear circuit, any switch between two channels embeds with piezoelectric ceramic will induce distinct mode transition in the output voltages. In addition, synchronous inputs from two piezoelectric ceramics will induce competition on exciting the nonlinear circuit and then the mode selection becomes competitive. In this paper, two piezoelectric devices are incorporated in two different branch circuits of the Chua circuit, and each piezoelectric ceramic is connected with a resistor in series in the branch circuit, the Chua circuit will be driven by two different external stimuli generated from the piezoelectric devices along the two branch circuits in parallel. The two branch circuits embedded with piezoelectric devices are controlled by two switchers             ,             , and the induced piezoelectric voltages are described by periodic from without losing generality. Three cases are investigated for detecting the stability of attractors and mode selection in the chaotic Chua circuit driven by piezoelectric voltage sources. It is confirmed that the involvement of piezoelectric ceramic into the nonlinear circuit can control the dynamics and firing patterns effectively.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Feifei Yang; Jun Ma; Xinlei An;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A flexible grey Fourier model based on integral matching for forecasting seasonal PM2.5 time series]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_afgfmbffspts.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_afgfmbffspts.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.845Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PM in each city exhibits seasonal and trend variations, but its seasonal pattern differed regionally. Under the novel grey modelling framework, a flexible grey Fourier model is developed by introducing the Fourier series to approximate the seasonal forcing. An integral matching method is employed to estimate the structural parameters and initial value simultaneously, then a data-driven order selection approach is utilized to accommodate various seasonal features. Next, Monte-Carlo simulation is designed to verify the effectiveness of the order selection approach and the influence of noise level. Finally, this model is established for predicting the monthly PM of four capital cities in the Yangtze River Delta of China. The results indicate that it not only reflects the different seasonal patterns of the four cities but also performs well compared to the seven competitive models.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaolei Wang; Naiming Xie; Lu Yang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatial dynamics of a fractional predator-prey system with time delay and Allee effect]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sdoafpwtdaae.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_sdoafpwtdaae.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.845Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, we investigate the spatial dynamics of a class of spatial fractional predator-prey systems with time delay and Allee effect. Firstly, Hopf bifurcation and Turing bifurcation conditions are obtained by using stability theory and bifurcation theory. Then, the abundant dynamic behaviors of the system are demonstrated by numerical simulation. Finally, numerical results show that time delay, Allee effect, and fractional diffusion can affect the formation 3D Turing patterns such as spherical, tube, spherical and tube coexisting and the constitution of 3D spiral wave patterns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhimin Bi; Shutang Liu; Miao Ouyang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new chaotic system with novel multiple shapes of two-channel attractors]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ancswnmsota.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ancswnmsota.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.842Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, a three-dimensional nonlinear system with only one equilibrium point is constructed based on the Anishchenko-Astakhov oscillator. The system is analyzed in detail using time-domain waveform plots, phase diagrams, bifurcation diagrams, Lyapunov exponent spectra, basins of attraction, spectral entropy, and C complexity (a parameter for dynamic properties). It is found that this system has excellent dynamical behavior: the emergence of novel multiple shapes of two-channel attractors and the gradual evolution of clumped and ring-shaped attractors can be tuned by only one parameter. The system also exhibits multistability with three types of dynamical behavior, namely, coexistence of two types of periodic attractors, and coexistence of quasi-periodic/chaotic attractors at different initial values. Moreover, the system has transient behavior, significantly increasing the complexity of the system. Finally, a hardware circuit mimicking the system is implemented. Such dynamical characteristics can be controlled by only one parameter, which is great cost savings and highly efficient in engineering applications.            A chaotic system with novel multiple shapes of two-channel attractors is discovered.By adjusting only one parameter of the system, rich dynamic behavior can be obtained.The system has three different types of multistability phenomena.It has transient behavior and high spectral entropy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chenyang Hu; Qiao Wang; Xiefu Zhang; Zean Tian; Xianming Wu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The limit dynamics for the vacuum Einstein equations in a homogeneous universe]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_tldftveeiahu.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_tldftveeiahu.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.841Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We study the dynamics of the Bianchi IX universe when one of the structure constants tends to zero, i.e. we study the dynamics of the Bianchi VII universe. We prove that there is a surface filled of periodic orbits surrounding an equilibrium point, and that except for another surface filled of equilibria the remainder orbits comes and go to infinity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaume Llibre;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Approximate solutions for the fractional order quadratic Riccati and Bagley-Torvik differential equations]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_asftfoqrabde.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_asftfoqrabde.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.821Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In order to apply the Galerkin method, the motivation of the study is to drive and use new theorems in order to facilitate the calculations of inner products between Legendre polynomials and their integer/fractional derivatives.The Legendre-Galerkin technique is used to solve the quadratic Riccati and Bagley-Torvik and other fractional-order differential equations.The suggested approach for the linear Bagley-Torvik differential equation error estimate is discussed and the results are computed.To demonstrate the effectiveness of the Legendre-Galerkin method, tables and graphs were utilized to show outcomes and the estimated error.        The Galerkin method is presented and applied for getting semi-analytical solutions of quadratic Riccati and Bagley-Torvik differential equations in fractional order. New theorems are proved to minimize the generated residual after invoking the Legendre polynomials as a basis in the Galerkin method. The proposed method is compared with other methods by solving some initial value problems of different fractional orders. The comparisons and results are illustrated via tables and figures. It can be concluded that the Legendre-Galerkin method is convenient for these problems due to its efficiency and reliability.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohamed Fathy; K.M. Abdelgaber;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finite-time input-to-state stability of switched stochastic time-varying nonlinear systems with time delays]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_fisosstnswtd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_fisosstnswtd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.820Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article extends the finite-time input-to-state stability (FTISS) to switched stochastic time-varying nonlinear systems with time delays. By using the methods of Razumikhin theorem, comparison principle combined with average dwell-time (ADT) approach, several sufficient conditions of nonlinear switched stochastic delayed systems are analyzed to obtain ISS property in the framework of finite time. Compared with the existing results, we allow the upper bound estimation for the derivative of Lyapunov function to be time-varying, which takes both positive and negative values. Finally, an example is given to illustrate the effectiveness of the proposed results.            A novel definition of FTISS is introduced, which generalizes the traditional ISS definition of nonlinear systems.The time delays are considered in this paper, and we generalize current results to the stochastic setting.Different from the existing results, the derivative of Lyapunov function is relaxed to be positive definite or indefinite.An example is presented to demonstrated the effectiveness of the proposed results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meng Zhang; Quanxin Zhu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Formation factors for a class of deterministic models of pre-fractal pore-fracture networks]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_fffacodmoppn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_fffacodmoppn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.819Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The main aim of this paper is to reveal effects of fractal features on the formation factors associated with different transport processes in scale invariant pore-fracture networks. Accordingly, we explore a class of deterministic infinitely ramified networks associated with pre-fractal standard Sierpinski carpets (including Sierpinski cubes and inverse Menger sponges). The focus is placed on the effects of network ramification, connectivity, and loopiness on the transport streamline constriction and tortuosity of transmission paths. The differences between the formation factors associated with the diffusibility, electrical conductivity, and hydraulic permeability are elucidated. Explicit expressions for the constrictivity and formation factors of deterministic pre-fractal networks are derived. In this regard, we stress that the electrical formation factor obeys the Archie law only if the random walk in the pre-fractal pore-fracture network is recurrent. We also note that the Archie's exponent can be either equal to, or less than the power-law exponent characterizing the scaling behavior of diffusibility. The notion of the structural formation factor is introduced. The values of scaling exponents characterizing the formation factors associated with different transport properties of the model networks are found to be within the ranges of field observations.            Effects of fractal features of pore-fracture network on the transport properties of a porous medium are ascertained.Effects of network ramification, connectivity, and loopiness on the formation factors are revealed.Differences between scaling exponents of formation factors associated with different transport phenomena are elucidated.Explicit analytic relations are derived for some kinds of deterministic models of pre-fractal pore-fracture networks.Electrical formation factor obeys Archie law only if the random walk in the pre-fractal pore-fracture network is recurrent.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander S. Balankin; Juan Ramírez-Joachin; Gabriela González-López; Sebastián Gutíerrez-Hernández;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exponential stabilization of chaotic systems based on fuzzy time-triggered intermittent control]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_esocsboftic.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_esocsboftic.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.819Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The exponential stabilization of chaotic systems is studied via fuzzy time-triggered intermittent control (FTIC). For the Takagi-Sugeno (T-S) fuzzy model representing a chaotic system, the mathematical description of FTIC is presented initially. Compared with fuzzy intermittent control (FIC), FTIC just needs the information at sampling instants on control time intervals. Compared with fuzzy sampled-data control (FSC), FTIC only transmits partial sampling data. Then, for the deduced FTIC system, a novel mixed Lyapunov functional is constructed to establish an exponential stabilization theorem. Based on it, FTIC can be designed. Further, the amount of transmitted data and the cost function are considered as two performance indexes. Finally, the inverted pendulum system and the chaotic Lorenz system are taken as examples to show the effectiveness and superiority of FTIC.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuo Peng; Qingzhi Wang; Baozeng Fu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Higher order smooth positon and breather positon solutions of an extended nonlinear Schrödinger equation with the cubic and quartic nonlinearity]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_hospabwtcaqn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_hospabwtcaqn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.818Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We construct certain higher order smooth positon and breather positon solutions of an extended nonlinear Schrödinger equation with the cubic and quartic nonlinearity. We utilize the generalized Darboux transformation method to construct the aforementioned solutions. The three well-known equations, namely nonlinear Schrödinger equation, Hirota equation, and generalized nonlinear Schrödinger equation, are sub-cases of the considered extended nonlinear Schrödinger equation. The solutions which we construct are more general. We analyze how the positon and breather positon solutions of the constituent equations get modified by the higher order nonlinear and dispersion terms. Our results show that the width and direction of the smooth positon and breather-positon solutions are highly sensitive to higher-order effects. Further, we carry out an asymptotic analysis to predict the behaviour of positons. We observe that during collision positons exhibit a time-dependent phase shift. We also present the exact expression of time-dependent phase shift of positons. Finally, we show that this time-dependent phase shift is directly proportional to the higher order nonlinear and dispersion parameters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Monisha; N. Vishnu Priya; M. Senthilvelan; S. Rajasekar;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Master-slave synchronization of a new fractal-fractional order quaternion-valued neural networks with time-varying delays]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_msoanfqnnwtd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_msoanfqnnwtd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.817Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the first time in the literature, quaternion algebra is combined with a new fractal-fractional order NNs.This paper generalizes the fractional derivative by incorporating the fractal dimension into the fractional operator.Firstly, constructing adaptive quaternion-valued controllers with sign function has been established.Novel sufficient criteria are derived to guarantee the existence and uniqueness of equilibrium points.Finally, new synchronization criteria have been developed for FFoQVNNs.        In this paper, a new fractional differentiation operator is considered the convolution of a power law with a fractal derivative. The novel operator sought to attract more non-local memory effects and self-similarities in chaotic attractors. This paper addresses the problem of fractal-fractional order quaternion-valued neural networks (FFoQVNNs) with time-varying delays. The sufficient conditions for the existence and uniqueness of an equilibrium point are derived for the proposed model by employing contraction mapping. The Lyapunov direct technique and fractal-fractional differential theory achieve the finite-time synchronization criteria by dividing the FFoQVNNs into four real-valued systems. Furthermore, the settling time is determined, which impact by the fractal dimension , fractional-order , and control parameters. Finally, a corresponding numerical simulation is demonstrated to show the accuracy of the theoretical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Ramesh Babu; P. Balasubramaniam;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some local fractional Maclaurin type inequalities for generalized convex functions and their applications]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_slfmtigcfata.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_slfmtigcfata.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.816Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, we establish a new local fractional integral identity involving three point by the use of Peano kernel approach. Using this identity we derive some new local fractional integrals inequalities of Maclaurin-type for functions whose local fractional derivatives are generalized convex functions. In order to show the effectiveness of the obtained results, we apply them in numerical integration and to special means.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Meftah; A. Souahi; M. Merad;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic analysis of mean-field and fractional-order epidemic vaccination strategies by evolutionary game approach]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_daomafvsbega.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_daomafvsbega.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.816Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Individual's perception of the participant in a vaccine program reflects their intrinsic appreciation of the trade-off between vaccine behavior, risk of infection, and memory effect. Here we present a mean-field approximation and fractional-order model embedded with the evolutionary game theory (EGT) process for susceptible-vaccinated-infected-recovered (SVIR) epidemic dynamics, where the two types of immunity, artificial and natural immunity, are considered. Besides the well-known vaccination game models, we successfully establish a theoretical approach of fractional-order dynamics for vaccination games in which epidemic spread and individual decisions are supposed to evaluate social behavior. The EGT governs the strategy adoption, while the fractional-order process directs the memory eff…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohammad Sharif Ullah; M. Higazy; K.M. Ariful Kabir;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impacts of special cooperation strategy with reward and punishment mechanism on cooperation evolution]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ioscswapmoce.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ioscswapmoce.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.814Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper introduces a special cooperation strategy with both punishment and reward capabilities and analyzes the effect of this strategy on cooperation evolution. The results show that the evolutionary stable states include full defection, the coexistence of ordinary cooperators and defectors, the coexistence of special cooperators and defectors, the coexistence of special cooperators and ordinary cooperators, and the coexistence of the three strategies. Punishment can induce cooperation. Under moderate punishment, the greater the reward the more conducive to cooperation, while under larger punishment, higher rewards conversely weaken the facilitative effect on cooperation. As the temptation increases, ordinary cooperators decrease to zero, while special cooperators increase first and start to decrease or even die out when the ordinary cooperators disappear. The coexistence of the three strategies presents that the ordinary cooperator group is exploited by the defectors, the special cooperator group is invaded by the ordinary cooperators, and the defector group is suppressed by the special cooperators, making the three strategies mutually suppressive and interdependent, and ultimately stable coexistence. The presence of special cooperators significantly promotes cooperation evolution in systems. This contributes to a better understanding of the origins and transformations of social norms and institutions.            Introduces special cooperators with reward and punishment in social dilemmaThree strategies have distinct circular invasion and circular dependence.Moderate punishment and reward contribute to cooperation.At higher punishment, excessive rewards weaken the facilitation of cooperation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiuhui Pan; Yue Wang; Mingfeng He;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controversy in financial chaos research and nonlinear dynamics: A short literature review]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_cifcrandaslr.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_cifcrandaslr.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.814Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Controversy between chaotic versus stochastic dynamics in the academic literature is shown.Debate around Hurst exponents, multifractality, momentum and market efficiency stated.Full citation network is proposed for over 80,000 publications.Bibliometric analysis shows relevant communities and research papers.Empirical findings of the literature and coherent publication overviews are depicted.        In this study, we apply a bibliometric analysis paired with a subsequent snowball sampling procedure. Moreover, we display a full citation network analysis, outlining the most relevant publications and contributions, defining relevant measures and show the interconnectivities and gaps within the existing research. Second, we will present a controversy within financial chaos literature, namely, whether financial dataset dynamics are chaotic or stochastic in nature and state empirical insights derived from the sampled literature. In addition, we show the interconnections between chaoticity, Hurst exponents, multifractality, scaling, long memory and market efficiency. Finally, we conclude our findings and discuss critically future avenues of research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Markus Vogl;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics in the biparametric spaces of a three-species food chain model with vigilance]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ditbsotfcmwv.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ditbsotfcmwv.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.814Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investigated the effect of basal prey's and middle predator's vigilance on the stability of a three-species food chain model.Focused on exploring system dynamics in multiple biparametric spaces using isospike and largest Lyapunov exponent diagrams.The chaotic regime features numerous periodic patches, including shrimp-like structures that show period-bubbling phenomena.Multiple overlaps between periodic structures give rise to multiple coexisting attractors having intricate basin boundaries.Investigation shows that vigilance promotes regularity; however, too much vigilance may cause species extinction.        In nature, vigilance is a common anti-predator strategy prey individuals employ to protect themselves from a possible attack. It gives them sufficient time to take cover or flee. Yet …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mainul Hossain; Ruma Kumbhakar; Nikhil Pal;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time-fractional telegraph equation with ψ-Hilfer derivatives]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ttewd.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ttewd.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.813Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper deals with the investigation of the solution of the time-fractional telegraph equation in higher dimensions with -Hilfer fractional derivatives. By application of the Fourier and -Laplace transforms the solution is derived in closed form in terms of bivariate Mittag-Leffler functions in the Fourier domain and in terms of convolution integrals involving Fox H-functions of two-variables in the space-time domain. A double series representation of the first fundamental solution is deduced for the case of odd dimension. The results derived here are of general nature since our fractional derivatives allow to interpolate between Riemann-Liouville and Caputo fractional derivatives and the use of an arbitrary positive monotone increasing function  in the kernel allows to encompass most of the fractional derivatives in the literature. In the one dimensional case, we prove the conditions under which the first fundamental solution of our equation can be interpreted as a spatial probability density function evolving in time, generalizing the results of Orsingher and Beghin (2004). Some plots of the fundamental solutions for different fractional derivatives are presented and analysed, and particular cases are addressed to show the consistency of our results.2010 MSC: 35R11, 26A33, 35A08, 35A22, 35C15, 60G22.            Integral and series representations of the solution of the time-fractional telegraph equation with ψ-Hilfer derivatives.Probabilist interpretation of the first fundamental solution in the one-dimensional case.Computation of fractional moments of the first fundamental solution and analysis of their asymptotic behaviours.Some plots of the fundamental solutions for different choices of the function ψ are presented and analysed.Connections between the telegraph process and the Brownian motion are shown.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Vieira; M. Ferreira; M.M. Rodrigues;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of local timescales in a cellular automata model of excitable media]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ioltiacamoem.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_ioltiacamoem.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.813Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A cellular automata system known as the Greenberg-Hastings cellular automata (GHCA), with cyclic and excitable individual dynamics, provides a useful paradigm for modeling emergent phenomena in an excitable medium. Most past studies of GHCA have investigated the asymptotic dynamics of the system, assuming fixed extents for the active and passive dynamical phases. This study is a systematic investigation of the relationship between the dynamical properties of individual cells of a small system implementing excitable dynamics, and the emergent system wide asymptotic state. The impact of the temporal extents of individual dynamical phases (            ,             ), on the probability of persistence (            ,            ), defined as the fraction of initial configurations which sustain spatiotemporal oscillations asymptotically, is examined for each unique configuration of the system. The main result obtained is that the probability of persistence (            ,             ) assumes a characteristic sigmoidal form, as the dynamical behaviour of the system transitions from absolute quiescence to persistent spatiotemporal oscillations, with respect to the parameters (            ,             ). A plot of the numerical findings in the (            ,             ) space provides a consolidated view of their impact on the emergent behaviour of the system. In conclusion, some implications of the methods and results presented in this work, to the study of emergent phenomena in excitable systems, are discussed.            Cellular automata with discrete reaction-diffusion dynamics models excitable media.Timescales of local dynamics determine emergence of persistent oscillations.Introduces general method for exhaustively parsing phase space of cellular automataTransition from quiescence to persistence observed with increasing local activity]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Promit Moitra; Abhijit Sen;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cold-start link prediction integrating community information via multi-nonnegative matrix factorization]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_clpicivmmf.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_clpicivmmf.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.811Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cold-start link prediction has attracted much attention as a sub-problem of link prediction recently. However, due to the influence of some isolated nodes existing in the network, the network structure is disconnected, so that the existing methods cannot realize the task of link prediction well. Therefore, how to excavate and fuse some available information from the network data to help complete the link prediction is the key to solve this problem. In this paper, we propose a multi-nonnegative matrix factorization model that implements the prediction of missing edges of isolated nodes in the overall disconnected state of the network structure. Through several methods, three global and local attribute information, namely the community membership information of the node attributes, the attribute similarity between the nodes, and the partial first-order structure characteristics existing among the nodes, are extracted on network. Then, using the proposed new model, the cold-start link prediction problem on the structured disconnected network is finally solved by integrating the three kinds of information from multiple perspective. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our proposed method performs better than state-of-the-art methods when solving the cold-start link prediction problem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minghu Tang; Wenjun Wang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An efficient numerical scheme for fractional characterization of MHD fluid model]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_aensffcomfm.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_aensffcomfm.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.811Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to precisely characterize the fractional modeling and physical treatment is an ongoing challenge in fluid mechanics and numerical techniques, especially in nonlinear complex models. A model study is conducted to report fractional time-dependent mixed convection incompressible fluid flow inside a channel. The physical system is under the impacts of viscous dissipation, electrical and magnetic fields. Three fractional operators Atangana Baleanu Caputo (ABC), Caputo Fabrizio (CF), and classical Caputo (CC) are involved into the temporal derivative. Transformations are used to convert the physical model into equivalent fractional partial differential equations (FPDEs). The computational code is developed for finite difference schemes and code validation is made for different fractional operators. The simulations have been performed to check the appropriate fractional operator and a comparison is made to check the accuracy and efficiency. Additionally, a set of graphs is asserted to show the velocity and temperature distribution for various values of parameters. Velocity is analyzed as decreasing function with an enhancement in the Rayleigh number while the higher fractional parameter (α) causes a dominant drop. A dropped velocity is analyzed in the absence of oscillation and enhanced velocity for higher oscillation, while a more dominant increment in the velocity is noted when Λ is non-zero. A decrease in the thermal layer is observed for higher , and a more dominant impact is noted for smaller values of the fractional parameter. The pattern of the thermal profile is observed enhancing when there is an involvement of radiative parameter while lower temperature distribution is noted in the absence of the radiative term.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Muhammad Hamid; Muhammad Usman; Yaping Yan; Zhenfu Tian;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A multilayer approach for systemic risk in the insurance sector]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_amafsritis.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_amafsritis.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.810Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, we provide a methodology suitable to identify relevant insurance companies in a systemic risk framework. To this end, we propose a complex network approach where insurers are linked to form a global interconnected system. In particular, we extend the current literature proposing an approach based on a directed weighted multilayer network. The reciprocal influence between insurers is indeed considered in each period and in subsequent periods, calibrating arc weights on the basis of specific risk measures. Hub and authority scores are then used to assess the prominence of a company in spreading and receiving risk from the others.            We identify relevant insurance companies in a systemic risk framework.Insurers are linked in a global interconnected system described by complex networks.We extend existing approaches using a directed and weighted multilayer network.Insurers are selected extending the concept of hub and authority scores.We provide marginal and conditional centralities indicators.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gian Paolo Clemente; Alessandra Cornaro;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos emerges from coexisting homoclinic cycles for a class of 3D piecewise systems]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_cefchcaco3ps.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_cefchcaco3ps.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.810Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accurately detecting a homoclinic cycle and chaos in a concrete system takes a huge challenge. This paper gives a sufficient condition of coexisting homoclinic cycles (degenerate) with respect to a saddle-focus in a class of three-dimensional piecewise systems with two switching manifolds. Furthermore, by constructing the Poincaré map, it is rigorously shown that chaotic behavior is induced by the coexisting cycles without necessary symmetry in the considered system, which is evidently different from the usual dynamics in smooth system theory that a pair of symmetrical homoclinic cycles can generate chaos but the asymmetric ones cannot. It finally provides an example to illustrate the effectiveness of the results established.            Obtain a criterion for accurately detecting coexisting homoclinic cycles (degenerate and non-degenerate) in a class of piecewise systems.Propose existence conditions of chaos, which generalizes the Shilnikov theorem of smooth systems to non-smooth systems.Rigorously prove the coexisting cycles possibly without symmetry can give rise to topological horseshoes, which is in sharp contrast with the smooth systems that need symmetrical homoclinic cycles to produce chaos.The new findings and theoretical results contribute to better understanding the geometry and generation mechanism of chaotic attractors.The analysis method in this paper is also applicable to a investigation on similar objects caused by other types of coexisting singular cycles in non-smooth dynamical systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kai Lu; Wenjing Xu; Ting Yang; Qiaomin Xiang;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Regarding the shallow water in an ocean via a Whitham-Broer-Kaup-like system: hetero-Bäcklund transformations, bilinear forms and                 M             solitons]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rtswiatbfams.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_rtswiatbfams.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.809Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Considering the water waves, people have investigated many systems. In this paper, what we study is a Whitham-Broer-Kaup-like system for the dispersive long waves in the shallow water in an ocean. With respect to the water-wave horizontal velocity and deviation height from the equilibrium of the water, we construct (A) two branches of the hetero-Bäcklund transformations, from that system to a known constant-coefficient nonlinear dispersive-wave system, (B) two branches of the bilinear forms and (C) two branches of the -soliton solutions, with  as a positive integer. Results rely upon the oceanic shallow-water coefficients in that system.            Whitham-Broer-Kaup-like system for the dispersive long waves in oceanic shallow water.For the velocity of water wave and deviation from the equilibrium position of water.As to the oceanic shallow water, building up (1) two branches of the hetero-Bäcklund transformations,(2) two branches of the bilinear forms and (3) two branches of the -soliton solutions.Results relying on different dispersion/diffusion powers from the oceanic shallow water.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xin-Yi Gao; Yong-Jiang Guo; Wen-Rui Shan;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modified generalized Darboux transformation and solitons for a Lakshmanan-Porsezian-Daniel equation]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mgdtasfale.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_mgdtasfale.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.808Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, a Lakshmanan-Porsezian-Daniel equation, which describes the nonlinear spin excitations in a (1+1)-dimensional isotropic biquadratic Heisenberg ferromagnetic spin chain with the octupole-dipole interaction, is investigated. With respect to the coherent amplitude of the spin deviation operator for the ferromagnetic spin chain in the coherent state, we construct a modified generalized Darboux transformation in which the multiple spectral parameters are involved, and the th-order semirational solutions in the determinant form, where  is a positive integer. Then, we obtain and analyze three types of the semirational solutions: Type-I degenerate soliton solutions which describe the degenerate solitons; Type-II degenerate soliton solutions which describe the interaction among the solitons and degenerate solitons; Type-III degenerate soliton solutions which describe the bound states among a set of the degenerate solitons. Generation conditions of the above semirational solutions are discussed. When the multiple solitons have the equal velocity, bound-state solitons are also constructed. Influence of  on the type-I degenerate solitons are graphically illustrated, where  denotes the strength of the higher-order linear and nonlinear effects in the equation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xi-Hu Wu; Yi-Tian Gao; Xin Yu; Cui-Cui Ding; Liu-Qing Li;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intermittent chimera-like and bi-stable synchronization states in network of distinct Izhikevich neurons]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_icabssinodin.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_icabssinodin.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.808Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The network of nonidentical neurons can display intermittent chimera-like phenomena.Individual dynamics is important to characterize several complex phenomena in the collective network dynamics.The size of the network for nonidentical neurons globally coupled can change the phase synchronization patterns.Phase synchronization hysteresis emerges for coupling strength change.        Phase synchronization phenomena of neuronal networks are one of many features depicted by real networks that can be studied using computational models. Here, we proceed with numerical simulations of a globally connected network composed of non-identical (distinct) Izhikevich neuron model to study clustered phase synchronization. We investigate the case in which, once coupled, there exist two main neuron clusters in the network: one of them is bi-stable, depicting phase-synchronized or unsynchronized states, depending on the initial conditions; and the second one shows just an unsynchronized state. For the set of initial conditions that lead the first cluster to the synchronized regime, we observe a chimera-like pattern of the network. For small networks, the dynamics can also present intermittent chimera-like scenarios. In this context, the mechanism for intermittent chimera states is based on two features: the coexistence of a synchronized cluster with an unsynchronized one; and the capability of one cluster to display bi-stability depending on the signal trait by which it is forced. We conclude with an understanding of intermittent chimera-like dynamics as the limit case where bi-stability is not maintained, which occurs due to the loss of uniformity in the neuron input synaptic currents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel Marghoti; Thiago de Lima Prado; Arturo Cagnato Conte; Fabiano Alan Serafim Ferrari; Sergio Roberto Lopes;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immunization strategies for false information spreading on signed social networks]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_isffisossn.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_isffisossn.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.806Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With high-speed communication and information sharing in social networks, the effective immunity to specific false information would markedly reduce the loss brought by the spreading of false information. To date, most studies only focus on the immunity of positive relationships for information spreading between individuals. However, negative relationships also exist in social networks and might have a strong influence on information spreading. In this study, three strategies of structural immunization and a heuristic strategy are proposed for signed social networks with both positive and negative relationships, which can effectively control the spread of false information by the users with opposing attitudes. After selecting the information spreading model suitable for signed networks, the influence of structural immunization strategies on spreading ranges is explored and shows different phase transitions which indicate that both positive and negative edges play a significant role in immune processes. Then, the results of two evaluation indices showed that the three proposed strategies had better immunity than the state-of-the-art approaches. In addition, to decrease algorithm complexity and achieve better performance, the results of the proposed structural strategies are selected to be the initial values of a heuristic strategy driven by a genetic algorithm. This study contributes to a deeper understanding of the role of negative relationships in information immunity and promotes the application of signed networks in information spreading and control.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ai-Wen Li; Xiao-Ke Xu; Ying Fan;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new ensemble spatio-temporal PM2.5 prediction method based on graph attention recursive networks and reinforcement learning]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_anespparnarl.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_anespparnarl.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.804Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new multi-index driven spatio-temporal PM2.5 prediction model is proposed.GAT is applied to study the spatio-temporal correlation between different sites.The Sarsa algorithm is used to build the ensemble learning model with the strongest ability to adapt to different data.        Inhalable particulate matter with a diameter of less than 2.5 μm spatio-temporal prediction technology is an important tool for environmental governance in urban traffic congestion areas. A new Ensemble Graph Attention Reinforcement Learning Recursive Network is proposed to create a multi-data-driven spatio-temporal prediction method with excellent application value. The modeling process includes three basic steps. In step I, the graph attention network is used to effectively aggregate the spatio-temporal correlation characteristics of the original air pollutant data. In step II, the features extracted from the graph attention network are transferred to the long short-term memory network and the temporal convolutional network and the prediction models are constructed respectively. In step III, the reinforcement learning algorithm effectively analyzes the adaptability of the two different models to the data sets and realizes ensemble based on continuous optimization of weights. By comparing the experimental results of the listed cases, the following points can be summarized: (a) the graph attention network can effectively aggregate the spatio-temporal correlation characteristics of the original data and optimize the performance of the predictor. (b) The reinforcement learning algorithm effectively realizes the integration of several neural networks and improves the comprehensive adaptability and generalization capabilities of the model. (c) The proposed model in this paper has great application potential and value in spatial and temporal prediction and has achieved better performance than the other 25 benchmark models.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jing Tan; Hui Liu; Yanfei Li; Shi Yin; Chengqing Yu;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vector centrality in hypergraphs]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_vcih.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_vcih.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.804Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ranking nodes in a hypergraphCentrality in hypergraphsRelevance of a node in a process        Identifying the most influential nodes in networked systems is of vital importance to optimize their function and control. Several scalar metrics have been proposed to that effect, but the recent shift in focus towards network structures which go beyond a simple collection of dyadic interactions has rendered them void of performance guarantees. We here introduce a new measure of node's centrality, which is no longer a scalar value, but a vector with dimension one lower than the highest order of interaction in a hypergraph. Such a vectorial measure is linked to the eigenvector centrality for networks containing only dyadic interactions, but it has a significant added value in all other situations where interactions occur at higher-orders. In particular, it is able to unveil different roles which may be played by the same node at different orders of interactions – information that is otherwise impossible to retrieve by single scalar measures. We demonstrate the efficacy of our measure with applications to synthetic networks and to three real world hypergraphs, and compare our results with those obtained by applying other scalar measures of centrality proposed in the literature.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Kovalenko; M. Romance; E. Vasilyeva; D. Aleja; R. Criado; D. Musatov; A.M. Raigorodskii; J. Flores; I. Samoylenko; K. Alfaro-Bittner; M. Perc; S. Boccaletti;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extension of dashpot model with elastoplastic deformation and rough surface in impact behavior]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eodmwearsiib.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_eodmwearsiib.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.801Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This investigation proposes a more general dashpot model with elastoplastic deformation and rough surface based on the  in allusion to the rough surface with fractal characteristic Firstly, the rough surface of the contact body is depicted using the  (W-M) function. The entire contact process of a single asperity is divided into the elastic, elastoplastic, and plastic phases, which are assumed to be governed by the  model. The contact stiffness coefficients between two rough surfaces at different contact phases can be derived according to the Ma-Liu model and the size distribution function of the  (M-B) model. Secondly, based on the energy and momentum conservation during impact, the corresponding hysteresis damping factors at different contact phases can be derived. A continuous dashpot m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gengxiang Wang; Matthias G.R. Faes; Fuan Cheng; Tengfei Shi; Peng Gao;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A novel approach for solving linear and nonlinear time-fractional Schrödinger equations]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_anafslantse.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_anafslantse.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.767Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We consider the Schrödinger differential equation with fractional derivatives.We offer a novel combined computational approach by using conformable natural transform and the homotopy perturbation method for extracting analytical and numerical solutions of the time-fractional conformable Schrödinger equation with zero and non-zero trapping potential.We use the Banach fixed point theory to test the uniqueness of the solution, convergence, and error analysis.We demonstrate the numerical simulations.        There is significant literature on Schrödinger differential equation (SDE) solutions, where the fractional derivatives are stated in terms of Caputo derivative (CD). There is hardly any work on analytical and numerical SDE solutions involving conformable fractional derivative (CFD). For the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Muhammad Imran Liaqat; Ali Akgül;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nonlinear, data-driven, ANNs-based approach to culture-led development policies in rural areas: The case of Gjakove and Peć districts, Western Kosovo]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_andaatgapdwk.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_andaatgapdwk.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.767Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We develop a computational approach to the analysis of cultural vibrancy and to the role of the cultural and creative sectors in the socio-economic organization of two districts of Western Kosovo, Gjakove and Peć. Our analysis is built on a geolocalized mapping of the cultural activities and facilities, and on the main socio-economic variables for the two districts, and makes use of innovative data analysis techniques: Theory of Impossible Words (TIW), the Topological Weighted Centroid (TWC), and the AutoCM ANN. We find that the dynamics of cultural vibrancy of the territory is mainly driven by the competing attraction pulls of the nearby countries of Serbia and Albania, that also form the region's main and often conflicting ethnicities, and that such dynamics are likely to further polarize in the future. We also find that the cultural system plays a marginal role in the territory's socio-economic organization. This situation makes a case for a more active role of cultural policy in shaping future local developmental models in rural areas and in acting as an agent of social cohesion.            We analyze the cultural vibrancy of the West Kosovo Region.We analyze the centrality of the cultural system in the regional socio-economy.We make use of TWC and AutoCM computational techniques.We find that the region is likely to become culturally polarized.We make a case for a more proactive role of cultural policy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Massimo Buscema; Guido Ferilli; Christer Gustafsson; Giulia Massini; Pier Luigi Sacco;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptive stochastic resonance based convolutional neural network for image classification]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_asrbcnnfic.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_asrbcnnfic.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.766Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this paper, we exploit the adaptive stochastic resonance effect in the convolutional neural network with threshold activation functions for enabling the back-propagation gradient computation. During training, the injection of noise into the threshold activation function makes it to be differentiable at forward pass, thus exact gradients of the loss function with respect to network parameters including the injected noise level can smoothly propagate at backforward pass. This training method effectively uses the non-zero noise to improve the performance of the designed convolutional neural network. In the testing phase, the differentiable activation function is decoupled into a set of threshold functions driven by mutually independent noise components, which endows a hardware-friendly feature of the designed neural network. Experiments show that the designed low-precision convolutional neural network has a comparable performance with the full-precision one with ReLU activation functions on two benchmark data sets. These results also extend the potential application of adaptive stochastic resonance into the convolutional neural network for image classification.            Exploring adaptive stochastic resonance effect in threshold convolutional neural networksPropagating exact gradients at backforward pass via the noise-smoothed neuronsEnhancing the testing accuracy of the convolutional neural networks by the noise injection]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lingling Duan; Yuhao Ren; Fabing Duan;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstration of unique problems from Soliton solutions to nonlinear Selkov–Schnakenberg system]]></title>
        <id>http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_doupfsstnss.xml</id>
        <link href="http://resolver.scholarsportal.info/resolve/09600779/v162icomplete/nfp_doupfsstnss.xml"/>
        <updated>2022-09-12T00:47:34.765Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article investigates the existence theory, exact solutions, and the unique solutions of physical problems. In this study the well-known Selkov–Schnakenberg system of coupled nonlinear unidirectional PDEs is analyzed. This is a simple chemical reaction system that admits periodic solutions. The existence of the system is extracted by applying contraction and self-mapping conditions. The new families of exact solutions which represent the concentration and chemical reactants in different forms are formulated. The periodic, singular periodic, shock wave, singular wave, and complex solitary-shock, shock-singular, double singular, and periodic-singular solutions are successfully extracted by using the new modified extended direct algebraic (MEDA) technique. Additionally the unique problems with corresponding proposed auxiliary data are discussed. The trends of these solutions are also sketched in different plots.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Muhammad S. Iqbal; Aly R. Seadawy; Muhammad Z. Baber;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Motor and cognitive deficits limit the ability to flexibly modulate spatiotemporal gait features in older adults with mild cognitive impairment [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.09.507368v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.09.507368v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dance-based therapies are an emerging form of movement therapy aiming to improve motor and cognitive function in older adults with mild cognitive impairments (MCIs). Despite promising effects of dance-based therapy on function, it remains unclear how age-related declines in motor and cognitive function influence which movements and rhythms maximize dance therapy efficacy. Here, we evaluated the effects of age and MCI on the ability to accurately modulate spatial (i.e., joint kinematics), temporal (i.e., step timing), and spatiotemporal features of gait to achieve spatial and temporal targets during walking. We developed novel rhythmic movement sequences - nine spatial, nine temporal, and four spatiotemporal - that deviated from typical spatial and temporal features of walking. Healthy young adults (HYA), healthy older adults (HOA), and adults with MCI were trained on each gait modification before performing the modification overground, with kinematic data recorded using wearable sensors. HOA performed spatial (p = 0.010) and spatiotemporal (p = 0.048) gait modifications less accurately than HYA. Individuals with MCI performed spatiotemporal gait modifications less accurately than HOA (p = 0.017). Spatial modifications to the swing phase of gait (p = 0.006, Cohen's d = -1.3), and two- and four-step Duple rhythms during temporal modifications (p  0.9) elicited the largest differences in gait performance in HYA vs. HOA and HOA vs. MCI, respectively. These findings suggest that age-related declines in strength and balance reduce the ability to accurately modulate spatial gait features, while declines in working memory in individuals with MCI may reduce the ability to perform longer temporal gait modification sequences. Differences in performance on rhythmic movement sequences highlight the impacts of motor and cognitive deficits on gait modulation capacity, which may assist therapists in personalizing therapies based on these deficits and provide more sensitive indices to track intervention efficacy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rosenberg, M. C.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Reprogramming T7RNA Polymerase in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Escherichia coli</named-content> Nissle 1917 under Specific <italic toggle="yes">Lac</italic> Operon for Efficient <italic toggle="yes">p</italic>‑Coumaric Acid Production]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00363</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00363"/>
        <updated>2022-09-10T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00363]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sefli Sri Wahyu Effendi and I-Son Ng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying interpretable gene-biomarker associations with functionally informed kernel-based tests in 190,000 exomes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32864-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32864-2"/>
        <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genetic association studies for rare variants suffer from lack of power and thus there is a need for methods to improve rare variant discovery. Here, the authors present functionally informed association tests with increased statistical power to aid discovery and interpretation of rare variants.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Pseudotyping Bacteriophage P2 Tail Fibers to Extend the Host Range for Biomedical Applications]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00629</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00629"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.1c00629]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabitha G. Cunliffe, Alan L. Parker, and Alfonso Jaramillo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gibson Assembly-based direct cloning of plasmid DNA in Lactiplantibacillus plantarum WCSF1 [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.09.507304v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.09.507304v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lactobacilli are gram-positive bacteria that are growing in importance for the healthcare industry and genetically engineering them as living therapeutics is highly sought after. However, progress in this field is hindered since most strains are difficult to genetically manipulate, partly due since their complex and thick cell walls limit our capability to transform them with exogenous DNA. To overcome this, large amounts of DNA (>1 microgram) are normally required to successfully transform these bacteria. An intermediate host, like E. coli, is often used to amplify recombinant DNA to such amounts although this approach poses unwanted drawbacks such as increase in plasmid size, different methylation patterns and limitation of introducing only genes compatible with the intermediate host. In this work, we have developed a direct cloning method based on Gibson assembly and PCR to amplify the DNA to sufficient quantities for successful transformation in L. plantarum WCFS1. This advantage of this method is demonstrated in terms of shorter experimental duration and the possibility to introduce a gene incompatible with E. coli into L. plantarum WCFS1.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Blanch Asensio, M.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FPCountR: Absolute protein quantification using fluorescence measurements [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2021.12.06.471413v3?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2021.12.06.471413v3?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This paper presents a generalisable method for the calibration of fluorescence readings on microplate readers, in order to convert arbitrary fluorescence units into absolute units. FPCountR relies on the generation of bespoke fluorescent protein (FP) calibrants, assays to determine protein concentration and activity, and a corresponding analytical workflow. We systematically characterise the assay protocols for accuracy, sensitivity and simplicity, and describe a novel  ECmax assay that outperforms the others and even enables accurate calibration without requiring the purification of FPs. To obtain cellular protein concentrations, we consider methods for the conversion of optical density to either cell counts or alternatively to cell volumes, as well as examining how cells can interfere with protein counting via fluorescence quenching, which we quantify and correct for the first time. Calibration across different instruments, disparate filter sets and mismatched gains is demonstrated to yield equivalent results. It also reveals that mCherry absorption at 600nm does not confound cell density measurements unless expressed to over 100,000 proteins per cell. FPCountR is presented as pair of open access tools (protocol and R package) to enable the community to use this method, and ultimately to facilitate the quantitative characterisation of synthetic microbial circuits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Csibra, E.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red light-emitting short Mango-based system enables tracking a mycobacterial small noncoding RNA in infected macrophages [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.07.506834v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.07.506834v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Progress in the studies of RNA metabolism and function relies largely on molecular imaging systems, including those comprising a fluorogenic dye and an aptamer-based fluorescence-activating tag. G4 aptamers of Mango family, typically combined with a duplex/hairpin scaffold, activate fluorescence of a green-emitting dye TO1-biotin and hold great promise for intracellular RNA tracking. Here, we report a new Mango-based imaging platform. Its key advantages are tunability of spectral properties and applicability for visualization of small RNA molecules that require minimal tag size. The former advantage is due to an expanded (green-to-red-emitting) palette of TO1-inspired fluorogenic dyes, and the latter is ensured by the truncated duplex scaffold. To illustrate applicability of the improved platform, we tagged Mycobacterium tuberculosis sncRNA with the shortened aptamer-scaffold tag and visualized it in bacteria and bacteria-infected macrophages using the new red light-emitting Mango-activated dye.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bychenko, O. S.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MilkyBase, a database of human milk composition as a function of maternal-, infant- and measurement conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01663-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01663-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement(s) Concentration of biochemical compounds in human milk or/and derived quantities, like their sums or ratios. Technology Type(s) Data mining, by means of Machine Learning and targeted manual literature search within available scientific publications in the internet. Factor Type(s) Georgaphical region • Cohort size • Measurement Method • Various characteristics (including history) of mother, child, breast milk and measurement Sample Characteristic - Organism Human milk Sample Characteristic - Environment Standard birth environment Sample Characteristic - Location Various regions of the world]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrating and formatting biomedical data as pre-calculated knowledge graph embeddings in the Bioteque]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33026-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-33026-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biomedical data is accumulating at a fast pace and integrating it into a unified framework is a major challenge. Here, the authors present a resource that contains pre-calculated biomedical descriptors derived from a very large knowledge graph.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traject3d allows label-free identification of distinct co-occurring phenotypes within 3D culture by live imaging]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32958-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32958-x"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are currently a lack of tools to detect heterogeneity in 3D cultures. Here the authors report Traject3d as a framework to identify heterogeneous states in 3D culture and to understand how these give rise to distinct phenotypes using label-free multi-day time-lapse imaging.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multimodal data integration improves immunotherapy response prediction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43018-022-00417-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43018-022-00417-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immunotherapy has shown great promise in the treatment of patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer. We show that integration of data collected during diagnostic clinical work-up with machine learning has the potential to improve predictions of response to immunotherapy and to identify the patients most likely to benefit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced detection of threat materials by dark-field x-ray imaging combined with deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32402-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32402-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dark-field X-ray imaging is sensitive to the microstructure of a material. Here, the authors combine this with a neural network algorithm to provide efficient material discrimination, e.g., of explosives vs non-threat materials.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting motor symptom fluctuations in Parkinson’s disease with generative adversarial networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-022-00674-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-022-00674-x"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Digital Medicine - Detecting motor symptom fluctuations in Parkinson’s disease with generative adversarial networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrative and comparative single-cell analysis reveals transcriptomic difference between human tumefactive demyelinating lesion and glioma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03900-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03900-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Integrative and comparative single-cell analysis reveals transcriptomic difference between human tumefactive demyelinating lesion and glioma.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genetic and microenvironmental intra-tumor heterogeneity impacts colorectal cancer evolution and metastatic development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03884-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03884-x"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The genetic and microenvironmental heterogeneity of colorectal cancer is analyzed using a prospective biobank of primary and metastatic tumor tissues to highlight features of intra-tumoral heterogeneity that favor tumor progression and metastasis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Black Hole’s Orbiting Ring of Light Could Encrypt Its Inner Secrets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118623</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/black-holes-ring-of-light-could-encrypt-its-inner-secrets-20220908/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T14:14:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physicists have discovered that the ring of photons orbiting a black hole exhibits a special kind of symmetry, hinting at a deeper meaning.            
The post A Black Hole’s Orbiting Ring of Light Could Encrypt Its Inner Secrets first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Lewton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-parametric tests for serial dependence in time series based on asymptotic implementations of ordinal-pattern statistics]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0094943?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0094943?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T08:05:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Ordinal patterns can be used to construct non-parametric hypothesis tests that aim to discover (possibly non-linear) serial dependence in a real-valued time series. We derive the asymptotic distribution of the vector of sample frequencies of ordinal patterns and that of various corresponding tests statistics such that the targeted tests for serial dependence are easily implemented based on asymptotic approximations. Simulations are used to check the finite-sample performance of these tests as well as their power properties with respect to various alternative scenarios. The application and interpretation of the tests in practice are illustrated by an environmental data example.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian H. Weiß</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the origin of chaotic attractors with two zero Lyapunov exponents in a system of five biharmonically coupled phase oscillators]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098163?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098163?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
We study chaotic dynamics in a system of four differential equations describing the interaction of five identical phase oscillators coupled via biharmonic function. We show that this system exhibits strange spiral attractors (Shilnikov attractors) with two zero (indistinguishable from zero in numerics) Lyapunov exponents in a wide region of the parameter space. We explain this phenomenon by means of bifurcation analysis of a three-dimensional Poincaré map for the system under consideration. We show that chaotic dynamics develop here near a codimension three bifurcation, when a periodic orbit (fixed point of the Poincaré map) has the triplet of multipliers [math]. As it is known, the flow normal form for such bifurcation is the well-known three-dimensional Arneodó–Coullet–Spiegel–Tresser (ACST) system, which exhibits spiral attractors. According to this, we conclude that the additional zero Lyapunov exponent for orbits in the observed attractors appears due to the fact that the corresponding three-dimensional Poincaré map is very close to the time-shift map of the ACST-system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny A. Grines</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting bifurcations in dynamical systems with CROCKER plots]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0102421?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0102421?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Existing tools for bifurcation detection from signals of dynamical systems typically are either limited to a special class of systems or they require carefully chosen input parameters and a significant expertise to interpret the results. Therefore, we describe an alternative method based on persistent homology—a tool from topological data analysis—that utilizes Betti numbers and CROCKER plots. Betti numbers are topological invariants of topological spaces, while the CROCKER plot is a coarsened but easy to visualize data representation of a one-parameter varying family of persistence barcodes. The specific bifurcations we investigate are transitions from periodic to chaotic behavior or vice versa in a one-parameter collection of differential equations. We validate our methods using numerical experiments on ten dynamical systems and contrast the results with existing tools that use the maximum Lyapunov exponent. We further prove the relationship between the Wasserstein distance to the empty diagram and the norm of the Betti vector, which shows that an even more simplified version of the information has the potential to provide insight into the bifurcation parameter. The results show that our approach reveals more information about the shape of the periodic attractor than standard tools, and it has more favorable computational time in comparison with the Rösenstein algorithm for computing the maximum Lyapunov exponent.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>İsmail Güzel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-subject emotion recognition using visibility graph and genetic algorithm-based convolution neural network]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098454?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0098454?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
An efficient emotion recognition model is an important research branch in electroencephalogram (EEG)-based brain–computer interfaces. However, the input of the emotion recognition model is often a whole set of EEG channels obtained by electrodes placed on subjects. The unnecessary information produced by redundant channels affects the recognition rate and depletes computing resources, thereby hindering the practical applications of emotion recognition. In this work, we aim to optimize the input of EEG channels using a visibility graph (VG) and genetic algorithm-based convolutional neural network (GA-CNN). First, we design an experiment to evoke three types of emotion states using movies and collect the multi-channel EEG signals of each subject under different emotion states. Then, we construct VGs for each EEG channel and derive nonlinear features representing each EEG channel. We employ the genetic algorithm (GA) to find the optimal subset of EEG channels for emotion recognition and use the recognition results of the CNN as fitness values. The experimental results show that the recognition performance of the proposed method using a subset of EEG channels is superior to that of the CNN using all channels for each subject. Last, based on the subset of EEG channels searched by the GA-CNN, we perform cross-subject emotion recognition tasks employing leave-one-subject-out cross-validation. These results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method in recognizing emotion states using fewer EEG channels and further enrich the methods of EEG classification using nonlinear features.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qing Cai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry breaking of solitons in the PT-symmetric nonlinear Schrödinger equation with the cubic–quintic competing saturable nonlinearity]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0091738?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0091738?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The symmetry breaking of solitons in the nonlinear Schrödinger equation with cubic–quintic competing nonlinearity and parity-time symmetric potential is studied. At first, a new asymmetric branch separates from the fundamental symmetric soliton at the first power critical point, and then, the asymmetric branch passes through the branch of the fundamental symmetric soliton and finally merges into the branch of the fundamental symmetric soliton at the second power critical point, while the power of the soliton increases. This leads to the symmetry breaking and double-loop bifurcation of fundamental symmetric solitons. From the power-propagation constant curves of solitons, symmetric fundamental and tripole solitons, asymmetric solitons can also exist. The stability of symmetric fundamental solitons, asymmetric solitons, and symmetric tripole solitons is discussed by the linear stability analysis and direct simulation. Results indicate that symmetric fundamental solitons and symmetric tripole solitons tend to be stable with the increase in the soliton power. Asymmetric solitons are unstable in both high and low power regions. Moreover, with the increase in saturable nonlinearity, the stability region of fundamental symmetric solitons and symmetric tripole solitons becomes wider.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wen-Bo Bo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dipole and quadrupole nonparaxial solitary waves]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096099?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096099?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
The cubic nonlinear Helmholtz equation with third and fourth order dispersion and non-Kerr nonlinearity, such as the self steepening and the self frequency shift, is considered. This model describes nonparaxial ultrashort pulse propagation in an optical medium in the presence of spatial dispersion originating from the failure of slowly varying envelope approximation. We show that this system admits periodic (elliptic) solitary waves with a dipole structure within a period and also a transition from a dipole to quadrupole structure within a period depending on the value of the modulus parameter of a Jacobi elliptic function. The parametric conditions to be satisfied for the existence of these solutions are given. The effect of the nonparaxial parameter on physical quantities, such as amplitude, pulse width, and speed of the solitary waves, is examined. It is found that by adjusting the nonparaxial parameter, the speed of solitary waves can be decelerated. The stability and robustness of the solitary waves are discussed numerically.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Naresh Saha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When costly migration helps to improve cooperation]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0100772?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0100772?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Motion is a typical reaction among animals and humans trying to reach better conditions in a changing world. This aspect has been studied intensively in social dilemmas where competing players’ individual and collective interests are in conflict. Starting from the traditional public goods game model, where players are locally fixed and unconditional cooperators or defectors are present, we introduce two additional strategies through which agents can change their positions of dependence on the local cooperation level. More importantly, these so-called sophisticated players should bear an extra cost to maintain their permanent capacity to evaluate their neighborhood and react accordingly. Hence, four strategies compete, and the most successful one can be imitated by its neighbors. Crucially, the introduction of costly movement has a highly biased consequence on the competing main strategies. In the majority of parameter space, it is harmful to defectors and provides a significantly higher cooperation level when the population is rare. At an intermediate population density, which would be otherwise optimal for a system of immobile players, the presence of mobile actors could be detrimental if the interaction pattern changes slightly, thereby blocking the optimal percolation of information flow. In this parameter space, sophisticated cooperators can also show the co-called Moor effect by first avoiding the harmful vicinity of defectors; they subsequently transform into an immobile cooperator state. Hence, paradoxically, the additional cost of movement could be advantageous to reach a higher general income, especially for a rare population when subgroups would be isolated otherwise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hsuan-Wei Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry breaking yields chimeras in two small populations of Kuramoto-type oscillators]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0088465?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0088465?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:47:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Despite their simplicity, networks of coupled phase oscillators can give rise to intriguing collective dynamical phenomena. However, the symmetries of globally and identically coupled identical units do not allow solutions where distinct oscillators are frequency-unlocked—a necessary condition for the emergence of chimeras. Thus, forced symmetry breaking is necessary to observe chimera-type solutions. Here, we consider the bifurcations that arise when full permutational symmetry is broken for the network to consist of coupled populations. We consider the smallest possible network composed of four phase oscillators and elucidate the phase space structure, (partial) integrability for some parameter values, and how the bifurcations away from full symmetry lead to frequency-unlocked weak chimera solutions. Since such solutions wind around a torus they must arise in a global bifurcation scenario. Moreover, periodic weak chimeras undergo a period-doubling cascade leading to chaos. The resulting chaotic dynamics with distinct frequencies do not rely on amplitude variation and arise in the smallest networks that support chaos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oleksandr Burylko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Delayed In Vivo Encapsulation of Enzymes Alters the Catalytic Activity of Virus-Like Particle Nanoreactors]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00636</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00636"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.1c00636]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dustin P. Patterson, Christy Hjorth, Andrea Hernandez Irias, Nathasha Hewagama, and Jessica Bird</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Base Editing for Reprogramming Cyanobacterium Synechococcus elongatus [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.05.506134v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.05.506134v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global climate change demands carbon-negative innovations to reduce the concentration of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2). Cyanobacteria can fix CO2 from the atmosphere and can be genetically reprogrammed for the production of biofuels, chemicals and food products, making an ideal microbial chassis for carbon-negative biotechnology. However, the progress seems to be slowed down due to the lagging-behind synthetic biology toolkits, especially the CRISPR-Cas-based genome-editing tools. As such, we developed a base-editing tool based on the CRISPR-Cas system and deamination for cyanobacterium Synechococcus elongatus. We achieved efficient and precise genome editing at a single-nucleotide resolution, and identified the pure population of edited cells at the first round of selection without extra segregation. By using the base-editing tool, we successfully manipulated the glycogen metabolic pathway via the introduction of premature STOP codons to inactivate the corresponding genes. We demonstrated multiplex base editing by editing two genes at once, obtaining a nearly two-fold increase in the glycogen content. We present here the first report of base editing in the phylum of cyanobacteria, and a paradigm for applying CRISPR-Cas systems in bacteria. We believe that this work will accelerate the synthetic biology of cyanobacteria and drive more innovations to alleviate global climate change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wang, S.-Y.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Datasets of in vitro clonogenic assays showing low dose hyper-radiosensitivity and induced radioresistance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01653-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01653-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement(s) surviving fraction of cells Technology Type(s) optical microscopy Factor Type(s) absorbed dose Sample Characteristic - Organism Homo sapiens • Chinese hamster • Rattus sp. Sample Characteristic - Environment cell culture]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopes are coming for your job]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01566-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01566-4"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advances in microscopy, computer vision and open source software are converging to usher in a new era of microscopes that control themselves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From biomedical cloud platforms to microservices: next steps in FAIR data and analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01619-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01619-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The biomedical research community is investing heavily in biomedical cloud platforms. Cloud computing holds great promise for addressing challenges with big data and ensuring reproducibility in biology. However, despite their advantages, cloud platforms in and of themselves do not automatically support FAIRness. The global push to develop biomedical cloud platforms has led to new challenges, including platform lock-in, difficulty integrating across platforms, and duplicated effort for both users and developers. Here, we argue that these difficulties are systemic and emerge from incentives that encourage development effort on self-sufficient platforms and data repositories instead of interoperable microservices. We argue that many of these issues would be alleviated by prioritizing microservices and access to modular data in smaller chunks or summarized form. We propose that emphasizing modularity and interoperability would lead to a more powerful Unix-like ecosystem of web services for biomedical analysis and data retrieval. We challenge funders, developers, and researchers to support a vision to improve interoperability through microservices as the next generation of cloud-based bioinformatics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Regulation associated modules reflect 3D genome modularity associated with chromatin activity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32911-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32911-y"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here the authors report histone modifications show a modular pattern referred to as ‘regulation associated modules’ (RAMs) that reflect the spatial modularity of chromatin. They find enhancer-promoter interactions and extrachromosomal DNAs (ecDNAs) occur more often within the same RAMs than within the same TADs, indicating stronger insulation of the RAM boundaries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data-driven causal model discovery and personalized prediction in Alzheimer's disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-022-00632-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-022-00632-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Digital Medicine - Data-driven causal model discovery and personalized prediction in Alzheimer's disease]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The impact of repeated rapid test strategies on the effectiveness of at-home antiviral treatments for SARS-CoV-2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32640-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32640-2"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Antiviral treatments for SARS-CoV-2 infection are only beneficial when used early in infection, so early case detection is important. Here, the authors assess the frequency of testing needed to achieve population-level benefits and demonstrate the importance of high coverage and short delays from test to treatment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of lipid flux to advance translational research: evolution of classic methods to the future of precision health]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s12276-022-00838-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s12276-022-00838-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Personalized tracking of how lipid (fat) metabolism changes over time could lead to improvements in the diagnosis and treatment of several diseases. Elizabeth Parks and colleagues from the University of Missouri, Columbia, USA, discuss the ways in which researchers use stable isotope labeling to monitor the kinetics of fatty acids and other lipids in the body. Usually, lipid quantities are measured only at a single timepoint, however the tracking of lipid turnover over time provides further diagnostic information. Aided by new techniques such as high-throughput mass spectrometry and machine learning, researchers are now able to continuously map total lipid contents in individual patients. The transition of measurements of lipid flux from the research laboratory to the doctor’s office will likely play a role in a new era of precision medicine.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Never-homozygous genetic variants in healthy populations are potential recessive disease candidates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41525-022-00322-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41525-022-00322-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Genomic Medicine - Never-homozygous genetic variants in healthy populations are potential recessive disease candidates]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacogenomics polygenic risk score for drug response prediction using PRS-PGx methods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32407-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32407-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To try to predict an individual’s drug response using genetic data, most studies have used traditional polygenic risk score (PRS) methods. Here, the authors develop a pharmacogenomics-specific PRS method, which can improve drug response prediction and patient stratification in pharmacogenomics studies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast intratumor heterogeneity inference from single-cell sequencing data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00298-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00298-x"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A computational method is introduced for mutational intratumor heterogeneity inference from noisy genotype matrices derived from single-cell sequencing data. The proposed method is shown to be accurate and faster than available alternatives.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model-informed experimental design recommendations for distinguishing intrinsic and acquired targeted therapeutic resistance in head and neck cancer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41540-022-00244-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41540-022-00244-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Systems Biology and Applications - Model-informed experimental design recommendations for distinguishing intrinsic and acquired targeted therapeutic resistance in head and neck cancer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying patterns in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression from sparse longitudinal data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00299-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00299-w"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A machine learning approach is presented to identify dominant patterns in disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), Alzheimer’s disease and Parkinson’s disease. The nonlinearity of ALS progression has important clinical implications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid metagenome assemblies link carbohydrate structure with function in the human gut microbiome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03865-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03865-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Longitudinal hybrid metagenomic analyses of a human stool sample reveal compositional and functional variation in response to six structurally-distinct carbohydrates, providing insight into how gut bacteria utilize various carbohydrate sources.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta-analysis reveals weak but pervasive plasticity in insect thermal limits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32953-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32953-2"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ability of organisms to acclimate to high temperatures is increasingly put to test by climate change. This global meta-analysis shows that plasticity of thermal limits in insects is widespread but unlikely to keep pace with climate change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterisation of HOIP RBR E3 ligase conformational dynamics using integrative modelling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18890-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18890-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Characterisation of HOIP RBR E3 ligase conformational dynamics using integrative modelling]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explainable artificial intelligence through graph theory by generalized social network analysis-based classifier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19419-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19419-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Explainable artificial intelligence through graph theory by generalized social network analysis-based classifier]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Publisher Correction: Standardized excitable elements for scalable engineering of far-from-equilibrium chemical networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01058-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01058-0"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature Chemistry - Publisher Correction: Standardized excitable elements for scalable engineering of far-from-equilibrium chemical networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Good Memory or a Bad One? One Brain Molecule Decides.]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118573</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/a-good-memory-or-a-bad-one-one-brain-molecule-decides-20220907/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T14:02:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the brain encodes memories as positive or negative, one molecule determines which way they will go.            
The post A Good Memory or a Bad One? One Brain Molecule Decides. first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yasemin Saplakoglu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Systematic Epigenome Editing Captures the Context-dependent Instructive Function of Chromatin Modifications [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.04.506519v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.04.506519v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chromatin modifications are linked with regulating patterns of gene expression, but their causal role and context-dependent impact on transcription remains unresolved. Here, we develop a modular epigenome editing platform that programmes nine key chromatin modifications - or combinations thereof - to precise loci in living cells. We couple this with single-cell readouts to systematically quantitate the magnitude and heterogeneity of transcriptional responses elicited by each specific chromatin modification. Amongst these, we show installing H3K4me3 at promoters causally instructs transcription activation by hierarchically remodeling the chromatin landscape. We further dissect how DNA sequence motifs influence the transcriptional impact of chromatin marks, identifying switch-like and attenuative effects within distinct cis contexts. Finally, we examine the interplay of combinatorial modifications, revealing co-targeted H3K27me3 and H2AK119ub maximise silencing penetrance across single-cells. Our precision perturbation strategy unveils the causal principles of how chromatin modification(s) influence transcription, and dissects how quantitative responses are calibrated by contextual interactions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Policarpi, C.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple, low-cost production of DNA MS2 virus-like particles as molecular diagnostic controls [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.04.506540v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.04.506540v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Suitable controls are integral for the validation and continued quality assurance of diagnostic workflows. Plasmids, DNA or in vitro transcribed RNA are often used to validate novel diagnostic workflows, however, they are poorly representative of clinical samples. RNA phage virus-like particles packaged with exogenous RNA have been used in clinical diagnostics as workflow controls, serving as surrogates for infectious viral particles. Comparable controls for DNA viruses are more challenging to produce, with analogous DNA phages being infectious and packaging of DNA within RNA phages requiring complex purification procedures and expensive chemical linkers. We present a simple and inexpensive method to produce MS2 virus-like particles, packaged with DNA, that makes use of affinity chromatography for purification and enzymatic production of exogenous DNA suitable for packaging. The produced virus-like particles were packaged with Hepatitis B Virus DNA and were then quantified using droplet digital PCR and calibrated against the WHO international standard using a commercial assay in an accredited clinical laboratory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Crone, M. A.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A machine learning technique for identifying DNA enhancer regions utilizing CIS-regulatory element patterns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19099-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19099-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A machine learning technique for identifying DNA enhancer regions utilizing CIS-regulatory element patterns]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving ascertainment of suicidal ideation and suicide attempt with natural language processing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19358-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19358-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Improving ascertainment of suicidal ideation and suicide attempt with natural language processing]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Establishment and evaluation of a risk-prediction model for hypertension in elderly patients with NAFLD from a health management perspective]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18718-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-18718-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Establishment and evaluation of a risk-prediction model for hypertension in elderly patients with NAFLD from a health management perspective]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TRFs and tiRNAs sequence in acute rejection for vascularized composite allotransplantation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01577-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-022-01577-y"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement(s) gene expression Technology Type(s) RNA sequence Factor Type(s) RNA Sample Characteristic - Organism rn6 Sample Characteristic - Location China]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning-based reconstruction on cardiac CT yields distinct radiomic features compared to iterative and filtered back projection reconstructions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19546-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-19546-1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Deep learning-based reconstruction on cardiac CT yields distinct radiomic features compared to iterative and filtered back projection reconstructions]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational biology and bioinformatics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Shannon Entropy Imposes Fundamental Limits on Communication]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118556</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-claude-shannons-concept-of-entropy-quantifies-information-20220906/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T14:09:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What’s a message, really? Claude Shannon recognized that the elemental ingredient is surprise.            
The post How Shannon Entropy Imposes Fundamental Limits on Communication first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Hartnett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analyzing the potential of AlphaFold in drug discovery]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/alphafold-potential-protein-drug-0906</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/alphafold-potential-protein-drug-0906"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study finds computer models that predict molecular interactions need improvement before they can help identify drug mechanisms of action.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anne Trafton | MIT News Office</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Modular Use of the Uniquely Small Ring A of Mersacidin Generates the Smallest Ribosomally Produced Lanthipeptide]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00343</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00343"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00343]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakob H. Viel and Oscar P. Kuipers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Development of Base Editors for Simultaneously Editing Multiple Loci in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Lactococcus lactis</named-content>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00561</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.1c00561"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.1c00561]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kairen Tian, Xia Hong, Manman Guo, Yanni Li, Hao Wu, Qinggele Caiyin, and Jianjun Qiao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracking the order of transcriptional events in living cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01610-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-022-01610-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers describe Retro-Cascorder, a tool that employs prokaryotic retrons and CRISPR integrases to write transcriptional events into the genome of Escherichia coli.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of an Escherichia coli strain growing on methanol via the ribulose monophosphate cycle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32744-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32744-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using one carbon compounds as feedstock is a promising approach in abating climate change. Here, the authors report the conversion of E. coli into a synthetic methylotroph that assimilates methanol via the ribulose monophosphate cycle and a set of distinctive mutations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MVsim is a toolset for quantifying and designing multivalent interactions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32496-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32496-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arising through multiple binding elements, multivalency can specify the avidity, duration, cooperativity, and selectivity of biomolecular interactions, but quantitative prediction and design of these properties has remained challenging. Here the authors enable facile analysis and engineering of multivalent binding by developing MVsim, a simulator that incorporates biochemical and biophysical parameters of interacting molecules and is accessible through a graphical user interface.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signal processing and generation of bioactive nitric oxide in a model prototissue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32941-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32941-6"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A challenge for synthetic biology is the design and construction of prototissue. Here, the authors spatially segregate layers of enzyme-decorated coacervate protocells as a model prototissue capable of chemical signal processing and modulating outputs of nitric oxide to inhibit blood clot formation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine-Learning Prospects for Detecting Selection Signatures Using Population Genomics Data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0447?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0447?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 943-960, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harshit Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Integer Linear Programming Approach for Scaffolding Based on Exemplar Breakpoint Distance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0399?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0399?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 961-973, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-kung Shieh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Design of Synthetic DNA Sequences Without Unwanted Binding Sites]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0417?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0417?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 974-986, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zehavit Leibovich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RDscan: A New Method for Improving Germline and Somatic Variant Calling Based on Read Depth Distribution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0269?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0269?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 987-1000, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sunho Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[kmer2vec: A Novel Method for Comparing DNA Sequences by word2vec Embedding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0536?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0536?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1001-1021, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruohan Ren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing Rewards Undermines Coordinated Hunting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0549?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0549?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1022-1030, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minglu Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-Organ Transcriptomic Comparison Reveals Universal Factors During Maturation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0349?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0349?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1031-1044, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandeep Kambhampati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harnessing Fuzzy Rule Based System for Screening Major Histocompatibility Complex Class I Peptide Epitopes from the Whole Proteome: An Implementation on the Proteome of Leishmania donovani]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0464?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2021.0464?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Volume 29, Issue 9, Page 1045-1058, September 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saravanan Vijayakumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synthetic genotype networks [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.01.506159v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.01.506159v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genotype networks are sets of genotypes connected by small mutational changes that share the same phenotype. They facilitate evolutionary innovation by enabling the exploration of different neighborhoods in genotype space. Genotype networks, first suggested by theoretical models, have been empirically confirmed for proteins and RNAs. Comparative studies also support their existence for gene regulatory networks (GRNs), but direct experimental evidence is lacking. Here, we report the construction of three interconnected genotype networks of synthetic GRNs producing three distinct gene expression phenotypes in Escherichia coli. These genotype networks, composed of over twenty different synthetic GRNs, provide robustness in face of mutations while enabling transitions to innovative phenotypes. Through realistic mathematical modeling, we quantify robustness and evolvability for the complete genotype-phenotype map and link these features mechanistically to GRN motifs. Our work thereby exemplifies how GRN evolution along genotype networks might be driving evolutionary innovation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Santos-Moreno, J.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A modular XNAzyme cleaves long, structured RNAs under physiological conditions and enables allele-specific gene silencing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01021-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41557-022-01021-z"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oligonucleotide catalysts such as ribozymes and DNAzymes can cleave RNA efficiently and specifically but are typically dependent on high concentrations of divalent cations, limiting their biological applications. A modular XNAzyme catalyst composed of 2′-deoxy-2′-fluoro-β-d-arabino nucleic acid (FANA) has now been developed that can cleave long (>5 kb), highly structured mRNAs under physiological conditions and enables allele-specific catalytic RNA knockdown inside cells.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dissecting aneuploidy phenotypes by constructing Sc2.0 chromosome VII and SCRaMbLEing synthetic disomic yeast [NEW RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.01.506252v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.09.01.506252v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aneuploidy compromises genomic stability, often leading to embryo inviability, and is frequently associated with tumorigenesis and aging. Different aneuploid chromosome stoichiometries lead to distinct transcriptomic and phenotypic changes, making it helpful to study aneuploidy in tightly controlled genetic backgrounds. By deploying the engineered SCRaMbLE system to the newly synthesized Sc2.0 megabase chromosome VII (synVII), we constructed a synthetic disomic yeast and screened hundreds of SCRaMbLEd derivatives with diverse chromosomal rearrangements. Phenotypic characterization and multi-omics analysis revealed that fitness defects associated with aneuploidy could be restored by i) removing most of the chromosome content, or ii) modifying specific regions in the duplicated chromosome. These findings indicate that both chromosome copy number and chromosomal regions contribute to the aneuploidy-related phenotypes, and the synthetic yeast resource opens new paradigms in studying aneuploidy.

In briefUse of SCRaMbLE and newly synthesized Mb-scale Sc2.0 chromosome VII enables insights into genotype/phenotype relationships associated with aneuploidy

HighlightsO_LIDe novo design and synthesis of a Mb-scale synthetic yeast chromosome VII, carrying 11.8% sequence modifications and representing nearly 10% of the yeast genome.
C_LIO_LIA disomic yeast (n + synVII) is constructed for dissecting the aneuploidy phenotype
C_LIO_LISCRaMbLE enables systematic exploration of regions causing aneuploidy phenotypes
C_LIO_LIChromosomal copy number and content both contribute to aneuploidy phenotypes
C_LIO_LIA 20 Kb deletion on the right arm of synVII leads to fitness improvement linked to up-regulation of protein synthesis
C_LI]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shen, Y.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In vitro selection of Engineered Transcriptional Repressors for targeted epigenetic silencing and initial evaluation of their specificity profile [CONFIRMATORY RESULTS]]]></title>
        <id>http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.08.30.505942v1?rss=1</id>
        <link href="http://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2022.08.30.505942v1?rss=1"/>
        <updated>2022-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gene inactivation is instrumental to study gene function and represents a promising strategy for the treatment of a broad range of diseases. Among traditional technologies, RNA interference suffers from partial target abrogation and requirement for life-long treatments. On the other hand, artificial nucleases can impose stable gene inactivation through induction of DNA Double Strand Breaks, but recent studies are questioning the safety of this approach. Targeted epigenetic editing via Engineered Transcriptional Repressors (ETRs) may represent a solution, as a single administration of specific ETRs combinations can lead to durable silencing without DNA breaks induction. ETRs are proteins containing a programmable DNA Binding Domain (DBD) and effectors from naturally occurring transcriptional repressors. Specifically, a combination of three ETRs equipped with the KRAB domain of human ZNF10, the catalytic domain of human DNMT3A and human DNMT3Lwas shown to induce heritable repressive epigenetic states on the ETR-target gene. The hit-and-run nature of this platform, the lack of impact on the DNA sequence of the target, and the possibility to revert on-demand the repressive state by DNA demethylation, make epigenetic silencing a game-changing tool. A critical step is the identification of the proper position on the target gene where to tether the ETRs in order to maximize on target and minimizing off-target silencing. Performing this step in the final ex vivo or in vivo preclinical setting can be cumbersome. Taking CRISPR-Cas9 system as a paradigmatic DBD for ETRs, here we describe a protocol consisting in the in vitro screen of gRNAs coupled to the triple ETRs combination for efficient on-target silencing, followed by evaluation of the genome-wide specificity profile of top hits. This allows to reduce the initial repertoire of candidate gRNAs to a short list of promising ones, whose complexity is suitable for their final evaluation in the therapeutically relevant setting of interest.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Migliara, A.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expanding the terpene biosynthetic code with non-canonical 16 carbon atom building blocks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32921-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32921-w"/>
        <updated>2022-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Establishing methods to access the chemical space that lies beyond canonical terpenoid biosynthesis will increase the applications of isoprenoids. Here, the authors reconstruct the modular structure of terpene biosynthesis on 16-carbon backbones by engineered yeast and synthesize 28 different unique terpenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action potential and chaos near the edge of chaos in memristive circuits]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097075?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0097075?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T09:53:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Memristor-based neuromorphic systems have a neuro-bionic function, which is critical for possibly overcoming Moore's law limitation and the von Neumann bottleneck problem. To explore neural behaviors and complexity mechanisms in memristive circuits, this paper proposes an N-type locally active memristor, based on which a third-order memristive circuit is constructed. Theoretical analysis shows that the memristive circuit can exhibit not only various action potentials but also self-sustained oscillation and chaos. Based on Chua's theory of local activity, this paper finds that the neural behaviors and chaos emerge near the edge of chaos through subcritical Hopf bifurcation, in which the small unstable limit cycle is depicted by the dividing line between the attraction basin of the large stable limit cycle and the attraction basin of the stable equilibrium point. Furthermore, an analog circuit is designed to imitate the action potentials and chaos, and the simulation results are in agreement with the theoretical analysis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiajie Ying</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effects of infection fatality ratio and social contact matrices on vaccine prioritization strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096532?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent</id>
        <link href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0096532?af=R&amp;feed=most-recent"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T09:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, Volume 32, Issue 9, September 2022. 
Effective strategies of vaccine prioritization are essential to mitigate the impacts of severe infectious diseases. We investigate the role of infection fatality ratio (IFR) and social contact matrices on vaccination prioritization using a compartmental epidemic model fueled by real-world data of different diseases and countries. Our study confirms that massive and early vaccination is extremely effective to reduce the disease fatality if the contagion is mitigated, but the effectiveness is increasingly reduced as vaccination beginning delays in an uncontrolled epidemiological scenario. The optimal and least effective prioritization strategies depend non-linearly on epidemiological variables. Regions of the epidemiological parameter space, in which prioritizing the most vulnerable population is more effective than the most contagious individuals, depend strongly on the IFR age profile being, for example, substantially broader for COVID-19 in comparison with seasonal influenza. Demographics and social contact matrices deform the phase diagrams but do not alter their qualitative shapes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arthur Schulenburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A visualization reporter system for characterizing antibiotic biosynthetic gene clusters expression with high-sensitivity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03832-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03832-9"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quorum sensing based visualization reporter system is presented for the characterization of promoters in Gram-positive bacteria, utilizing violacein production, especially for use in the identification of secondary metabolites.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automated model-predictive design of synthetic promoters to control transcriptional profiles in bacteria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32829-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32829-5"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transcription rates are regulated by the interactions between RNA polymerase, sigma factor, and promoter DNA sequences in bacteria. Here the authors combine massively parallel experiments & machine learning to develop a predictive biophysical model of transcription, validated across 22132 bacterial promoters, and apply it to the design and debugging of genetic circuits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatiotemporal control of signal-driven enzymatic reaction in artificial cell-like polymersomes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32889-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32889-7"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have been trying to mimick the cellular spatiotemporal control in normal cells with different approaches. Here, the authors present semi-permeable polymersomes comprising of amphiphilic triblock copolymers to achieve external signal-driven complex coacervation and biophysical reconstitution of cytoskeleton.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webb Space Telescope Snaps Its First Photo of an Exoplanet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118504</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/webb-space-telescope-snaps-its-first-photo-of-an-exoplanet-20220901/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T14:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The grainy image of a “super-Jupiter” is a sign of what’s to come as the telescope’s exoplanet observations ramp up.            
The post Webb Space Telescope Snaps Its First Photo of an Exoplanet first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan O'Callaghan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quartet Based Gene Tree Imputation Using Deep Learning Improves Phylogenomic Analyses Despite Missing Data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0212?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0212?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sazan Mahbub</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inconsistency of Triplet-Based and Quartet-Based Species Tree Estimation under Intralocus Recombination]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0265?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0265?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Hill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Genome Editing by CRISPR/Cas12 Recognizing AT-Rich PAMs in <italic toggle="yes">Shewanella oneidensis</italic> MR‑1]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00208</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00208"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00208]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yaru Chen, Meijie Cheng, Xueru Feng, Xiaolong Niu, Hao Song, and Yingxiu Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Horizontal gene transfer enables programmable gene stability in synthetic microbiota]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41589-022-01114-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41589-022-01114-3"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic redundancy by horizontal gene transfer stabilizes gene abundances amidst compositional fluctuations in microbial communities, which suggests a means to program gene stability of complex microbiota.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Isaac Newton Discovered the Binomial Power Series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=118388</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-isaac-newton-discovered-the-binomial-power-series-20220831/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-31T05:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking questions and chasing patterns led Newton to find the connection between curves and infinite sums.             
The post How Isaac Newton Discovered the Binomial Power Series first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Strogatz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] GB_SynP: A Modular dCas9-Regulated Synthetic Promoter Collection for Fine-Tuned Recombinant Gene Expression in Plants]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00238</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00238"/>
        <updated>2022-08-31T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00238]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Moreno-Giménez, Sara Selma, Camilo Calvache, and Diego Orzáez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] A Network Approach to Genetic Circuit Designs]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00255</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00255"/>
        <updated>2022-08-31T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00255]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Crowther, Anil Wipat, and Ángel Goñi-Moreno</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] An Easy-to-Use Plasmid Toolset for Efficient Generation and Benchmarking of Synthetic Small RNAs in Bacteria]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00164</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00164"/>
        <updated>2022-08-31T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00164]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tania S. Köbel, Rafael Melo Palhares, Christin Fromm, Witold Szymanski, Georgia Angelidou, Timo Glatter, Jens Georg, Bork A. Berghoff, and Daniel Schindler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homodimerized cytoplasmic domain of PD-L1 regulates its complex glycosylation in living cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03845-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-022-03845-4"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Membrane-anchored PD-L1 homodimerizes in cells. N-glycosylation of PD-L1 regulates its homodimerization. The formation of PD-L1 homodimers further regulates their glycan processing, localization to the plasma membrane, and binding to PD-1.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlling gene expression with deep generative design of regulatory DNA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32818-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32818-8"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design of de novo synthetic regulatory DNA is a promising avenue to control gene expression in biotechnology and medicine. Here the authors present EspressionGAN, a generative adversarial network that uses genomic and transcriptomic data to generate regulatory sequences.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reconstructing Kinetic Models for Dynamical Studies of Metabolism using Generative Adversarial Networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00519-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-022-00519-y"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kinetic models of metabolism capture time-dependent behaviour of cellular states and provide valuable insights into cellular physiology, but, due to the lack of experimental data, traditional kinetic modelling can be unreliable and computationally inefficient. A generative framework based on deep learning called REKINDLE can efficiently parameterize large-scale kinetic models, enabling new opportunities to study cellular metabolic behaviour.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nonlinear dynamics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopy technique reveals hidden nanostructures in cells and tissues]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/expansion-revealing-microscopy-cells-0829</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/expansion-revealing-microscopy-cells-0829"/>
        <updated>2022-08-29T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Separating densely packed molecules before imaging allows them to become visible for the first time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anne Trafton | MIT News Office</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Prebiotics-Controlled Disposable Engineered Bacteria for Intestinal Diseases]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00182</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00182"/>
        <updated>2022-08-29T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00182]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ting-Ting Fang, Zhen-Ping Zou, Ying Zhou, and Bang-Ce Ye</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The automated Galaxy-SynBioCAD pipeline for synthetic biology design and engineering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32661-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32661-x"/>
        <updated>2022-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated design and build processes can rapidly accelerate work in synthetic biology and metabolic engineering. Here the authors present Galaxy-SynBioCAD, a toolshed for synthetic biology, metabolic engineering, and industrial biotechnology that they use to build and execute Galaxy scientific workflows from pathway design to strain engineering through the automated generation of scripts driving robotic workstations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stochastic Modeling of Gene Expression Evolution Uncovers Tissue- and Sex-Specific Properties of Expression Evolution in the Drosophila Genus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0121?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0121?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-08-26T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Soumitra Pal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Overcoming Leak Sensitivity in CRISPRi Circuits Using Antisense RNA Sequestration and Regulatory Feedback]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00155</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00155"/>
        <updated>2022-08-26T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00155]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David A. Specht, Louis B. Cortes, and Guillaume Lambert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assay determines the percentage of Omicron, other variants in Covid wastewater]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/assay-determines-percentage-variants-covid-wastewater-0825</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/assay-determines-percentage-variants-covid-wastewater-0825"/>
        <updated>2022-08-25T19:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developed by the Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology, the assay can provide new details about the type of SARS-CoV-2 circulating in a community.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UNIFAN: A Tool for Unsupervised Single-Cell Clustering and Annotation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0251?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0251?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-08-25T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dongshunyi Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inducible expression of large gRNA arrays for multiplexed CRISPRai applications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32603-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32603-7"/>
        <updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CRISPR gene activation and inhibition has become a powerful synthetic tool for influencing the expression of native genes for foundational studies, cellular reprograming, and metabolic engineering. Here the authors demonstrate near leak-free, inducible expression of a polycistronic array containing up to 24 gRNAs from two orthogonal CRISPR/Cas systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] CRISPR/Cpf1-Mediated Multiplex and Large-Fragment Gene Editing in <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Staphylococcus aureus</named-content>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00248</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00248"/>
        <updated>2022-08-24T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00248]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhipeng Wang, Yu Wang, Yujue Wang, Weizhong Chen, and Quanjiang Ji</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] A Universal Method for Developing Autoinduction Expression Systems Using AHL-Mediated Quorum-Sensing Circuits]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00400</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00400"/>
        <updated>2022-08-24T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00400]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lai Li, Aihua Deng, Shuwen Liu, Junyue Wang, Ruilin Shi, Tiantian Wang, Di Cui, Hua Bai, Yun Zhang, and Tingyi Wen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Optogenetic Control of Bacterial Expression by Red Light]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00259</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00259"/>
        <updated>2022-08-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00259]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elina Multamäki, Andrés García de Fuentes, Oleksii Sieryi, Alexander Bykov, Uwe Gerken, Américo Tavares Ranzani, Jürgen Köhler, Igor Meglinski, Andreas Möglich, and Heikki Takala</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Enzymatic Supercoiling of Bacterial Chromosomes Facilitates Genome Manipulation]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00353</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00353"/>
        <updated>2022-08-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00353]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hironobu Fujita, Ayane Osaku, Yuto Sakane, Koki Yoshida, Kayoko Yamada, Seia Nara, Takahito Mukai, and Masayuki Su’etsugu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Nitrogenase Cofactor Maturase NifB Isolated from Transgenic Rice is Active in FeMo-co Synthesis]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00194</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00194"/>
        <updated>2022-08-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00194]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wenshu He, Stefan Burén, Can Baysal, Xi Jiang, Teresa Capell, Paul Christou, and Luis M. Rubio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence model can detect Parkinson’s from breathing patterns]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/artificial-intelligence-can-detect-parkinsons-from-breathing-patterns-0822</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/artificial-intelligence-can-detect-parkinsons-from-breathing-patterns-0822"/>
        <updated>2022-08-22T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An MIT-developed device with the appearance of a Wi-Fi router uses a neural network to discern the presence and severity of one of the fastest-growing neurological diseases in the world.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Ouyang | Abdul Latif Jameel Clinic for Machine Learning in Health</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forced and spontaneous symmetry breaking in cell polarization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00295-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00295-0"/>
        <updated>2022-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A spectrally accurate numerical method for solving partial differential equations (PDEs) on non-uniformly curved surfaces is developed. The method is applied to a PDE model of cell polarization to show that geometric effects allow the existence of unexpected multidomain solutions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nonlinear dynamics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A nanopore interface for higher bandwidth DNA computing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32526-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32526-3"/>
        <updated>2022-08-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Toe-hold-mediated strand displacement (DSD) is a widely used molecular tool in applications such as DNA computing and nucleic acid diagnostics. Here the authors characterize dozens of orthogonal barcode sequences that can be used for monitoring the output kinetics of multiplexed DSD reactions in real-time using a commercially-available portable nanopore array device.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Evolution-Guided Biosynthesis of Terpenoid Inhibitors]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00188</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00188"/>
        <updated>2022-08-19T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00188]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ankur Sarkar, Tom Foderaro, Levi Kramer, Andrew L. Markley, Jessica Lee, Matthew J. Traylor, and Jerome M. Fox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engineers fabricate a chip-free, wireless electronic “skin”]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/sensor-electronic-chipless-0818</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/sensor-electronic-chipless-0818"/>
        <updated>2022-08-18T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The device senses and wirelessly transmits signals related to pulse, sweat, and ultraviolet exposure, without bulky chips or batteries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jennifer Chu | MIT News Office</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Transfer Learning-Based Classification Model for Particle Pruning in Cryo-Electron Microscopy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0101?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0101?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-08-18T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hongjia Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting and Classifying Nuclei Using Multi-Scale Fully Convolutional Network]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0111?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0111?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-08-18T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bin Xin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Systematic Engineering of <named-content content-type="genus-species" xlink:type="simple">Escherichia coli</named-content> for Efficient Production of Nicotinamide Mononucleotide From Nicotinamide]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00100</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00100"/>
        <updated>2022-08-17T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00100]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhongshi Huang, Ning Li, Shiqin Yu, Weiping Zhang, Tianmeng Zhang, and Jingwen Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halogenation of tyrosine perturbs large-scale protein self-organization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32535-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32535-2"/>
        <updated>2022-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sun et al. has studied the genetically encodable halotyrosines in proteins of the prokaryotic cell division machinery to elucidate the general role of halogenation in cellular lifespan and oxidative damage-induced diseases such as aging and cancer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Molecule Sequence Generation with Rebalanced Variational Autoencoder Loss]]></title>
        <id>https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0063?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R</id>
        <link href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cmb.2022.0063?ai=su&amp;mi=cjwv&amp;af=R"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Computational Biology, Ahead of Print.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chaochao Yan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Author Correction: Engineering cofactor supply and recycling to drive phenolic acid biosynthesis in yeast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41589-022-01129-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41589-022-01129-w"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature Chemical Biology - Author Correction: Engineering cofactor supply and recycling to drive phenolic acid biosynthesis in yeast]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic cybergenetic control of bacterial co-culture composition via optogenetic feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32392-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32392-z"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Communities of microbes play important roles in natural environments and hold great potential for deploying division-of-labor strategies in synthetic biology and bioproduction. Here, in a community of two competing E. coli strains, the authors show that the relative abundances of the strains can be stabilized and steered dynamically with remarkable precision by coupling the cells to an automated computer-controlled feedback-loop.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living LEGOs]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/living-legos-0815</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/living-legos-0815"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematical modeling speeds up the process of programming bacterial systems to self-assemble into desired 2D shapes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandi Miller | Department of Mathematics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amy Keating named head of the Department of Biology]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2022/amy-keating-named-head-department-biology-0815</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/amy-keating-named-head-department-biology-0815"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The computational structural biology researcher continues to serve the department and the MIT life sciences community.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>School of Science</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] The Aspartic Protease Yps3p and Cell Wall Glucanase Scw10p Are Novel Determinants That Enhance the Secretion of the Antitumor Triterpenoid GA-HLDOA in <italic toggle="yes">Saccharomyces cerevisiae</italic>]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00005</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00005"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00005]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yubo Fang and Han Xiao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[[ASAP] Inducible CRISPR/Cas9 Allows for Multiplexed and Rapidly Segregated Single-Target Genome Editing in <italic toggle="yes">Synechocystis</italic> Sp. PCC 6803]]></title>
        <id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00375</id>
        <link href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acssynbio.2c00375"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ACS Synthetic Biology
DOI: 10.1021/acssynbio.2c00375]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ivana Cengic, Inés C. Cañadas, Nigel P. Minton, and Elton P. Hudson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bioengineered textiles with peptide binders that capture SARS-CoV-2 viral particles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-022-00278-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-022-00278-8"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Textiles that block the transmission of viral particles help to reduce virus spread. Here, peptides on the surface a bioengineered textile capture SARS-CoV-2 viral particles, reducing onward infection by 500-fold.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chimeric GPCRs mimic distinct signaling pathways and modulate microglia responses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32390-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32390-1"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the function of GPCRs requires stimulation with their specific ligands. Here, the authors design chemogenetic G-protein coupled receptors that allows for the study of receptors without knowing the immediate ligand, and demonstrate its use for the β2-adrenergic receptor in microglia.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Synthetic biology : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turing patterns, 70 years later]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00306-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-022-00306-0"/>
        <updated>2022-08-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the 70th anniversary of Alan Turing’s seminal paper on morphogenesis, we look back at the history of the paper and its many applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nonlinear dynamics : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>