<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-03-13T00:04:03.765Z</id>
    <title>A curated list of immersive ramblings</title>
    <updated>2024-03-13T00:04:03.765Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wong-Zakai approximations and random attractors for stochastic <em>p</em>-Laplacian lattice systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001207</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001207?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:51.913Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Xuping Zhang, Rong Liang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structural stability of subsonic steady-states to the bipolar Euler-Poisson equations with degenerate boundary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001189</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001189?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:51.723Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Shiqiang Zhao, Ming Mei, Kaijun Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharp well-posedness for the Cauchy problem of the two dimensional quadratic nonlinear Schrödinger equation with angular regularity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001153</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001153?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:51.657Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Hiroyuki Hirayama, Shinya Kinoshita, Mamoru Okamoto]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Note on a nonlinear coupled 4th-order parabolic problem]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001232</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001232?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:51.487Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Fengjie Li, Ping Li]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The maximum number of centers for planar polynomial Kolmogorov differential systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001190</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001190?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:51.242Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Hongjin He, Dongmei Xiao]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability of strong viscous shock wave under periodic perturbation for 1-D isentropic Navier-Stokes system in the half space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001293</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001293?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:51.058Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 July 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 396
Author(s): Lin Chang, Lin He, Jin Ma]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inverse spectral problem for a third-order differential operator on a finite interval]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002203962400127X</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002203962400127X?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:50.983Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 July 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 396
Author(s): V.A. Zolotarev]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of a Poisson–Nernst–Planck–Fermi system for charge transport in ion channels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001256</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001256?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:50.803Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Ansgar Jüngel, Annamaria Massimini]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Landau equation with moderate soft potentials: An approach using <em>ε</em>-Poincaré inequality and Lorentz spaces]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001244</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001244?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:50.793Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): R. Alonso, V. Bagland, B. Lods]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On counterexamples to unique continuation for critically singular wave equations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001025</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001025?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:50.754Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 25 June 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 395
Author(s): Simon Guisset, Arick Shao]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The linear term of the Poincaré map at singularities of planar vector fields]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001402</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001402?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:50.348Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 July 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 396
Author(s): Isaac A. García, Jaume Giné]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A free boundary singular transport equation as a formal limit of a discrete dynamical system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001281</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624001281?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T00:03:50.326Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 July 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 396
Author(s): Giovanni Bellettini, Alessandro Betti, Maurizio Paolini]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physicists Finally Find a Problem That Only Quantum Computers Can Do]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=136178</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/physicists-finally-find-a-problem-only-quantum-computers-can-do-20240312/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T14:07:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have shown that a problem relating to the energy of a quantum system is easy for quantum computers but hard for classical ones.            
The post Physicists Finally Find a Problem That Only Quantum Computers Can Do first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lakshmi Chandrasekaran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Computational Approach to Polynomial Conservation Laws]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1544014?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1544014?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 813-854, March 2024. 
 Abstract.For polynomial ODE models, we introduce and discuss the concepts of exact and approximate conservation laws, which are the first integrals of the full and truncated sets of ODEs. For fast-slow systems, truncated ODEs describe the fast dynamics. We define compatibility classes as subsets of the state space, obtained by equating the conservation laws to constants. A set of conservation laws is complete when the corresponding compatibility classes contain a finite number of steady states. Complete sets of conservation laws can be used for model order reduction and for studying the multistationarity of the model. We provide algorithmic methods for computing linear, monomial, and polynomial conservation laws of polynomial ODE models and for testing their completeness. The resulting conservation laws and their completeness are either independent or dependent on the parameters. In the latter case, we provide parametric case distinctions. In particular, we propose a new method to compute polynomial conservation laws by comprehensive Gröbner systems and syzygies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aurélien Desoeuvres</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preserving Bifurcations through Moment Closures]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M158440X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M158440X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 791-812, March 2024. 
 Abstract.Moment systems arise in a wide range of contexts and applications, e.g., in network modeling of complex systems. Since moment systems consist of a high or even infinite number of coupled equations, an indispensable step in obtaining a low-dimensional representation that is amenable to further analysis is, in many cases, to select a moment closure. A moment closure consists of a set of approximations that express certain higher-order moments in terms of lower-order ones, so that applying those leads to a closed system of equations for only the lower-order moments. Closures are frequently found drawing on intuition and heuristics to come up with quantitatively good approximations. In contrast to that, we propose an alternative approach where we instead focus on closures giving rise to certain qualitative features, such as bifurcations. Importantly, this fundamental change of perspective provides one with the possibility of classifying moment closures rigorously in regard to these features. This makes the design and selection of closures more algorithmic, precise, and reliable. In this work, we carefully study the moment systems that arise in the mean-field descriptions of two widely known network dynamical systems, the SIS epidemic and the adaptive voter model. We derive conditions that any moment closure has to satisfy so that the corresponding closed systems exhibit the transcritical bifurcation that one expects in these systems coming from the stochastic particle model.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Kuehn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tangential Cone Condition for the Full Waveform Forward Operator in the Viscoelastic Regime: The Nonlocal Case]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1551845?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1551845?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 2, Page 412-432, April 2024. 
 Abstract. We discuss mapping properties of the parameter-to-state map of full waveform inversion and generalize the results of [M. Eller and A. Rieder, Inverse Problems, 37 (2021), 085011] from the acoustic to the viscoelastic wave equation. In particular, we establish injectivity of the Fréchet derivative of the parameter-to-state map for a semidiscrete seismic inverse problem in the viscoelastic regime. Here the finite-dimensional parameter space is restricted to functions having global support in the propagation medium (the nonlocal case) and that are locally linearly independent. As a consequence, we deduce local conditional well-posedness of this nonlinear inverse problem. Furthermore, we show that the tangential cone condition holds, which is an essential prerequisite in the convergence analysis of a variety of inversion algorithms for nonlinear ill-posed problems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthias Eller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finite Amplitude Analysis of Poiseuille Flow in Fluid Overlying Porous Domain]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1575809?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1575809?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 2, Page 433-463, April 2024. 
 Abstract. A weakly nonlinear stability analysis of isothermal Poiseuille flow in a fluid overlying porous domain is proposed and investigated in this article. The nonlinear interactions are studied by imposing finite amplitude disturbances to the classical model deliberated in Chang, Chen, and Straughan [J. Fluid Mech., 564 (2006), pp. 287–303]. The order parameter theory is used to ascertain the cubic Landau equation, and the regimes of instability for the bifurcations are determined henceforth. The well-established controlling parameters viz. the depth ratio [math] depth of fluid domain/depth of porous domain), the Beavers–Joseph constant [math], and the Darcy number [math] are inquired upon for the bifurcation phenomena. The imposed finite amplitude disturbances are viewed for bifurcations along the neutral stability curves and away from the critical point as a function of the wave number [math] and the Reynolds number [math]. The even-fluid-layer (porous) mode along the neutral stability curves correlates to the subcritical (supercritical) bifurcation phenomena. On perceiving the bifurcations as a function of [math] and [math] by moving away from the bifurcation/critical point, subcritical bifurcation is observed for increasing [math] and decreasing [math]. In contrast to only fluid flow through a channel, it is found that the inclusion of porous domain aids in the early appearance of subcritical bifurcation when [math]. A considerable difference between the computed skin friction coefficient for the base and the distorted state is observed for small (large) values of [math]. In addition, an intrinsic relation among the mode of instability, bifurcation phenomena, and secondary flow pattern is also observed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Aleria</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data-driven autonomous operation of VOCs removal system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56502-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56502-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Data-driven autonomous operation of VOCs removal system]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Application of machine learning algorithms for accurate determination of bilirubin level on in vitro engineered tissue phantom images]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56319-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56319-4"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Application of machine learning algorithms for accurate determination of bilirubin level on in vitro engineered tissue phantom images]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short-depth QAOA circuits and quantum annealing on higher-order ising models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41534-024-00825-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41534-024-00825-w"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Quantum Information - Short-depth QAOA circuits and quantum annealing on higher-order ising models]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the cellular neighborhood]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/exploring-cellular-neighborhood-0311</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/exploring-cellular-neighborhood-0311"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T20:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software allows scientists to model shapeshifting proteins in native cellular environments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Biester | Department of Biology</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny Tweaks to Neurons Can Rewire Animal Motion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=136114</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/tiny-tweaks-to-neurons-can-rewire-animal-motion-20240311/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T14:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Altering a protein in the neurons that coordinate a rattlesnake’s movement made a slow slither neuron more like a speedy rattle neuron, showing one way evolution can generate new ways of moving.            
The post Tiny Tweaks to Neurons Can Rewire Animal Motion first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elise Cutts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No installation required: how WebAssembly is changing scientific computing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00725-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00725-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Enabling code execution in the web browser, the multilanguage tool is powerful but complicated.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anomaly detection in IoT-based healthcare: machine learning for enhanced security]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56126-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56126-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Anomaly detection in IoT-based healthcare: machine learning for enhanced security]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development and validation of prognostic machine learning models for short- and long-term mortality among acutely admitted patients based on blood tests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56638-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56638-6"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Development and validation of prognostic machine learning models for short- and long-term mortality among acutely admitted patients based on blood tests]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMENet is a monocular depth estimation network designed for automatic stereoscopic display]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56095-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56095-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - AMENet is a monocular depth estimation network designed for automatic stereoscopic display]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards a universal mechanism for successful deep learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56609-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56609-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Towards a universal mechanism for successful deep learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Author Correction: A challenge for rounded evaluation of recommender systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-024-00819-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-024-00819-5"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature Machine Intelligence - Author Correction: A challenge for rounded evaluation of recommender systems]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pushing the limits of OFDFT with neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00610-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00610-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A neural network-based method for advancing orbital-free density functional theory (OFDFT) is developed, which reaches DFT accuracy and maintains lower cost complexity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overcoming the barrier of orbital-free density functional theory for molecular systems using deep learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00605-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00605-8"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[M-OFDFT is a deep learning implementation of orbital-free density functional theory (OFDFT) that achieves DFT-level accuracy on molecular systems with lower cost complexity, and can extrapolate to much larger molecules than those seen during training.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Monte Carlo with large patched transformers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01584-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01584-y"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ground state representations with artificial neural network methods enable high-accuracy simulations of quantum many-body systems. The authors study the performance of the transformer network architecture on this task and demonstrate its vast potential for novel findings in quantum physics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Numerical investigation of shipping noise in the Red Sea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56523-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56523-2"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Numerical investigation of shipping noise in the Red Sea]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Scientific Computing]]></title>
        <id>10915</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10915"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast SVD-Based Linear Elastic Eigenvalue Problem Solver for Band Structures of 3D Phononic Crystals]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02483-8</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02483-8"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this article, a Fast Linear Elastic Eigenvalue Problem Solver (FLEEPS) is developed to calculate the band structures of three-dimensional (3D) isotropic phononic crystals (PnCs). In brief, FLEEPS solves in linear time complexity the smallest few eigenvalues and associated eigenvectors of the linear elastic eigenvalue problem originating from the finite difference discretization of the frequency-domain linear elastic wave equation. Notably, FLEEPS employs the weighted singular value decomposition based preconditioner to greatly improve the convergence rate of the conjugate gradient iteration, and uses the fast Fourier transform algorithm to accelerate this preconditioner times a vector, based on the structured decomposition of the dense unitary factor T of this preconditioner. Band structure calculations of several 3D isotropic PnCs are presented to showcase the capabilities of FLEEPS. The preliminary MATLAB implementation of FLEEPS is available at https://github.com/FAME-GPU/FLEEPS-MATLAB.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Reduced Order Model for Domain Decompositions with Non-conforming Interfaces]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02465-w</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02465-w"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this paper, we propose a reduced-order modeling strategy for two-way Dirichlet–Neumann parametric coupled problems solved with domain-decomposition (DD) sub-structuring methods. We split the original coupled differential problem into two sub-problems with Dirichlet and Neumann interface conditions, respectively. After discretization by, e.g., the finite element method, the full-order model (FOM) is solved by Dirichlet–Neumann iterations between the two sub-problems until interface convergence is reached. We then apply the reduced basis (RB) method to obtain a low-dimensional representation of the solution of each sub-problem. Furthermore, we apply the discrete empirical interpolation method (DEIM) at the interface level to achieve a fully reduced-order representation of the DD techniques implemented. To deal with non-conforming FE interface discretizations, we employ the INTERNODES method combined with the interface DEIM reduction. The reduced-order model (ROM) is then solved by sub-iterating between the two reduced-order sub-problems until the convergence of the approximated high-fidelity interface solutions. The ROM scheme is numerically verified on both steady and unsteady coupled problems, in the case of non-conforming FE interfaces.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pointwise Error Estimates of Numerical Solutions to Linear Quadratic Optimal Control Problems]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02484-7</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02484-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
An auxiliary optimal control problem is formulated that provides with its unique solution, a continuous representation of the global error of a numerical approximation to the solution of a linear quadratic optimal control problem. The resulting error functions are characterized as the unique solutions to an optimality system that is reformulated as a boundary value problem. With this formulation, reliable pointwise error estimates can be generated utilizing well-established techniques of defect control. A novel algorithm based on defect correction and defect control is presented that generates pointwise approximations to the global error of numerical optimal control solutions on a uniform grid. It is proven and numerically validated that this algorithm can generate pointwise estimates that approximate the true global error with a prescribed accuracy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nonconforming Virtual Element Method with Curved Edges]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02441-w</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02441-w"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
We introduce a nonconforming virtual element method for the Poisson problem on domains with fixed curved boundary and internal interfaces. We prove arbitrary order optimal convergence in the energy and 
                      
                      \(L^2\)
                      
                     norms, and assess the theoretical results with numerical experiments. The proposed scheme has the upside that it can be designed and analyzed in any dimension.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A deep learning method for empirical spectral prediction and inverse design of all-optical nonlinear plasmonic ring resonator switches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56522-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56522-3"/>
        <updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A deep learning method for empirical spectral prediction and inverse design of all-optical nonlinear plasmonic ring resonator switches]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sentiment analysis of video danmakus based on MIBE-RoBERTa-FF-BiLSTM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56518-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56518-z"/>
        <updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Sentiment analysis of video danmakus based on MIBE-RoBERTa-FF-BiLSTM]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlphaPept: a modern and open framework for MS-based proteomics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46485-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46485-4"/>
        <updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mass spectrometry-based proteomics faces the challenge of processing vast data amounts. Here, the authors introduce AlphaPept, an open-source, Python-based framework that offers high speed analysis and easy integration for large-scale proteome analysis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drivers and impact of the early silent invasion of SARS-CoV-2 Alpha]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46345-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46345-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The SARS-CoV-2 Alpha variant of concern emerged in the UK in late 2020 but spread internationally before it was detected. Here, the authors reconstruct the dynamics of dissemination of this variant out of the UK by combining extent of genomic sequencing, travel volume, and local epidemic dynamics in a Bayesian model.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Optimal Control Problem for the Wigner Equation]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1515033?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1515033?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 2, Page 387-411, April 2024. 
 Abstract. The Wigner quasi-density function allows a phase-space formulation of statistical quantum mechanics that is of fundamental importance in theoretical investigation and in applications. This work contributes to these tasks with the formulation and analysis of an optimal control problem for the Wigner equation, which describes the time evolution of the quasi-density function. For this purpose, two possible control mechanisms are considered, and, correspondingly, a detailed analysis in weighted Sobolev spaces for the controlled nonhomogeneous Wigner equation is presented. Further theoretical results are reported concerning existence of optimal controls and differentiability of the control-to-state map and of the ensemble cost functional, which allows the derivation of the optimality system that characterizes the optimal controls sought.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Omar Morandi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers enhance peripheral vision in AI models]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/researchers-enhance-peripheral-vision-ai-models-0308</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/researchers-enhance-peripheral-vision-ai-models-0308"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By enabling models to see the world more like humans do, the work could help improve driver safety and shed light on human behavior.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Zewe | MIT News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative artificial intelligence in chemical engineering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44286-024-00041-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44286-024-00041-5"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generative artificial intelligence will transform the way we design and operate chemical processes, argues Artur M. Schweidtmann.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MFCA-Net: a deep learning method for semantic segmentation of remote sensing images]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56211-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56211-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - MFCA-Net: a deep learning method for semantic segmentation of remote sensing images]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhancing parasitic organism detection in microscopy images through deep learning and fine-tuned optimizer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56323-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56323-8"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Enhancing parasitic organism detection in microscopy images through deep learning and fine-tuned optimizer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhancing discovery of host–guest binders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-023-00584-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-023-00584-2"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Determining what guest can effectively bind in a host, or the reverse, is a central challenge in chemistry. To address this, an electron-density-based transformer method of generating and optimizing host–guest binders is proposed, applied to two different host systems and validated by experiment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative artificial intelligence in chemical engineering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44286-024-00041-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44286-024-00041-5"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generative artificial intelligence will transform the way we design and operate chemical processes, argues Artur M. Schweidtmann.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron density-based GPT for optimization and suggestion of host–guest binders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00602-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00602-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An optimization algorithm is used to discover guest molecules based on knowing only the structure of the host. The molecules are represented as 3D volumes, optimized to improve host–guest interaction and converted into SMILES using a transformer model.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discontinuous Galerkin Method Based on the Reduced Space for the Nonlinear Convection–Diffusion–Reaction Equation]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02486-5</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02486-5"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this paper, by introducing a reconstruction operator based on the Legendre moments, we construct a reduced discontinuous Galerkin (RDG) space that could achieve the same approximation accuracy but using fewer degrees of freedom (DoFs) than the standard discontinuous Galerkin (DG) space. The design of the “narrow-stencil-based” reconstruction operator can preserve the local data structure property of the high-order DG methods. With the RDG space, we apply the local discontinuous Galerkin (LDG) method with the implicit-explicit time marching for the nonlinear unsteady convection–diffusion–reaction equation, where the reduction of the number of DoFs allows us to achieve higher efficiency. In terms of theoretical analysis, we give the well-posedness and approximation properties for the reconstruction operator and the 
                      
                      \(L^2\)
                      
                     error estimate for the semi-discrete LDG scheme. Several representative numerical tests demonstrate the accuracy and the performance of the proposed method in capturing the layers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Breakthrough Brings Matrix Multiplication Closer to Ideal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=136063</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/new-breakthrough-brings-matrix-multiplication-closer-to-ideal-20240307/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T15:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By eliminating a hidden inefficiency, computer scientists have come up with a new way to multiply large matrices that’s faster than ever.            
The post New Breakthrough Brings Matrix Multiplication Closer to Ideal first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Nadis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guarantees for Spontaneous Synchronization on Random Geometric Graphs]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1559270?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1559270?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 779-790, March 2024. 
 Abstract. The Kuramoto model is a classical mathematical model in the field of nonlinear dynamical systems that describes the evolution of coupled oscillators in a network that may reach a synchronous state. The relationship between the network’s topology and whether the oscillators synchronize is a central question in the field of synchronization, and random graphs are often employed as a proxy for complex networks. On the other hand, the random graphs on which the Kuramoto model is rigorously analyzed in the literature are homogeneous models and fail to capture the underlying geometric structure that appears in several examples. In this work, we leverage tools from random matrix theory, random graphs, and mathematical statistics to prove that the Kuramoto model on a random geometric graph on the sphere synchronizes with probability tending to one as the number of nodes tends to infinity. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first rigorous result for the Kuramoto model on random geometric graphs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pedro Abdalla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning high-level visual representations from a child’s perspective without strong inductive biases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-024-00802-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-024-00802-0"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visual representations are thought to develop from visual experience and inductive biases. Orhan and Lake show that modern machine learning algorithms can learn visual knowledge from a few hundred hours of longitudinal headcam recordings collected from young children during the course of early development, without strong inductive biases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The model student: GPT-4 performance on graduate biomedical science exams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55568-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55568-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - The model student: GPT-4 performance on graduate biomedical science exams]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development of risk models of incident hypertension using machine learning on the HUNT study data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56170-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56170-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Development of risk models of incident hypertension using machine learning on the HUNT study data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cellular Self-Destruction May Be Ancient. But Why?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=136017</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/cellular-self-destruction-may-be-ancient-but-why-20240306/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T14:54:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How did cells evolve a process to end their own lives? Recent research suggests that apoptosis, a form of programmed cell death, first arose billions of years ago in bacteria with a primitive sociality.            
The post Cellular Self-Destruction May Be Ancient. But Why? first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Veronique Greenwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upscaling an Extended Heterogeneous Stefan Problem from the Pore-Scale to the Darcy Scale in Permafrost]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1552000?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1552000?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling & Simulation, Volume 22, Issue 1, Page 436-475, March 2024. 
 Abstract. In this paper we upscale thermal models from the pore–scale to the Darcy scale for applications in permafrost. We incorporate thawing and freezing of water at the pore-scale and adapt rigorous homogenization theory from [A. Visintin, SIAM J. Math. Anal., 39 (2007), pp. 987–1017] to the original nonlinear multivalued relationship to derive the effective properties. To obtain agreement of the effective model with the known Darcy scale empirical models, we revisit and extend the pore-scale model to include the delicate microscale physics in small pores. We also propose a practical reduced model for the nonlinear effective conductivity. We illustrate with simulations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Malgorzata Peszynska</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fano Resonances in All-Dielectric Electromagnetic Metasurfaces]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1554825?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1554825?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling & Simulation, Volume 22, Issue 1, Page 476-526, March 2024. 
 Abstract. We are interested in the resonant electromagnetic scattering by all-dielectric metasurfaces made of a two-dimensional lattice of nanoparticles with high refractive indices. In [Ammari, Li, and Zou, Trans. Amer. Math. Soc., 376 (2023), pp. 39–90], it has been shown that a single high-index nanoresonator can couple with the incident wave and exhibit a strong magnetic dipole response. Recent physics experiments reveal that when the particles are arranged in certain periodic configurations, they may have different anomalous scattering effects in the macroscopic scale, compared to the single-particle case. In this work, we shall develop a rigorous mathematical framework for analyzing the resonant behaviors of all-dielectric metasurfaces. We start with the characterization of subwavelength scattering resonances in such a periodic setting and their asymptotic expansions in terms of the refractive index of the nanoparticles. Then we show that real resonances always exist below the essential spectrum of the periodic Maxwell operator and that they are the simple poles of the scattering resolvent with the exponentially decaying resonant modes. By using group theory, we discuss the implications of the symmetry of the metasurface on the subwavelength band functions and their associated eigenfunctions. For the symmetric metasurfaces with the normal incidence, we use a variational method to show the existence of embedded eigenvalues (i.e., real subwavelength resonances embedded in the continuous radiation spectrum). Furthermore, we break the configuration symmetry either by introducing a small deformation of particles or by slightly deviating from the normal incidence and prove that Fano-type reflection and transmission anomalies can arise in both of these scenarios.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Habib Ammari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coarsening of Thin Films with Weak Condensation]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1559336?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1559336?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 2, Page 362-386, April 2024. 
 Abstract. A lubrication model can be used to describe the dynamics of a weakly volatile viscous fluid layer on a hydrophobic substrate. Thin layers of the fluid are unstable to perturbations and break up into slowly evolving interacting droplets. A reduced-order dynamical system is derived from the lubrication model based on the nearest-neighbor droplet interactions in the weak condensation limit. Dynamics for periodic arrays of identical drops and pairwise droplet interactions are investigated, providing insights into the coarsening dynamics of a large droplet system. Weak condensation is shown to be a singular perturbation, fundamentally changing the long-time coarsening dynamics for the droplets and the overall mass of the fluid in two additional regimes of long-time dynamics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hangjie Ji</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why scientists trust AI too much — and what to do about it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00639-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00639-y"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some researchers see superhuman qualities in artificial intelligence. All scientists need to be alert to the risks this creates.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Chinese named entity recognition model incorporating recurrent cell and information state recursion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56166-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56166-3"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A Chinese named entity recognition model incorporating recurrent cell and information state recursion]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complex hybrid weighted pruning method for accelerating convolutional neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55942-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55942-5"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Complex hybrid weighted pruning method for accelerating convolutional neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new secure offloading approach for internet of vehicles in fog-cloud federation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56141-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56141-y"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A new secure offloading approach for internet of vehicles in fog-cloud federation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction of teaching system of public art major using CMOS image sensor technology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56224-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56224-w"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Construction of teaching system of public art major using CMOS image sensor technology]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatial deformable transformer for 3D point cloud registration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56217-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56217-9"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Spatial deformable transformer for 3D point cloud registration]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermal fault diagnosis of complex electrical equipment based on infrared image recognition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56142-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56142-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Thermal fault diagnosis of complex electrical equipment based on infrared image recognition]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning quantum Hamiltonians from high-temperature Gibbs states and real-time evolutions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-023-02376-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-023-02376-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Complexity of learning Hamiltonians from Gibbs states is an important issue for both many-body physics and machine learning. The optimal sample and time complexities of quantum Hamiltonian learning for high temperature has now been proven.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complex hybrid weighted pruning method for accelerating convolutional neural networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55942-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55942-5"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Complex hybrid weighted pruning method for accelerating convolutional neural networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flame self-interactions in MILD combustion of homogeneous and inhomogeneous mixtures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55782-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55782-3"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Flame self-interactions in MILD combustion of homogeneous and inhomogeneous mixtures]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Validation of computational fluid dynamics models for airway deposition with SPECT data of the same population]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56033-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56033-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Validation of computational fluid dynamics models for airway deposition with SPECT data of the same population]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction of teaching system of public art major using CMOS image sensor technology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56224-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56224-w"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Construction of teaching system of public art major using CMOS image sensor technology]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integration of graph neural networks and genome-scale metabolic models for predicting gene essentiality]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41540-024-00348-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41540-024-00348-2"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Systems Biology and Applications - Integration of graph neural networks and genome-scale metabolic models for predicting gene essentiality]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elliptic Curve ‘Murmurations’ Found With AI Take Flight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=135959</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/elliptic-curve-murmurations-found-with-ai-take-flight-20240305/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T15:12:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematicians are working to fully explain unusual behaviors uncovered using artificial intelligence.            
The post Elliptic Curve ‘Murmurations’ Found With AI Take Flight first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lyndie Chiou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using generative AI to improve software testing]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/using-generative-ai-improve-software-testing-datacebo-0305</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/using-generative-ai-improve-software-testing-datacebo-0305"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIT spinout DataCebo helps companies bolster their datasets by creating synthetic data that mimic the real thing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Winn | MIT News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unlocking the potential of smartphone and ambient sensors for ADL detection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56123-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56123-0"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Unlocking the potential of smartphone and ambient sensors for ADL detection]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Incorporating high-frequency information into edge convolution for link prediction in complex networks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56144-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56144-9"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Incorporating high-frequency information into edge convolution for link prediction in complex networks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computer programmers show distinct, expertise-dependent brain responses to violations in form and meaning when reading code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56090-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56090-6"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Computer programmers show distinct, expertise-dependent brain responses to violations in form and meaning when reading code]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable-Order Fractional Laplacian and its Accurate and Efficient Computations with Meshfree Methods]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02472-x</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02472-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
The variable-order fractional Laplacian plays an important role in the study of heterogeneous systems. In this paper, we propose the first numerical methods for the variable-order Laplacian 
                      
                      \((-\varDelta )^{\alpha (\textbf{x} )/2}\)
                      
                     with 
                      
                      \(0 < \alpha (\textbf{x} ) \le 2\)
                      
                    , which will also be referred as the variable-order fractional Laplacian if 
                      
                      \(\alpha (\textbf{x} )\)
                      
                     is strictly less than 2. We present a class of hypergeometric functions whose variable-order Laplacian can be analytically expressed. Building on th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Regularization Continuation Method for Optimization Problems with Nonlinear Equality Constraints]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02476-7</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02476-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
This paper considers the regularization continuation method and the trust-region updating strategy for the nonlinearly equality-constrained optimization problem. Namely, it uses the inverse of the regularization quasi-Newton matrix as the pre-conditioner and the Sherman–Morrison–Woodbury formula to improve its computational efficiency in the well-posed phase, and it adopts the inverse of the regularization two-sided projection of the Hessian as the pre-conditioner to improve its robustness in the ill-conditioned phase. Since it only solves a linear system of equations and the Sherman–Morrison–Woodbury formula significantly saves the computational time at every iteration, and the sequential quadratic programming (SQP) method needs to solve a quadratic programming subproblem at every iteration, it is faster than SQP. Numerical results also show that it is more robust and faster than SQP (the built-in subroutine fmincon.m of the MATLAB2020a environment and the subroutine SNOPT executed in GAMS v28.2 (GAMS Corporation, 2019) environment). The computational time of the new method is about one third of that of fmincon.m for the large-scale problem. Finally, the global convergence analysis of the new method is also given.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A GAN-based anomaly detector using multi-feature fusion and selection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52378-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52378-9"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A GAN-based anomaly detector using multi-feature fusion and selection]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bias of AI-generated content: an examination of news produced by large language models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55686-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55686-2"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Bias of AI-generated content: an examination of news produced by large language models]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hierarchical graph contrastive learning of local and global presentation for multimodal sentiment analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-54872-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-54872-6"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Hierarchical graph contrastive learning of local and global presentation for multimodal sentiment analysis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Applying explainable artificial intelligence methods to models for diagnosing personal traits and cognitive abilities by social network data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56080-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-56080-8"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Applying explainable artificial intelligence methods to models for diagnosing personal traits and cognitive abilities by social network data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prediction of highly stable 2D carbon allotropes based on azulenoid kekulene]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46279-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46279-8"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of 2D materials with useful electronic properties is challenging. Here, the authors use DFT to design a stable semiconducting 2D carbon allotrope for optoelectronic applications that has light charge carriers and unusual secondary bandgap.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A GAN-based anomaly detector using multi-feature fusion and selection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52378-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52378-9"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A GAN-based anomaly detector using multi-feature fusion and selection]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hierarchical graph contrastive learning of local and global presentation for multimodal sentiment analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-54872-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-54872-6"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Hierarchical graph contrastive learning of local and global presentation for multimodal sentiment analysis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-precision regressors for particle physics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52941-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52941-4"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - High-precision regressors for particle physics]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding scholar-trajectories across scientific periodicals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-54693-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-54693-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Understanding scholar-trajectories across scientific periodicals]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Correction to : An Oscillation-Free Bound-Preserving Discontinuous Galerkin Method for Multi-Component Chemically Reacting Flows]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02480-x</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02480-x"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Scientific Computing -]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active Flux Methods for Hyperbolic Systems Using the Method of Bicharacteristics]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02462-z</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02462-z"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
The Active Flux method is a third order accurate finite volume method for hyperbolic conservation laws, which is based on the use of point values as well as cell average values of the conserved quantities. The resulting method is fully discrete and has a compact stencil in space and time. An important component of Active Flux methods is the evolution formula for the update of the point values. A previously proposed exact evolution formula for acoustics is reviewed and used to construct an Active Flux method for the two-dimensional Maxwell’s equation. Furthermore, the method of bicharacteristics is discussed as a methodology for the derivation of truly multidimensional approximative evolution operators that can be used for the evolution of point values in Active Flux methods. We study accuracy and stability of the resulting methods for acoustics and compare with the Active Flux method that uses the exact evolution operator. Finally, we used the method of bicharacteristics to derive Cartesian grid Active Flux methods for the linearised and nonlinear Euler equations. Numerous test computations illustrate the performance of these new Active Flux methods.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A road data assets revenue allocation model based on a modified Shapley value approach considering contribution evaluation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55819-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55819-7"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A road data assets revenue allocation model based on a modified Shapley value approach considering contribution evaluation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A cluster-based SMOTE both-sampling (CSBBoost) ensemble algorithm for classifying imbalanced data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55598-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55598-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A cluster-based SMOTE both-sampling (CSBBoost) ensemble algorithm for classifying imbalanced data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning solutions for smart city challenges in urban development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55928-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55928-3"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Deep learning solutions for smart city challenges in urban development]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fiber optic computing using distributed feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01549-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01549-1"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Optical techniques adopted in optical computing rely on spatial multiplexing, requiring numerous integrated elements and restricting the architecture to perform a single kernel convolution per layer. The authors demonstrate a fiber-optic computing architecture based on temporal multiplexing that performs multiple convolutions in a single layer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migraine headache (MH) classification using machine learning methods with data augmentation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55874-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55874-0"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Migraine headache (MH) classification using machine learning methods with data augmentation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Convergent Numerical Algorithm for $$\alpha $$ -Dissipative Solutions of the Hunter–Saxton Equation]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02479-4</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02479-4"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
A convergent numerical method for 
                      
                      \(\alpha \)
                      
                    -dissipative solutions of the Hunter–Saxton equation is derived. The method is based on applying a tailor-made projection operator to the initial data, and then solving exactly using the generalized method of characteristics. The projection step is the only step that introduces any approximation error. It is therefore crucial that its design ensures not only a good approximation of the initial data, but also that errors due to the energy dissipation at later times remain small. Furthermore, it is shown that the main quantity of interest, the wave profile, converges in 
                      
                      \(L^{\infty }\)
                      
                     for all 
                      
                      \(t \ge 0\)
                      
                    , while a subsequence of the energy density converges weakly for almost every time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatiotemporal Patterns in a Lengyel–Epstein Model Near a Turing–Hopf Singular Point]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1552668?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1552668?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 2, Page 338-361, April 2024. 
 Abstract. In this paper, a study is carried out on the spatiotemporal dynamics of a Lengyel–Epstein model describing the chlorite-iodine-malonic-acid (CIMA) reaction with time delay and the Neumann boundary condition in a two-dimensional region. The existences for Turing, Hopf, Turing–Turing, Turing–Hopf, and Bogdanov–Takens bifurcations are derived by analyzing the dispersion relation between eigenvalues and wave numbers. In particular, to study the dynamics around a Turing–Hopf bifurcation singularity, the amplitude equations near a codimension-two bifurcation point are derived by employing the weakly nonlinear analysis method. Different spatiotemporal patterns for the system in parameter space are classified and various patterns identified, including spatially homogeneous periodic solutions, mixed mode, coexistence mode, bistable phenomenon, square, hexagon, black eye, two-phase oscillating staggered hexagon lattice, and other complex spatiotemporal patterns. The theoretical predictions are verified by numerical simulations showing an excellent agreement with many reported experiment results not only in chemistry but also in physics and biology. Results presented in this article reveal the mechanism of generating the spatiotemporal patterns of the CIMA reaction.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuangrui Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computation of Riesz [math]-Capacity [math] of General Sets in [math] Using Stable Random Walks]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1568077?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1568077?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 2, Page 317-337, April 2024. 
 Abstract. A method for computing the Riesz [math]-capacity, [math], of a general set [math] is given. The method is based on simulations of isotropic [math]-stable motion paths in [math]-dimensions. The familiar walk-on-spheres method, often utilized for simulating Brownian motion, is modified to a novel walk-in-and-out-of-balls method adapted for modeling the stable path process on the exterior of regions “probed” by this type of generalized random walk. It accounts for the propensity of this class of random walk to jump through boundaries because of the path discontinuity. This method allows for the computationally efficient simulation of hitting locations of stable paths launched from the exterior of probed sets. Reliable methods of computing capacity from these locations are given, along with non-standard confidence intervals. Illustrative calculations are performed for representative types of sets [math], where both [math] and [math] are varied.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John P. Nolan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup accelerates progress toward light-speed computing]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/startup-lightmatter-accelerates-progress-toward-light-speed-computing-0301</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/startup-lightmatter-accelerates-progress-toward-light-speed-computing-0301"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lightmatter, founded by three MIT alumni, is using photonic technologies to reinvent how chips communicate and calculate.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Winn | MIT News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dealing with the limitations of our noisy world]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/tamara-broderick-quantifying-uncertainty-0301</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/tamara-broderick-quantifying-uncertainty-0301"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tamara Broderick uses statistical approaches to understand and quantify the uncertainty that can affect study results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Zewe | MIT News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A novel multi-scale CNN and Bi-LSTM arbitration dense network model for low-rate DDoS attack detection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55814-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55814-y"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A novel multi-scale CNN and Bi-LSTM arbitration dense network model for low-rate DDoS attack detection]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning the hierarchy of steering measurement settings of qubit-pair states]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01563-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01563-3"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To prepare steerable assembles from a bipartite quantum state is a cumbersome task due to the optimization over all possible incompatible measurements. Here the authors leverage the power of the deep learning model to infer the hierarchy of steering measurement settings and reveal the most compact parameters to characterize the Alice-to-Bob steerability.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Study on settlement prediction of soft ground considering multiple feature parameters based on ISSA-RF model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55236-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-55236-w"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Study on settlement prediction of soft ground considering multiple feature parameters based on ISSA-RF model]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Empirical data drift detection experiments on real-world medical imaging data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46142-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-46142-w"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data drift is the systematic change in the underlying distribution of input features in prediction models, and can cause deterioration in model performance. Here, the authors highlight the importance of detecting data drift in clinical settings and evaluate methods for detecting drift in medical image data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics of Controllable Matter-Wave Solitons and Soliton Molecules for a Rabi-Coupled Gross–Pitaevskii Equation with Temporally and Spatially Modulated Coefficients]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M155551X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M155551X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 748-778, March 2024. 
 Abstract. This paper studies the soliton dynamics for the Rabi-coupled Gross–Pitaevskii model in multicomponent Bose–Einstein condensates. The model has variable nonlinearities and external potentials and is used to construct a complex multisoliton in an explicit form. The variable nonlinearity and external potential cause the soliton to compress and change its velocity, respectively. A new generalized similarity transformation is proposed to eliminate the [math] Rabi-coupled terms in the [math]-component model, which can make the Hirota bilinear method be applied to obtain multisoliton solutions. The bound state of the two-soliton forms the soliton molecule under velocity resonance. Asymptotic analysis can give the asymptotic expressions of each single soliton in multisoliton solutions, which can clearly give each soliton’s width, velocity, amplitude, and energy; these parameters can control multisolitons. When the solitons’ relative velocity or the solitons’ width is large, the interferogram between solitons will be observed. Numerical simulation shows that these solitons can steadily propagate. It is easy for the soliton molecule and interference dynamics to occur because of the controlled soliton. Since the coupled Gross–Pitaevskii equation describes the mechanics of matter waves in Bose–Einstein condensates, it is proved that we can observe the stable solitons and soliton molecules in Bose–Einstein condensates. The method and results presented in this paper are also common to other similar models. When observing particle multiple distributions, quantum interferometry, and interferometers, the results presented and the model in this paper can provide a reference for these applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haotian Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four-Coloring [math]-Free Graphs. II. Finding an Excellent Precoloring]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/18M1234849?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjcat&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/18M1234849?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjcat&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Computing, Volume 53, Issue 1, Page 146-187, February 2024. 
 Abstract. This is the second paper in a series of two. The goal of the series is to give a polynomial-time algorithm for the 4-coloring problem and the 4-precoloring extension problem restricted to the class of graphs with no induced six-vertex path, thus proving a conjecture of Huang. Combined with previously known results, this completes the classification of the complexity of the 4-coloring problem for graphs with a connected forbidden induced subgraph. In this paper we give a polynomial time-algorithm that starts with a 4-precoloring of a graph with no induced six-vertex path and outputs a polynomial-sized collection of so-called excellent precolorings. Excellent precolorings are easier to handle than general ones, and, in addition, in order to determine whether the initial precoloring can be extended to the whole graph, it is enough to answer the same question for each of the excellent precolorings in the collection. The first paper in the series deals with excellent precolorings, thus providing a complete solution to the problem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maria Chudnovsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Correction to: The Hermite Finite Volume Method with Global Conservation Law]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02475-8</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02475-8"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Scientific Computing -]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anderson Acceleration as a Krylov Method with Application to Convergence Analysis]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02464-x</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02464-x"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
Anderson acceleration (AA) is widely used for accelerating the convergence of nonlinear fixed-point methods, but little is known about how to quantify the asymptotic convergence acceleration provided by AA. As a roadway towards gaining more understanding of convergence acceleration by AA, we study AA(m), i.e., Anderson acceleration with finite window size m, applied to the case of linear fixed-point iterations. We write AA(m) as a Krylov method with polynomial residual update formulas, and derive 
                      
                      \((m+2)\)
                      
                    -term recurrence relations for the AA(m) polynomials. We derive several results based on these polynomial residual update formulas, including orthogonality relations, acceleration coefficient bounds, nonlinear recursions, and residual convergence bounds. We apply these results to study AA(1) residual convergence patterns and the influence of the initial guess on the asymptotic convergence factor.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>