<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-02-07T00:03:44.126Z</id>
    <title>A curated list of immersive ramblings</title>
    <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:44.126Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pullback dynamics and statistical solutions for dissipative non-autonomous Zakharov equations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000470</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000470?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:33.397Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 390
Author(s): Hujun Yang, Xiaoling Han, Caidi Zhao]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sharp Moser-Trudinger type inequality involving <em>L</em><sup><em>p</em></sup> norm in <math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si1.svg" class="math"><msup><mrow><mi mathvariant="double-struck">R</mi></mrow><mrow><mi>n</mi></mrow></msup></math> with degenerate potential]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000494</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000494?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:33.255Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 390
Author(s): Jingxuan Sun, Zhen Song, Wenming Zou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3D stochastic Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equations coupled with Maxwell's equations with full energy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000445</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000445?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:33.189Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 390
Author(s): Zdzisław Brzeźniak, Ben Goldys, Liang Li]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controllability of quasi-linear Hamiltonian Schrödinger equations on tori]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000421</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000421?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:33.085Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 390
Author(s): Felice Iandoli, Jingrui Niu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global quantitative stability of wave equations with strong and weak dampings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000469</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000469?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:32.826Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 5 May 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 390
Author(s): Jiangbo Han, Keyan Wang, Runzhang Xu, Chao Yang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical properties in the axiomatic theory of ordinary differential equations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000561</id>
        <link href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022039624000561?dgcid=rss_sd_all"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T00:03:32.591Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publication date: 15 May 2024
Source: Journal of Differential Equations, Volume 391
Author(s): Tomoharu Suda]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Differential Equations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six MIT students selected as spring 2024 MIT-Pillar AI Collective Fellows]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/mit-pillar-ai-collective-fellows-0206</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/mit-pillar-ai-collective-fellows-0206"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T21:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The graduate students will aim to commercialize innovations in AI, machine learning, and data science.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>School of Engineering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radio Maps May Reveal the Universe’s Biggest Magnetic Fields]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=134999</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/radio-maps-may-reveal-the-universes-biggest-magnetic-fields-20240206/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T14:51:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A controversial technique has produced detailed maps of the magnetic fields in colossal galaxy clusters. If confirmed, the approach could be used to reveal where cosmic magnetic fields come from.            
The post Radio Maps May Reveal the Universe’s Biggest Magnetic Fields first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan O'Callaghan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized Multiscale Finite Element Treatment of a Heterogeneous Nonlinear Strain-limiting Elastic Model]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1514179?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1514179?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling & Simulation, Volume 22, Issue 1, Page 334-368, March 2024. 
 Abstract. In this work, we consider a nonlinear strain-limiting elastic model in heterogeneous domains. We investigate heterogeneous material with soft and stiff inclusions and perforations that are important to understand an elastic solid’s behavior and crack-tip fields. Numerical solutions of problems in computational domains with inclusions and perforations require the construction of a sufficiently fine grid that resolves heterogeneity on the grid level. Approximations on such grids lead to a large system of equations with large computational costs. To reduce the size of the system and provide an accurate solution, we present a generalized multiscale finite element approximation on the coarse grid. In this method, we construct multiscale basis functions in each local domain associated with the coarse-grid cell and based on the construction of the snapshot space and solution of the local spectral problem reduce the size of the snapshot space. Two types of multiscale basis function construction are presented. The first type is a general case that can handle any boundary conditions on the global boundary of the heterogeneous domain. The considered problem requires an accurate approximation of the crack-surface boundary. In the second type of multiscale basis functions, we incorporate global boundary conditions in the basis construction process which provide an accurate approximation of the stress and strain on the crack boundary. We present numerical results for three cases of heterogeneity: soft inclusions, stiff inclusions, and perforations. A numerical investigation is presented for the two examples of loading on the domain with and without crack boundary conditions. The presented generalized multiscale finite element solver provides an accurate solution with a large reduction of the discrete system size. Our results illustrate the significant error reduction on the crack surface when we use the second type of basis functions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maria Vasilyeva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting Anti-integrability to Attractors for Three-Dimensional Quadratic Diffeomorphisms]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1571897?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1571897?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 616-640, March 2024. 
 Abstract. We previously showed that three-dimensional quadratic diffeomorphisms have anti-integrable (AI) limits that correspond to a quadratic correspondence, a pair of one-dimensional maps. At the AI limit the dynamics is conjugate to a full shift on two symbols. Here we consider a more general AI limit, allowing two parameters of the map to go to infinity. We prove the existence of AI states for each symbol sequence for three cases of the quadratic correspondence: parabolas, ellipses, and hyperbolas. A contraction argument gives parameter domains such that this is a bijection, but the correspondence also is observed to apply more generally. We show that orbits of the original map can be obtained by numerical continuation for a volume-contracting case. These results show that periodic AI states evolve into the observed periodic attractors of the diffeomorphism. We also continue a periodic AI state with a symbol sequence chosen so that it continues to an orbit resembling a chaotic attractor that is a 3D version of the classical 2D Hénon attractor.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amanda E. Hampton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI chatbot shows surprising talent for predicting chemical properties and reactions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00347-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00347-7"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers lightly tweak ChatGPT-like system to offer chemistry insight.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classification of human walking context using a single-point accelerometer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53143-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53143-8"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Classification of human walking context using a single-point accelerometer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A serverless computing architecture for Martian aurora detection with the Emirates Mars Mission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53492-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53492-4"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A serverless computing architecture for Martian aurora detection with the Emirates Mars Mission]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced Aquila optimizer based on tent chaotic mapping and new rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53064-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53064-6"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Enhanced Aquila optimizer based on tent chaotic mapping and new rules]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leveraging large language models for predictive chemistry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-023-00788-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-023-00788-1"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Machine learning techniques are widely employed in chemical science, but are application specific and their development requires dedicated expertise. Jablonka and colleagues fine-tune the GPT-3 model and show that it can provide surprisingly accurate answers to a wide range of chemical questions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced Aquila optimizer based on tent chaotic mapping and new rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53064-6</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53064-6"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Enhanced Aquila optimizer based on tent chaotic mapping and new rules]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How symmetry can come to the aid of machine learning]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/how-symmetry-can-aid-machine-learning-0205</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/how-symmetry-can-aid-machine-learning-0205"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T15:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploiting the symmetry within datasets, MIT researchers show, can decrease the amount of data needed for training neural networks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Nadis | MIT CSAIL</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Your Brain Is Doing When You’re Not Doing Anything]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=134926</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/what-your-brain-is-doing-when-youre-not-doing-anything-20240205/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T15:01:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When your mind is wandering, your brain’s “default mode” network is active. Its discovery 20 years ago inspired a raft of research into networks of brain regions and how they interact with each other.            
The post What Your Brain Is Doing When You’re Not Doing Anything first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nora Bradford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Mechanics for Closure of Dynamical Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1514246?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1514246?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling & Simulation, Volume 22, Issue 1, Page 283-333, March 2024. 
 Abstract. We propose a scheme for data-driven parameterization of unresolved dimensions of dynamical systems based on the mathematical framework of quantum mechanics and Koopman operator theory. Given a system in which some components of the state are unknown, this method involves defining a surrogate system in a time-dependent quantum state which determines the fluxes from the unresolved degrees of freedom at each timestep. The quantum state is a density operator on a finite-dimensional Hilbert space of classical observables and evolves over time under an action induced by the Koopman operator. The quantum state also updates with new values of the resolved variables according to a quantum Bayes’ law, implemented via an operator-valued feature map. Kernel methods are utilized to learn data-driven basis functions and represent quantum states, observables, and evolution operators as matrices. The resulting computational schemes are automatically positivity-preserving, aiding in the physical consistency of the parameterized system. We analyze the results of two different modalities of this methodology applied to the Lorenz 63 and Lorenz 96 multiscale systems and show how this approach preserves important statistical and qualitative properties of the underlying chaotic dynamics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David C. Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exponential Convergence of a Generalized FEM for Heterogeneous Reaction-Diffusion Equations]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1522231?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1522231?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling & Simulation, Volume 22, Issue 1, Page 256-282, March 2024. 
 Abstract. A generalized finite element method (FEM) is proposed for solving a heterogeneous reaction-diffusion equation with a singular perturbation parameter [math], based on locally approximating the solution on each subdomain by solution of a local reaction-diffusion equation and eigenfunctions of a local eigenproblem. These local problems are posed on some domains slightly larger than the subdomains with oversampling size [math]. The method is formulated at the continuous level as a direct discretization of the continuous problem and at the discrete level as a coarse-space approximation for its standard finite element (FE) discretizations. Exponential decay rates for local approximation errors with respect to [math] and [math] (at the discrete level with [math] denoting the fine FE mesh size) and with the local degrees of freedom are established. In particular, it is shown that the method at the continuous level converges uniformly with respect to [math] in the standard [math] norm, and that if the oversampling size is relatively large with respect to [math] and [math] (at the discrete level), the solutions of the local reaction-diffusion equations provide good local approximations for the solution and thus the local eigenfunctions are not needed. Numerical results are provided to verify the theoretical results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chupeng Ma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Unified Approach to Reverse Engineering and Data Selection for Unique Network Identification]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1540570?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1540570?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 592-615, March 2024. 
 Abstract.Due to cost concerns, it is optimal to gain insight into the connectivity of biological and other networks using as few experiments as possible. Data selection for unique network connectivity identification has been an open problem since the introduction of algebraic methods for reverse engineering for almost two decades. In this manuscript we determine what data sets uniquely identify the unsigned wiring diagram corresponding to a system that is discrete in time and space. Furthermore, we answer the question of uniqueness for signed wiring diagrams for Boolean networks. Computationally, unsigned and signed wiring diagrams have been studied separately, and in this manuscript we also show that there exists an ideal capable of encoding both unsigned and signed information. This provides a unified approach to studying reverse engineering that also gives significant computational benefits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alan Veliz-Cuba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feature importance feedback with Deep Q process in ensemble-based metaheuristic feature selection algorithms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53141-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53141-w"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Feature importance feedback with Deep Q process in ensemble-based metaheuristic feature selection algorithms]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-efficiency reinforcement learning with hybrid architecture photonic integrated circuit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45305-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45305-z"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Authors present a universal framework that utilizes photonic integrated circuits (PIC) to enhance the efficiency of reinforcement learning (RL). Leveraging the advantages of the hybrid architecture PIC (HyArch PIC), the PIC-RL experiment demonstrates a remarkable 56% improvement in efficiency for synthesizing perovskite materials.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A novel extreme adaptive GRU for multivariate time series forecasting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53460-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53460-y"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A novel extreme adaptive GRU for multivariate time series forecasting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prediction of the axial compression capacity of stub CFST columns using machine learning techniques]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53352-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53352-1"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Prediction of the axial compression capacity of stub CFST columns using machine learning techniques]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fuzzy PID control of permanent magnet synchronous motor electric steering engine by improved beetle antennae search algorithm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52600-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52600-8"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Fuzzy PID control of permanent magnet synchronous motor electric steering engine by improved beetle antennae search algorithm]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fuzzy PID control of permanent magnet synchronous motor electric steering engine by improved beetle antennae search algorithm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52600-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52600-8"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Fuzzy PID control of permanent magnet synchronous motor electric steering engine by improved beetle antennae search algorithm]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journal of Scientific Computing]]></title>
        <id>10915</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10915"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Helmholtz Equation with Uncertainties in the Wavenumber]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02450-3</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02450-3"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
We investigate the Helmholtz equation with suitable boundary conditions and uncertainties in the wavenumber. Thus the wavenumber is modeled as a random variable or a random field. We discretize the Helmholtz equation using finite differences in space, which leads to a linear system of algebraic equations including random variables. A stochastic Galerkin method yields a deterministic linear system of algebraic equations. This linear system is high-dimensional, sparse and complex symmetric but, in general, not hermitian. We therefore solve this system iteratively with GMRES and propose two preconditioners: a complex shifted Laplace preconditioner and a mean value preconditioner. Both preconditioners reduce the number of iteration steps as well as the computation time in our numerical experiments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Positivity-Preserving and Robust Fast Solver for Time-Fractional Convection–Diffusion Problems]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-024-02454-z</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-024-02454-z"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
This paper presents a fast solver for time-fractional two-dimensional convection-diffusion problems that maintains non-negativity of numerical solutions. To this end, two new techniques are developed. (i) A three-part decomposition of the L1 discretization for Caputo derivatives is proposed and justified for fast evaluation while maintaining positivity; (ii) A positivity-correction technique is devised for both diffusive and convective fluxes. An upwinding technique for the bilinear finite volume approximation on general quadrilaterals is utilized for enabling the solver robustness in handling convection dominance. The solver attains optimal convergence rates when graded temporal meshes are used. These properties are theoretically justified and numerically illustrated.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waveform shaping in photonic time-crystals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53391-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53391-8"/>
        <updated>2024-02-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Waveform shaping in photonic time-crystals]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modeling Excitable Cells with the EMI Equations: Spectral Analysis and Iterative Solution Strategy]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02449-2</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02449-2"/>
        <updated>2024-02-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this work, we are interested in solving large linear systems stemming from the extra–membrane–intra model, which is employed for simulating excitable tissues at a cellular scale. After setting the related systems of partial differential equations equipped with proper boundary conditions, we provide its finite element discretization and focus on the resulting large linear systems. We first give a relatively complete spectral analysis using tools from the theory of Generalized Locally Toeplitz matrix sequences. The obtained spectral information is used for designing appropriate preconditioned Krylov solvers. Through numerical experiments, we show that the presented solution strategy is robust w.r.t. problem and discretization parameters, efficient and scalable.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YOLOX target detection model can identify and classify several types of tea buds with similar characteristics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53498-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53498-y"/>
        <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - YOLOX target detection model can identify and classify several types of tea buds with similar characteristics]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence-driven virtual rehabilitation for people living in the community: A scoping review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-024-00998-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-024-00998-w"/>
        <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[npj Digital Medicine - Artificial intelligence-driven virtual rehabilitation for people living in the community: A scoping review]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interactive curriculum learning increases and homogenizes motor smoothness]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53253-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53253-3"/>
        <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Interactive curriculum learning increases and homogenizes motor smoothness]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Template-Based Image Reconstruction Facing Different Topologies]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02446-5</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02446-5"/>
        <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
The reconstruction of images from measured data is an increasing field of research. For highly under-determined problems, template-based image reconstruction provides a way of compensating for the lack of sufficient data. A caveat of this approach is that dealing with different topologies of the template and the target image is challenging. In this paper, we propose a LDDMM-based image-reconstruction model that resolves this issue by adding a source term. On the theoretical side, we show that the model satisfies all criteria for being a well-posed regularization method. For the implementation, we pursue a discretize-then-optimize approach involving the proximal alternating linearized minimization algorithm, which is known to converge under mild assumptions. Our simulations with both artificial and real data confirm the robustness of the method, and its ability to successfully deal with topology changes even if the available amount of data is very limited.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jacobi Processes with Jumps as Neuronal Models: A First Passage Time Analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1516877?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1516877?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 1, Page 189-214, February 2024. 
 Abstract. To overcome some limits of classical neuronal models, we propose a Markovian generalization of the classical model based on Jacobi processes by introducing downwards jumps to describe the activity of a single neuron. The statistical analysis of interspike intervals is performed by studying the first passage times of the proposed Markovian Jacobi process with jumps through a constant boundary. In particular, we characterize its Laplace transform, which is expressed in terms of some generalization of hypergeometric functions that we introduce, and deduce a closed-form expression for its expectation. Our approach, which is original in the context of first-passage-time problems, relies on intertwining relations between the semigroups of the classical Jacobi process and its generalization, which have been recently established in [P. Cheridito et al., J. Ec. Polytech. - Math., 8 (2021), pp. 331–378]. A numerical investigation of the firing rate of the considered neuron is performed for some choices of the involved parameters and of the jump distributions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giuseppe D’Onofrio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear Regularized 13-Moment Equations with Onsager Boundary Conditions for General Gas Molecules]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1556472?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1556472?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 1, Page 215-245, February 2024. 
 Abstract. We develop the steady-state regularized 13-moment equations in the linear regime for rarefied gas dynamics with general collision models. For small Knudsen numbers, the model is accurate up to the super-Burnett order, and the resulting system of moment equations is shown to have a symmetric structure. We also propose Onsager boundary conditions for the moment equations that guarantee the stability of the equations. The validity of our model is verified by benchmark examples for the one-dimensional channel flows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhenning Cai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detection, differentiation and localization of replay attack and false data injection attack based on random matrix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52954-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52954-z"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Detection, differentiation and localization of replay attack and false data injection attack based on random matrix]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine learning enables non-Gaussian investigation of changes to peripheral nerves related to electrical stimulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53284-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53284-w"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Machine learning enables non-Gaussian investigation of changes to peripheral nerves related to electrical stimulation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-platform social dynamics: an analysis of ChatGPT and COVID-19 vaccine conversations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53124-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53124-x"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Cross-platform social dynamics: an analysis of ChatGPT and COVID-19 vaccine conversations]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extending deterministic transport capabilities for very-high and ultra-high energy electron beams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-51143-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-51143-8"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Extending deterministic transport capabilities for very-high and ultra-high energy electron beams]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Criticality in FitzHugh-Nagumo oscillator ensembles: Design, robustness, and spatial invariance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01530-y</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-024-01530-y"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reservoir computing uses networks of interacting components to provide a flexible framework for decision-making, control, and signal processing, but the implementation is complicated by inherent parameter variabilities and uncertainties. The authors design a reservoir of FitzHugh-Nagumo oscillators exhibiting critical behavior and robustness across a wide range of resistive coupling strengths.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integration of Swin UNETR and statistical shape modeling for a semi-automated segmentation of the knee and biomechanical modeling of articular cartilage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52548-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52548-9"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Integration of Swin UNETR and statistical shape modeling for a semi-automated segmentation of the knee and biomechanical modeling of articular cartilage]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In a ‘Dark Dimension,’ Physicists Search for the Universe’s Missing Matter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=134877</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/in-a-dark-dimension-physicists-search-for-missing-matter-20240201/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T15:40:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An idea derived from string theory suggests that dark matter is hiding in a (relatively) large extra dimension. The theory makes testable predictions that physicists are investigating now.            
The post In a ‘Dark Dimension,’ Physicists Search for the Universe’s Missing Matter first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Nadis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes for ‘Good’ Mathematics?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=134856</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/what-makes-for-good-mathematics-20240201/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T14:03:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terence Tao, who has been called the “Mozart of Mathematics,” wrote an essay in 2007 about the common ingredients in “good” mathematical research. In this episode, the Fields Medalist joins Steven Strogatz to revisit the topic.            
The post What Makes for ‘Good’ Mathematics? first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Strogatz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Inversion Scheme for Elastic Diffraction Tomography Based on Mode Separation]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1538909?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1538909?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 1, Page 165-188, February 2024. 
 Abstract. We consider the problem of elastic diffraction tomography, which consists in reconstructing elastic properties (i.e., mass density and elastic Lamé parameters) of a weakly scattering medium from full-field data of scattered waves outside the medium. Elastic diffraction tomography refers to the elastic inverse scattering problem after linearization using a first-order Born approximation. In this paper, we prove the Fourier diffraction theorem, which relates the two-dimensional Fourier transform of scattered waves with the Fourier transform of the scatterer in the three-dimensional spatial Fourier domain. Elastic wave mode separation is performed, which decomposes a wave into five modes. A new two-step inversion process is developed, providing information on the modes first and second on the elastic parameters. Finally, we discuss reconstructions with plane wave excitation experiments for different tomographic setups and with different plane wave excitation frequencies, respectively.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bochra Mejri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wireless body area sensor networks based human activity recognition using deep learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53069-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53069-1"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Wireless body area sensor networks based human activity recognition using deep learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simulating real-life scenarios to better understand the spread of diseases under different contexts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52903-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52903-w"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Simulating real-life scenarios to better understand the spread of diseases under different contexts]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spike frequency adaptation: bridging neural models and neuromorphic applications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00165-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44172-024-00165-9"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This review explores adaptive neuron models from computational neuroscience, emphasizing their significance in the future development of power efficient artificial intelligence applications and hardware integration.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A study on the evaluation of competitiveness in the aviation logistics industry cluster in Zhengzhou]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52697-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52697-x"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A study on the evaluation of competitiveness in the aviation logistics industry cluster in Zhengzhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Application solutions of highway freight information systems based on quantum communication]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52987-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52987-4"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Application solutions of highway freight information systems based on quantum communication]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elementary cellular automata realized by stateful three-memristor logic operations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53125-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53125-w"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Elementary cellular automata realized by stateful three-memristor logic operations]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A collapse risk assessment method for subway foundation pit based on cloud model and improved Dempster–Shafer evidence theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52643-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52643-x"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A collapse risk assessment method for subway foundation pit based on cloud model and improved Dempster–Shafer evidence theory]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A study on the evaluation of competitiveness in the aviation logistics industry cluster in Zhengzhou]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52697-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52697-x"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A study on the evaluation of competitiveness in the aviation logistics industry cluster in Zhengzhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Application solutions of highway freight information systems based on quantum communication]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52987-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52987-4"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Application solutions of highway freight information systems based on quantum communication]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Dimensional-Splitting Weak Galerkin Finite Element Method for 2D Time-Fractional Diffusion Equation]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02448-3</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02448-3"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this article, the weak Galerkin finite element method, coupled with an operator-splitting method or known as dimensional-splitting technique, is proposed to solve a class of 2D time-fractional diffusion equation of order 
                      
                      \(\beta \)
                      
                    , 
                      
                      \(0<\beta <1\)
                      
                     numerically. The time-fractional term is discretized using the well-known non-uniform L1-method, as the integer-order temporal derivatives of the solution blow up at the initial point. For the spatial discretization, a dimensional-splitting weak Galerkin finite element method is used in both x and y directions over a uniform mesh. The stability and the optimal error estimate of the proposed scheme are addressed in the 
                      
                      \(L^2\)
                      
                    -norm. Finally, we present a numerical experiment to demonstrate the suitability of the stated method.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Double Precision is not Necessary for LSQR for Solving Discrete Linear Ill-Posed Problems]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02447-4</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02447-4"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
The growing availability and usage of low precision floating point formats attracts many interests of developing lower or mixed precision algorithms for scientific computing problems. In this paper we investigate the possibility of exploiting mixed precision computing in LSQR for solving discrete linear ill-posed problems. Based on the commonly used regularization model for linear inverse problems, we analyze the choice of proper computing precision in the two main parts of LSQR, including the construction of Krylov subspace and updating procedure of iterative solutions. We show that, under some mild conditions, the Lanczos vectors can be computed using single precision without loss of any accuracy of the final regularized solution as long as the noise level is not extremely small. We also show that the most time consuming part for updating iterative solutions can be performed using single precision without sacrificing any accuracy. The results indicate that several highly time consuming parts of the algorithm can be implemented using lower precisions, and provide a theoretical guideline for implementing a robust and efficient mixed precision variant of LSQR for solving discrete linear ill-posed problems. Numerical experiments are made to test two mixed precision variants of LSQR and confirming our results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plants Find Light Using Gaps Between Their Cells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=134812</id>
        <link href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/plants-find-light-using-gaps-between-their-cells-20240131/"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T15:10:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A mutant seedling revealed how plant tissues scatter incoming light, allowing plants to sense its direction and move toward it.            
The post Plants Find Light Using Gaps Between Their Cells first appeared on Quanta Magazine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Asher Elbein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can scientists make the most of the public’s trust in them?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00238-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00238-x"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have a part to play in addressing concerns about government interference in science.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating new skills and new connections with MIT’s Quantitative Methods Workshop]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/quantitative-methods-workshop-0130</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/quantitative-methods-workshop-0130"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80 students and faculty from a dozen collaborating institutions became immersed at the intersection of computation and life sciences and forged new ties to MIT and each other.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Orenstein | The Picower Institute for Learning and Memory</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Particle-Continuum Multiscale Modeling of Sea Ice Floes]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M155904X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M155904X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=mmsubt&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling & Simulation, Volume 22, Issue 1, Page 230-255, March 2024. 
 Abstract. Sea ice profoundly influences the polar environment and the global climate. Traditionally, sea ice has been modeled as a continuum under Eulerian coordinates to describe its large-scale features, using, for instance, viscous-plastic rheology. Recently, Lagrangian particle models, also known as the discrete element method models, have been utilized for characterizing the motion of individual sea ice fragments (called floes) at scales of 10 km and smaller, especially in marginal ice zones. This paper develops a multiscale model that couples the particle and the continuum systems to facilitate an effective representation of the dynamical and statistical features of sea ice across different scales. The multiscale model exploits a Boltzmann-type system that links the particle movement with the continuum equations. For the small-scale dynamics, it describes the motion of each sea ice floe. Then, as the large-scale continuum component, it treats the statistical moments of mass density and linear and angular velocities. The evolution of these statistics affects the motion of individual floes, which in turn provides bulk feedback that adjusts the large-scale dynamics. Notably, the particle model characterizing the sea ice floes is localized and fully parallelized in a framework that is sometimes called superparameterization, which significantly improves computational efficiency. Numerical examples demonstrate the effective performance of the multiscale model. Additionally, the study demonstrates that the multiscale model has a linear-order approximation to the truth model.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quanling Deng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bifurcation Analysis of Bogdanov–Takens Bifurcations in Delay Differential Equations]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1527532?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1527532?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 553-591, March 2024. 
 Abstract. In this paper, we will perform the parameter-dependent center manifold reduction near the generic and transcritical codimension two Bogdanov–Takens bifurcation in classical delay differential equations. Using an approximation to the homoclinic solutions derived with a generalized Lindstedt–Poincaré method, we develop a method to initialize the continuation of the homoclinic bifurcation curves emanating from these points. The normal form transformation is derived in the functional analytic perturbation framework for dual semigroups (sun-star calculus) using a normalization technique based on the Fredholm alternative. The obtained expressions give explicit formulas, which have been implemented in the freely available bifurcation software package DDE-BifTool. The effectiveness is demonstrated on various models]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. M. Bosschaert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tipping Points in Seed Dispersal Mutualism Driven by Environmental Stochasticity]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1531579?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1531579?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 1, Page 114-138, February 2024. 
 Abstract. The mechanism of seed dispersal mutualism is fundamental to understanding vegetation diversity and its conservation. In this study, we propose a stochastic model that extends the classical framework of seed dispersal mutualism to explore the effects of environmental stochasticity on mutualistic interactions between seed dispersers and plants. We first provide a comprehensive picture of the long-term dynamics of seed dispersal mutualism in deterministic and stochastic environments. We then analyze the relationship between stochasticity and the probability and time that seed dispersal mutualism tips between stable states. Additionally, we evaluate the extinction risk of seed dispersal mutualism for different population values and accordingly assign extinction warning levels to these values. The analysis reveals that the impact of environmental stochasticity on tipping phenomena is scenario-dependent but follows some interpretable trends. The probability (resp., time) of tipping towards the extinction state typically increases (resp., decreases) monotonically with noise intensity, while the probability of tipping towards the coexistence state typically peaks at intermediate noise intensity. Noise in animal populations contributes to tipping toward the coexistence state, whereas noise in plant populations slows down the tipping toward the coexistence state. Noise-induced changes in warning levels of initial population values are most pronounced near the boundaries of the basin of attraction, but sufficiently loud noise (especially for plant populations) may alter the risk far from these boundaries. These findings provide a theoretical explanation for the effect of environmental stochasticity on multistability transitions in seed dispersal mutualism and can be utilized to study the interplay between other population systems and environmental stochasticity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tao Feng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Hierarchy of Kinetic Discrete-Velocity Models for Traffic Flow Derived from a Nonlocal Prigogine–Herman Model]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1583065?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1583065?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 1, Page 139-164, February 2024. 
 Abstract. Starting from a nonlocal version of the Prigogine–Herman traffic model, we derive a natural hierarchy of kinetic discrete-velocity models for traffic flow consisting of systems of quasi-linear hyperbolic equations with relaxation terms. The hyperbolic main part of these models turns out to have several favorable features. In particular, we determine Riemann invariants and prove richness and total linear degeneracy of the hyperbolic systems. Moreover, a physically reasonable invariant domain is obtained for all equations of the hierarchy. Additionally, we investigate the full relaxation system with respect to stability and persistence of periodic (stop-and-go-type) solutions and derive a condition for the appearance of such solutions. Finally, numerical results for various situations are presented, illustrating the analytical findings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Borsche</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reaching carbon neutrality requires energy-efficient training of AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00200-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00200-x"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Letter to the Editor]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Method for multi-task learning fusion network traffic classification to address small sample labels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-51933-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-51933-8"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Method for multi-task learning fusion network traffic classification to address small sample labels]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient pneumonia detection using Vision Transformers on chest X-rays]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52703-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52703-2"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Efficient pneumonia detection using Vision Transformers on chest X-rays]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved machine learning algorithm for predicting ground state properties]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45014-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45014-7"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recent work proposed a machine learning algorithm for predicting ground state properties of quantum many-body systems that outperforms any non-learning classical algorithm but requires extensive training data. Lewis et al. present an improved algorithm with exponentially reduced training data requirements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Network structure shapes the impact of diversity in collective learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52837-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52837-3"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Network structure shapes the impact of diversity in collective learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical optimisation of a novel gas sensor using periodically closed resonators]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52851-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52851-5"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Theoretical optimisation of a novel gas sensor using periodically closed resonators]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient pneumonia detection using Vision Transformers on chest X-rays]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52703-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52703-2"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Efficient pneumonia detection using Vision Transformers on chest X-rays]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physics and semantic informed multi-sensor calibration via optimization theory and self-supervised learning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53009-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-53009-z"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Physics and semantic informed multi-sensor calibration via optimization theory and self-supervised learning]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Application of Optimal Control Techniques to the Shadowing Approach for Time Averaged Sensitivity Analysis of Chaotic Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1550219?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1550219?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 505-552, March 2024. 
 Abstract. Traditional sensitivity analysis methods fail for chaotic systems due to the unstable characteristics of the linearized equations. To overcome these issues two methods have been developed in the literature, one being the shadowing approach, which results in a minimization problem, and the other being numerical viscosity, where a damping term is added to the linearized equations to suppress the instability. The shadowing approach is computationally expensive but produces accurate sensitivities, while numerical viscosity can produce less accurate sensitivities but with significantly reduced computational cost. However, it is not fully clear how the solutions generated by these two approaches compare to each other. In this work we aim to bridge this gap by introducing a control term, found with optimal control theory techniques, to prevent the exponential growth of solution of the linearized equations. We will refer to this method as optimal control shadowing. We investigate the computational aspects and performance of this new method on the Lorenz and Kuramoto–Sivashinsky systems and compare its performance with simple numerical viscosity schemes. We show that the tangent solution generated by the proposed approach is similar to that generated by shadowing methods, suggesting that optimal control attempts to stabilize the unstable shadowing direction. Further, for the spatially extended system, we examine the energy budget of the tangent equation and show that the control term found via the solution of the optimal control problem acts only at length scales where production of tangent energy dominates dissipation, which is not necessarily the case for the numerical viscosity methods.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhys E. Gilbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reduced Order Characterization of Nonlinear Oscillations Using an Adaptive Phase-Amplitude Coordinate Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1551699?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1551699?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 470-504, March 2024. 
 Abstract. We propose a general strategy for reduced order modeling of systems that display highly nonlinear oscillations. By considering a continuous family of forced periodic orbits defined in relation to a stable fixed point and subsequently leveraging phase-amplitude-based reduction strategies, we arrive at a low order model capable of accurately capturing nonlinear oscillations resulting from arbitrary external inputs. In the limit that oscillations are small, the system dynamics relax to those obtained from local linearization, i.e., that can be fully described using linear eigenmodes. For larger amplitude oscillations, the behavior can be understood in terms of the dynamics of a small number of nonlinear modes. We illustrate the proposed strategy in a variety of examples yielding results that are substantially better than those obtained using standard linearization-based techniques.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resource constrained neural network training]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52356-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52356-1"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Resource constrained neural network training]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction and optimization of representative actual driving cycles based on the improved autoencoder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52865-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52865-z"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Construction and optimization of representative actual driving cycles based on the improved autoencoder]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harnessing machine learning to find synergistic combinations for FDA-approved cancer drugs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52814-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52814-w"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Harnessing machine learning to find synergistic combinations for FDA-approved cancer drugs]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptive tactile interaction transfer via digitally embroidered smart gloves]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45059-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45059-8"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptive tactile interactions transfer across users, space, and time, via embroidered smart gloves is reported by the authors. The scalable fabrication and adaptive computation pipeline enable tactile occlusion alleviation, human skills transfer, and interactive teleoperation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A hybridization of evolution strategies with iterated greedy algorithm for no-wait flow shop scheduling problems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-47729-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-47729-x"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - A hybridization of evolution strategies with iterated greedy algorithm for no-wait flow shop scheduling problems]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computer science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cover runners-up of 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00592-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43588-024-00592-w"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We continue our yearly tradition of highlighting our favorite cover suggestions that did not make it as covers at Nature Computational Science.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of medical technologies may be predicted using constructed graph bibliometrics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52233-x</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52233-x"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Impact of medical technologies may be predicted using constructed graph bibliometrics]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resource constrained neural network training]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52356-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52356-1"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Resource constrained neural network training]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of nasal septal perforation on the airflow and air-conditioning characteristics of the nasal cavity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52755-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52755-4"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Impact of nasal septal perforation on the airflow and air-conditioning characteristics of the nasal cavity]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An artificial intelligence approach to predicting personality types in dogs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52920-9</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52920-9"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - An artificial intelligence approach to predicting personality types in dogs]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An actor-model framework for visual sensory encoding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45105-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-45105-5"/>
        <updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Encoding and downsampling images is key for visual prostheses. Here, the authors show that an actor-model framework using the inherent computation of the retinal network yields better performance in downsampling images compared to learning-free methods.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Aggregation-Based Two-Grid Method for Multilevel Block Toeplitz Linear Systems]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02434-9</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02434-9"/>
        <updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
This paper presents an aggregation-based two-grid method for solving a multilevel block Toeplitz system. Different from the existing multigrid methods for multilevel block Toeplitz systems, we aggregate a given multilevel block Toeplitz matrix to a new multilevel Toeplitz matrix in such a way that a very sparse coarse grid matrix is constructed in practice. Then, we give an asymptotically tight bound of the convergence rate and provide an algorithm for selecting the optimal prolongation vector and the relaxation factor for our method. Numerical experiments on artificial examples are provided for visualizing the correctness of our analysis, while experiments associated with practical examples show the efficiency of our method in terms of computing time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bursts of communication increase opinion diversity in the temporal Deffuant model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52458-w</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52458-w"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Bursts of communication increase opinion diversity in the temporal Deffuant model]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potholes and traffic signs detection by classifier with vision transformers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52426-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52426-4"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Potholes and traffic signs detection by classifier with vision transformers]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entrepreneur creates career pathways with MIT OpenCourseWare]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/entrepreneur-creates-career-pathways-mit-opencourseware-0125</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/entrepreneur-creates-career-pathways-mit-opencourseware-0125"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[June Odongo uses free, online MIT courses to train high-quality candidates, making them job-ready.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sara Feijo | MIT Open Learning</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discrepancy Modeling Framework: Learning Missing Physics, Modeling Systematic Residuals, and Disambiguating between Deterministic and Random Effects]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M148375X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M148375X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 440-469, March 2024. 
 Abstract.Physics-based and first-principles models pervade the engineering and physical sciences, allowing for the ability to model the dynamics of complex systems with a prescribed accuracy. The approximations used in deriving governing equations often result in discrepancies between the model and sensor-based measurements of the system, revealing the approximate nature of the equations and/or the signal-to-noise ratio of the sensor itself. In modern dynamical systems, such discrepancies between model and measurement can lead to poor quantification, often undermining the ability to produce accurate and precise control algorithms. We introduce a discrepancy modeling framework to identify the missing …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Megan R. Ebers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay between Normal Forms and Center Manifold Reduction for Homoclinic Predictors near Bogdanov–Takens Bifurcation]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M151354X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M151354X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 410-439, March 2024. 
 Abstract.This paper provides for the first time correct third-order homoclinic predictors in [math]-dimensional ODEs near a generic Bogdanov–Takens bifurcation point, which can be used to start the numerical continuation of the appearing homoclinic orbits. To achieve this, higher-order time approximations to the nonlinear time transformation in the Lindstedt–Poincaré method are essential. Moreover, a correct transform between approximations to solutions in the normal form and approximations to solutions on the parameter-dependent center manifold is derived rigorously. A detailed comparison is done between applying different normal forms (smooth and orbital), different phase conditions, and different perturbation methods (regular and Lindstedt–Poincaré) to approximate the homoclinic solution near Bogdanov–Takens points. Examples demonstrating the correctness of the predictors are given. The new homoclinic predictors are implemented in the open-source MATLAB/GNU Octave continuation package MatCont.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maikel M. Bosschaert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An innovative machine learning based on feed-forward artificial neural network and equilibrium optimization for predicting solar irradiance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52462-0</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52462-0"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - An innovative machine learning based on feed-forward artificial neural network and equilibrium optimization for predicting solar irradiance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-organized intracellular twisters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-023-02372-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-023-02372-1"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cytoplasmic flows in the fruit fly oocyte can reorganize cellular components. These structured vortical flows arise through self-organizing dynamics of microtubules, molecular motors and cytoplasm.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robustly federated learning model for identifying high-risk patients with postoperative gastric cancer recurrence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-44946-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-44946-4"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medical data faces isolation and cross-center performance issues. Here, the authors propose a robust federated learning model to identify high-risk postoperative gastric cancer recurrence, achieving promising results across data from four independent medical institutions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implicit Active Flux Methods for Linear Advection]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02433-w</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02433-w"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
In this work we develop implicit Active Flux schemes for the scalar advection equation. At every cell interface we approximate the solution by a polynomial in time. This allows to evolve the point values using characteristics and to update the cell averages using fluxes obtained by integrating this polynomial. The resulting schemes have order of convergence up to five, but show only moderate oscillations with high frequencies for discontinuous solutions. In numerical experiments we compare the different methods and show an application to network flows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Numerical Solution of the Biot/Elasticity Interface Problem Using Virtual Element Methods]]></title>
        <id>10.1007/s10915-023-02444-7</id>
        <link href="http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s10915-023-02444-7"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract
We propose, analyse and implement a virtual element discretisation for an interfacial poroelasticity/elasticity consolidation problem. The formulation of the time–dependent poroelasticity equations uses displacement, fluid pressure and total pressure, and the elasticity equations are written in displacement-pressure formulation. The construction of the virtual element scheme does not require Lagrange multipliers to impose the transmission conditions (continuity of displacement and total traction, and no-flux for the fluid) on the interface. We show the stability and convergence of the virtual element method for different polynomial degrees, and the error bounds are robust with respect to delicate model parameters (such as Lamé constants, permeability, and storativity coefficient). Finally we provide some simple numerical examples that illustrate the properties of the scheme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Latest Results</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q&A: A blueprint for sustainable innovation]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/qa-atacama-biomaterials-blueprint-sustainable-innovation-0124</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/qa-atacama-biomaterials-blueprint-sustainable-innovation-0124"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Atacama Biomaterials, co-founded by Paloma Gonzalez-Rojas SM ’15, PhD ’21, combines architecture, machine learning, and chemical engineering to create eco-friendly materials.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adelaide Zollinger | MIT Morningside Academy for Design</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying Nonlinear Dynamics with High Confidence from Sparse Data]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1560252?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M1560252?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 383-409, March 2024. 
 Abstract.We introduce a novel procedure that, given sparse data generated from a stationary deterministic nonlinear dynamical system, can characterize specific local and/or global dynamic behavior with rigorous probability guarantees. More precisely, the sparse data is used to construct a statistical surrogate model based on a Gaussian process (GP). The dynamics of the surrogate model is interrogated using combinatorial methods and characterized using algebraic topological invariants (Conley index). The GP predictive distribution provides a lower bound on the confidence that these topological invariants, and hence the characterized dynamics, apply to the unknown dynamical system (assumed to be a sample path of the GP). The focus of this paper is on explaining the ideas, thus we restrict our examples to one-dimensional systems and show how to capture the existence of fixed points, periodic orbits, connecting orbits, bistability, and chaotic dynamics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bogdan Batko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convergence and Approximation of Invariant Measures for Neural Field Lattice Models under Noise Perturbation]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M157137X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/23M157137X?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=sjaday&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Dynamical Systems, Volume 23, Issue 1, Page 358-382, March 2024. 
 Abstract. This paper is mainly concerned with limiting behaviors of invariant measures for neural field lattice models in a random environment. First of all, we consider the convergence relation of invariant measures between the stochastic neural field lattice model and the corresponding deterministic model in weighted spaces, and prove any limit of a sequence of invariant measures of such a lattice model must be an invariant measure of its limiting system as the noise intensity tends to zero. Then we are devoted to studying the numerical approximation of invariant measures of such a stochastic neural lattice model. To this end, we first consider convergence of invariant measures between such a neural lattice model and the system with neurons only interacting with its n-neighborhood; then we further prove the convergence relation of invariant measures between the system with an n-neighborhood and its finite dimensional truncated system. By this procedure, the invariant measure of the stochastic neural lattice models can be approximated by the numerical invariant measure of a finite dimensional truncated system based on the backward Euler–Maruyama (BEM) scheme. Therefore, the invariant measure of a deterministic neural field lattice model can be observed by the invariant measure of the BEM scheme when the noise is not negligible.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomas Caraballo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Domain Decomposition Method for Solution of a PDE-Constrained Generalized Nash Equilibrium Model of Biofilm Community Metabolism]]></title>
        <id>https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1511023?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search</id>
        <link href="https://epubs.siam.org/doi/abs/10.1137/22M1511023?mi=9v4ths&amp;af=R&amp;countTerms=true&amp;publication=smjmap&amp;searchCollection=jb&amp;sortBy=Earliest_desc&amp;target=multi-search"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SIAM Journal on Applied Mathematics, Volume 84, Issue 1, Page 97-113, February 2024. 
 Abstract. Microbes are able to deploy different strategies in response to, and depending upon, local environmental conditions. In the setting of a microbial community, this property induces a Nash equilibrium problem because access to environmental resources is bounded. If microbes are also distributed in space, then those resources are subject to transport limitations (encoded in a PDE) and so microbial strategies at one location influence resources and, hence, microbial strategies, at another. Here we formulate the resulting PDE-coupled generalized Nash equilibrium problem for a multispecies biofilm community, and propose a domain-decomposition-based method for its solution. An example consisting of a model with two microbial species biofilm with 33 externally transported chemical concentrations is presented.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaac Klapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downstream network transformations dissociate neural activity from causal functional contributions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52423-7</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-024-52423-7"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientific Reports - Downstream network transformations dissociate neural activity from causal functional contributions]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Computational science : nature.com subject feeds</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What to do about AI in health?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.mit.edu/2024/what-to-do-about-ai-in-health-0123</id>
        <link href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/what-to-do-about-ai-in-health-0123"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T21:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although artificial intelligence in health has shown great promise, pressure is mounting for regulators around the world to act, as AI tools demonstrate potentially harmful outcomes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Ouyang | Abdul Latif Jameel Clinic for Machine Learning in Health</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>